<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20140421083029</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter April 2014</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS April 2014 Newsletter. Information about Tamil New year celebrations 2014, Monthly Satsang and Kids event etc.,</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter April 2014</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2014-05-20</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>April</NMonth>
  <NYear>2014</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;In Hinduism, Akshaya Tritiyai was the day when Lord Ganesha, the God of wisdom and obstacle removal, started writing the epic Mahabharata to dictation of Veda Vyas. This day is ruled by God Vishnu, the preserver God in the Hindu Trinity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kubera received his wealth and position as custodian of wealth and property with Goddess Lakshmi on this day, by praying to Lord Shiva at Shivapuram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Mahabharata, Yudhishtira receives the Akshaya patra, which he uses to serve food for all the needy in his kingdom. It is on this day that poor Sudama, the best friend of Lord Krishna visits Him (Lord Krishna) to greet Him after He became the King. With nothing to offer, Sudama takes with him Aval and offers it to his friend and never discusses his poverty though he intends to. On his return he finds his hut changed to a palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Vedic Scriptures say that knowledge gained or charity done on Akshaya Tritiyai is very fruitful. It is considered to be a very lucky day to start new business or venture. Many people buy gold or property on this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is believed that god Kubera, the treasurer of the Gods, is the richest deity. Lakshmi Tantram says that even Kubera will pray to Goddess Lakshmi, the Goddess of wealth and consort of Vishnu, on Akshaya Tritiyai. A day-long Kubera Lakshmi Puja is performed in which an image of Lakshmi is worshiped with Sudarsana Kubera Yantra symbolising Kubera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year Akshaya Tritiyai falls on the 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; of May.  We pray Goddess Lashmi along with God Maha Vishnu to give all the wealth, as was given to God Kubera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations – 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; April 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrangements are in full swing, for one of the major events of SIS, which is the SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations (Jaya Varuda Pirappu Kondattangal) on the 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of April 2014. As always, Tamil New Year Celebrations are celebrated grandly, as it is one of the landmark events for SIS. The evening will be packed with number of exciting programmes that would cater to people of all age groups. We welcome you all! 3 DAYS LEFT TO AVAIL EARLY BIRD DISCOUNTS!  If you have not registered already we request you RESIGTER AND PAY as soon as possible. Details about the event including the map are available on the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS May Satsang – 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Sainath and Mrs Srilatha Sainath have kindly volunteered to host the May Satsang at their residence on Saturday, the 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of May 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt;41 Seymour Road, Wimbledon, SW19 5JL&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please attend in large numbers. RSVP by 9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May either by replying to this e-mail or by calling Mrs. Srilatha Sainath on 020 8879 1191.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;Details of SIS events lined-up till June are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Vaanavil – SIS Kids Event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; June&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; June&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Rajathi Raja - A Tribute to Ilayaraja&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; June&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Sports Event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;Success Without Stress – Other events (11&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May – 16&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6 evening talks in English by Swami Swaroopananda. Discourses on Chapter 3 of the Bhagavad Geeta, organised by Chinmaya Mission UK.  For more details and registration visit &lt;a href="http://chinmayauk.org/events/success-without-stress/" target="_blank"&gt;http://chinmayauk.org/events/success-without-stress/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;The Website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We trust that the articles that we are publishing on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits thathave gone up multifold. This month, we have uploaded more interesting articles. We hope you will enjoy reading all the articles on the website. Please visit &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;., read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our patrons that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>