<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20130418101956</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter April 2013 - Chithirai Matham</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS April 2013 Newsletter. Information about SIS Tamil New year 2013 celebrations, Monthly Satsang, South Indian Society next events etc</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter April 2013</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2013-05-15</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>April</NMonth>
  <NYear>2013</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;விஜய ஆண்டு வாழ்த்துக்கள் &lt;br /&gt;
வட்டப் பாதை நம்வாழ்க்கை - அதன்&lt;br /&gt;
வழியில் அறுபது மைல்கற்கள் - இரு&lt;br /&gt;
சுற்றுப் பயணம் முழுவயது - நமைச்&lt;br /&gt;
சுமந்து இழுப்பது காலம் - அதை&lt;br /&gt;
எட்டிப் பறந்து அறிந்து - 'நான்யார்'&lt;br /&gt;
என்றே உணர்தல் முக்தி - இதைச்&lt;br /&gt;
சுட்டப் பிறந்தது ஆண்டு - சுகம்&lt;br /&gt;
சூடிக் கொடுத்திடும் நேரம் - வரம்&lt;br /&gt; 
கொட்ட மைல்கல் விஜய! - நலம்&lt;br /&gt;
கொடுக்கும் வெற்றிமேல் வெற்றி - மனம்&lt;br /&gt;
முற்றப் பிறந்தது வருடம் - நாம்&lt;br /&gt;
முழுமைப் பயணிகள் அன்றோ?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
அன்புடன்&lt;br /&gt;
மீ. ராஜகோபாலன்
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like to start the newsletter with this beautiful poem by our patron Mr. Rajja Rajagopalan. We take the opportunity to wish you all a happy Vijaya Varusham. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month Chithirai is significant for more than one reason apart from the start of spring (இளவேனில்). While the whole of India is getting ready to celebrate Sri Rama Navami on the 20th of April, Madurai is in the peak of its festivity as the famous Chithirai ThiruVizha is being celebrated. The other key celebration this month is &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/religion/chitra-pournami-20130418045857.aspx" target="_blank"&gt; Chithira Pournami &lt;/a&gt;, which falls on the 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of April.  We hope you thoroughly enjoy the spring and all the celebrations, including the Tamil New Year celebrations at SIS on the 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of April.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations – 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; April 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrangements are in full swing, for one of the major events of South Indian Society, which is the SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations (Vijaya Varuda Pirappu Kondattangal) on the 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of April 2013. This being the 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Anniversary year for SIS and indeed the 150&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; birth anniversary year for &lt;a href=" http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/religion/swami-vivekananda-epochal-journey-from-madras-to-chicago-20130418051221.aspx" target="_blank"&gt; Swami Vivekananda &lt;/a&gt;, we plan to celebrate it grandly. The evening will be packed with number of exciting programmes that would cater to people of all age groups. We welcome you all! &lt;span style="color:red; font-weight: bold; font-size:12px;"&gt; If you have not registered already, we request you register as soon as possible.&lt;/span&gt; Details about the event including the map is available on the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/london-tamil-new-year-celebrations-april-2013-20130306105808.aspx" target="_blank"&gt; website&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border="1"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size:14px"&gt;&lt;center&gt;Introducing &lt;a href="http://www.tilda.com/" target="_blank"&gt; Tilda Grand&lt;/a&gt; Our Longest Grain Yet&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="align:centre; font-size:12px"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;center&gt; With over 40 years of expertise in the rice world, Tilda ‘the connoisseurs of fine rice’ is unveiling its latest new range of legendary rice - Tilda Grand&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tilda Grand is a truly unique rice with long beautiful grains perfect for dishes like biryanis.  Its distinct and versatile shape means it can absorb a variety of flavours during the cooking process which make it superb for biryani and other such dishes where the length of the grain is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slender shape, sweet taste and delicate texture of the rice makes this an ideal ingredient for one pot dishes. The lusciously long grains also look fantastic on the plate which makes this the most beautiful rice on earth. Available in 5 kg and 10 kg Seal ‘n’ Store bags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="right"&gt;Advert &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS May Satsang – 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. PK Ramakrishnan and Mrs. Raji Ramakrishnan has kindly volunteered to host the May SIS Satsang at their residence.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt; 11 Faithful Close, Stone, Aylesbury, Bucks, HP17 8PW&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;span style="color:red; font-weight: bold"&gt;RSVP by 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt;May&lt;/span&gt; either by e-mailing &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; Mrs. Raji or Mr. Ramki directly on 01296 748336.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Alaigal Oivadhillai – 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the grand success of Sunset Cruise on Thames, we have had number of requests from several participants to organise a similar event again. To quench the thirst of number of patrons we announce the event SIS Alaigal Oivadhillai. &lt;a style="color:red; font-weight: bold; font-size:14px;"&gt;More fun but new route with spectacular view of Olympic stadium from the other side….&lt;/a&gt; What more…. Visit the website for more details……. 
Please block your calendar for all SIS events.  Details on all our events are posted in our &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details on all our events are posted in our &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;An Appeal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you bet your life on 1 in 20,000 odds? No one should have to – but that’s what Stanford Professor Nalini Ambady – and other South Asians - face. Will you help save her life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nalini Ambady has had a relapse of the Leukemia she battled in 2004. Nalini is a renowned scientist (if you have read Malcolm Gladwell’s Blink you know her work), an admired researcher, an inspirational teacher, an amazing mom, and a groundbreaking South Asian (the first South Asian faculty member in both Harvard's and Stanford’s Psychology Department). She needs your help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nalini needs to find a bone marrow donor within the next 8 weeks in order to survive.  Due to certain genetic markers, her match will almost certainly be South Asian. Right now, there is no match in the registry for Nalini. The power to fix this is in your hands: please register and ask all of your South Asian friends to register as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please help save Nalini’s life: Join the National Bone Marrow Donor Registry. Registering takes only minutes – a simple cheek swab and a little paperwork. These days, donating bone marrow is similar to donating blood – quick and almost painless. If you register today, it could be Nalini's life that you save. Just click this link to get a registration kit sent right to your door: &lt;a href="http://www.anthonynolan.org/What-you-can-do/save-a-life/Online-application.aspx" target="_blank"&gt; Anthonynolan.org&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLEASE HELP. It is a tragedy to consider the possibility that there is a match out there, but (s)he is simply not on the registry. Imagine the heartbreak of knowing you, or your mother, sister, or daughter, could be saved but that the match you need simply didn’t bother to register. You can fix that with just a few minutes of your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href="http://www.helpnalininow.org" target="_blank"&gt; HelpNaliniNow&lt;/a&gt;  for more information about how you can get involved and save Nalini !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;The Website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, we have uploaded several articles, which we hope you will find interesting and useful. 
We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, i.e., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the gro]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>