<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20120413023056</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - April 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society April 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter April 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-05-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>April</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;எந்தனமும் எல்லோர்க்கும் எப்போதும் தருவதற்கு&lt;br /&gt;
நந்தனமா மிந்த நல்லாண்டு பிறக்கிறது!&lt;br /&gt;
வந்தனமே! நலமே! வருங்காலப் பெருவளமே!&lt;br /&gt;
வந்து உதி! சிந்தை தெளி! வையசுகம் வாழவிழி!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 -- Rajja (SIS member)&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;With this beautiful Kavithai by our long term member Rajja Rajagopal, we take the opportunity to wish you all a wonderful Tamil New Year (Nanthana Aandu). We pray the almighty that all of us are blessed with all prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;In order to keep the newsletter short and for the fact that we have a lengthy list of exciting events for the next few months, we would like to dive in to the events straight away. &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS April Satsang - Saturday, the 14th of April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Srini Balaji and Mrs.Sangeetha Srini has kindly volunteered to host this month SIS Satsang at their residence on this auspicious day of "Vishu".  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address: 12 Waterville Drive, Vange, Basildon, Essex, SS16 4TY&lt;br /&gt;
Time: 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP by today either by e-mailing sisnambalava@gmail.com or contacting Mrs.Sangeetha  directly on 01268 583398.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations - Saturday, the 21st of April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We are happy to invite you with your family to the Tamil New Year Celebrations (Nanthana Varuda Pirappu Kondattangal) which is scheduled for Saturday, the 21st of April 2012. As always, the evening will be packed with number of exciting programmes that would cater to people of all age groups. We welcome you all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venue: Church of the Ascension Hall, Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB&lt;br /&gt;
Date   : Saturday the 21st of April 2012&lt;br /&gt;
Time  : 5:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Registration - 5:30 pm&lt;br /&gt;
Prayer Song - 6:00 pm&lt;br /&gt;
Panchanga Padalam&lt;br /&gt;
Variety Entertainment&lt;br /&gt;
Vote of thanks&lt;br /&gt;
Dinner @ 8:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP and Pay by Thursday the 19th April 2012&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Reduced fee for Members Confirming &amp; Paying in advance (by 19th April): £7 (Preferred option)&lt;br /&gt;
Members at entrance: £10&lt;br /&gt;
Non members : £12&lt;br /&gt;
Children (between 5 and 10) : £4&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Career Event - Saturday, the 19th of May&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Venue: Church of the Ascension Hall, Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB&lt;br /&gt;
Date   : Saturday the 19th of May 2012&lt;br /&gt;
Entry  : FREE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Sunset Cruise on Thames - Saturday, the 16th of June&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;SIS is thrilled to announce a fun filled evening in June, Sunset Cruise on Thames. Let’s welcome the summer with our friends. Let’s gather together on a sun-kissed evening for fabulous music, dance and much more. Tongue tickling food guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;And all this at a very nominal cost&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Spoil yourself, chill out and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Date : Saturday the 16th of June 2012&lt;br /&gt;
Venue              : Will be announced closer to the date&lt;br /&gt;
Boarding Time : 5 pm&lt;br /&gt;
Departure Time: 6 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduced fee for Members Confirming &amp; Paying in advance (by 16th May): £15 (Preferred option)&lt;br /&gt;
Non-Members paying in advance: £20&lt;br /&gt;
Members and Non-members paying at entrance: £25&lt;br /&gt;
Children between 5 and 10: £10&lt;br /&gt;
Children (below 5): FREE.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP and Pay by 16th of May&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that, there is a limited capacity on the cruise and hence we are forced to operate on a first come first served basis.  Please confirm and pay as soon as possible to avoid disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We trust that the articles being published on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone up multi-fold. Please visit our website to read the articles and kindly let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie, South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>