<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20110412082032</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - April 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society April 2011 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter April 2011</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2011-05-08</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>April</NMonth>
  <NYear>2011</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As we welcome the advent of Spring, we wish to start this version of the newsletter for April on a very high note, with India winning the World Cup, Rama Navami and Tamil New Year just round the corner adding to the high spirit of every Indian in India and in the United Kingdom and also with Easter break and the Royal wedding adding joy to the festive mood and spirits. SIS wishes its members a very Happy Tamil New Year and a wonderful holiday season ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of SIS Health and Fun afternoon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a view to keeping in constant touch with members, the earlier practice of holding Monthly Meetings has been revived. The first monthly meeting  for this year was held on Sunday the 20th March at the Little Chalfont Village Hall.  Mr. Maheshwar, ENT Consultant, talked about ENT related problems, which was well received by the audience.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;This very informative presentation was followed by 'bingo with a difference', an idea that was conducted by Mrs Raji Rajagopal. The Bingo was based on a quiz that helped to brush up our general knowledge specifically on numbers, historical dates etc.. Despite the India vs West Indies deciding cricket match, the meeting was well attended and concluded with snacks and refreshments being served to all the attendees.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Our Sincere thanks to everyone who attended the meeting and to those who could not attend, we will be uploading the powerpoint presentation on our website &lt;i&gt;&lt;u&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. We are happy to organise a similar presentation on ENT, in case of popular demand.&lt;/p&gt;  
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil New Year Programme and the new price structure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;SIS will be celebrating the welcome of Kara varusham on the 30th of April at the Church of Ascension Hall, Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB. The celebration is scheduled to start at &lt;b&gt;6 pm&lt;/b&gt; sharp, starting with a prayer song, Panchangam Padalam followed by  cultural entertainment by some of our talented members. Dinner will be served at the end of the programme. &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We as SIS members come from a background where we abhor wastage of any kind. Over the years, one of the frustrations of organisers of SIS events has been 'no shows', resulting in avoidable cost and food wastage. As an incentive to encourage early confirmations and payments whilst simultaneously attempting to keep costs and food wastage down to the minimum, we have restructured the entrance fee.  We are pleased to announce that the new price structure has worked well so far. We have received plenty of confirmations and payments in advance. We wish to encourage all members to avail of the "early bird" opportunity by confirming AND pre-paying (membership for 2011 and for the event) by the 26th of April.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The new price structure at a glance:&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Reduced fee for Members Confirming &amp; Paying in advance (by 26th April) : £6 (Preferred option)&lt;br /&gt;
Members paying on the day : £8&lt;br /&gt;
Non members : £10&lt;br /&gt;
Children (between 5 and 10) : £4&lt;br /&gt;
Further details about the programme are available on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forthcoming Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The next Monthly Meeting will be held on Sunday  the 29th of  May at the Church of Ascension Hall, Beaufort Road, London W5 3EB (off North Circular Road, A406).  At this meeting, Mr Vedanarayanan, a long-standing Member, will present a slide show about Temples of South India with a brief narrative about each temple.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Following the grand success of the SIS Cricket Event last year, we have scheduled to hold this year's cricket event on the 9th of July.  Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details of the events are available under the Events Section on the website.  Members are requested to attend these meetings and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you may have already noticed, we are taking all possible efforts to provide interesting and useful articles on the website &lt;strong&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/strong&gt;. We have uploaded Tamil Panchangam Calendar for the year 2011, tips for Grammar School admissions in London etc.  This month, we have number of interesting articles including recipes for "Veppamboo Pachadi" and "Oma Kuzhambu" (tried and tested). The number of hits to our website across the globe has been encouraging and so has been the feedback. Please visit the website, read the articles and let us know your views.  We welcome articles from all our members.  The articles will be uploaded after being reviewed by the editorial panel.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success of Charity Drive so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, last month the SIS committee initiated a charity drive to support Rajapatasala in Kumbakonam, one of the oldest Veda Patasalas in India dating back to 1542. We are extremely pleased with the response we have got to support the drive. We have collected over £500 so far. We have set ourselves an aggressive target of £5000/- for this year. We are committed to this cause and wish to assure you that the entire proceeds from this charity drive will be donated to the Veda Patasala.  The Committee requests you all to donate generously to this noble cause.  You can easily transfer the money / set up a  standing order through your bank to the following SIS account:  &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Name: South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
Name of Bank:BARCLAYS BANK&lt;br /&gt;
Sort Code:   20-29-37 &lt;br /&gt;                          
Account No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Patasala&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on the Patasala please visit &lt;a href="http://www.rajapatasala.in" target="_blank"&gt;www.rajapatasala.in.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country.  We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed. For those who have not paid your annual membership yet, may we request you pay your membership (£20/-) at the earliest? You can send your cheque in the name of &lt;b&gt;"South Indian Society"&lt;/b&gt; and mail it to the address below or alternatively make the payment via bank transfer to SIS Account (details given below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mailing address&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
No 7 Erroll Road&lt;br/&gt;
Romford&lt;br/&gt;
Essex&lt;br /&gt;
RM1 3DJ&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bank account details&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Name of Bank:BARCLAYS BANK&lt;br/&gt;
Bank Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br/&gt;
A/c Name:  South Indian Society&lt;br/&gt;
A/c No. 50284645&lt;br/&gt;
Ref: Membership&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Wish you all a very happy new year and hope to see you at our Tamil New Year celebrations on the 30th of April.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>