<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20130819122119</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter August 2013</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS August 2013 Newsletter. Information about SIS Navaratri Dandiya 2013 celebrations, Monthly Satsang, South Indian Society next events etc</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter August 2013</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2013-09-19</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>August</NMonth>
  <NYear>2013</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;நவமணியும் பொற்கிழியும் நல்லரிசி மாமஞ்சள்&lt;br /&gt;
நறுமலர்கள் கலச மிட்டோம்&lt;br /&gt;
நாற்புறமும் பூமாலை மேற்புறமும் தேங்கனியில்&lt;br /&gt;
நளினமுக வடிவ மிட்டோம்&lt;br /&gt;
பவதரணி ஜகஜனனி சிவசக்தி மாலெக்ஷ்மி&lt;br /&gt;
பதியவரக் கோல மிட்டோம்&lt;br /&gt;
பாலமுது பூரணமும் பாயசமும் பழவகையும்&lt;br /&gt;
படைத்துனது காலி லிட்டோம்&lt;br /&gt;
பவபயமும் கருகமணி பரிசணியத் தருமநெறி&lt;br /&gt;
பற்றுவரச் சுற்ற மிட்டோம்&lt;br /&gt;
பணித்தருளை முடிச்சரடில் பதித்தணியக் கரமழகு&lt;br /&gt;
பாவனையும் பெற்று விட்டோம்&lt;br /&gt;
தவமணியே வரலெக்ஷ்மித் தாயமுதே காமாக்ஷி&lt;br /&gt;
தருமபரி பாலகி உமையே!&lt;br /&gt;
வரவேண்டும், வரம்வேண்டும், வளமுலகு பெறவேண்டும்&lt;br /&gt;
வல்லவி வரலெக்ஷ்மி மாதே!&lt;br /&gt;
மீ. ராஜகோபாலன்
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like to start this newsletter with the wonderful Kavidhai by our Patron Rajja Rajagopalan on Varalakshmi. We trust you all had a wonderful Varalakshmi Vrutham. We sincerely pray the almighty to shower the blessings to all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rig and Yajur Upakarma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year 20th August is Rig and Yajur Upakarma.  We have uploaded an interesting article on the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/religion/a-primer-on-aavani-avittam-or-upakarma-20130819100453.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;significance of Upakarma&lt;/a&gt;, the number of things we do and the reason behind doing the different rituals on that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rig &amp; Yajur Upakarma will be performed at the following places.  Please check with your nearest temple for their schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@ Eastham at 7 am, 8 am and 9 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sri Murugan Temple &lt;br&gt;
78 Church Road, &lt;br&gt;
Manor Park, &lt;br&gt;
E12 6AF&lt;br&gt;
Tel No 02084788433&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@ Wembley at 8-30 am&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vinayakar Temple&lt;br&gt;
1-2 The Broad Way, &lt;br&gt;
Preston Road, &lt;br&gt;
Wembley,&lt;br&gt;
Middlesex, HA9 8JT&lt;br&gt;
Tel: No 07942 491 274&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please come half hour early with Pancha Pathram ,Uddhurni and Plate. Flowers and Fruits are optional. Punul, Pavithram etc will be supplied by the priest. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to do it at home, please download &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/downloads/upakarma-sankalpam-2013.pdf"&gt;SANKALPAM&lt;/a&gt; from the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Musical Galatta Evening – Saturday, 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; September&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;டாண்டியா ஆட்டமுமாட தசரா கூட்டமும் கூட…. Yes.  The most awaited Dandiya Musical Galatta evening is on this year. We have scheduled this event on Saturday, the 21st of September. More Music… More Dance…. and More Fun !!!!…. More details are available on the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/2013-navaratri-dandiya-in-london-20130807065626.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border="1"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;h2 style="text-align: center;font-family: Arial;font-size: 16px;color: #7789A2;"&gt;Tilda Goes Vintage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div style="float:left; margin:0px 0px 10px 10px;"&gt;
        &lt;img border="0" src="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/images/newsletter/tilda-new-recipe.png" alt="" title="" hspace="5" vspace="5"&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style="font-weight:normal; margin: 0 2px 0 2px;"&gt;Tilda is continuing to excite Indian food lovers everywhere with the launch of its NEW Tilda Humara rice pouches - a range of five authentic Indian recipes that are perfect those who are short of time as these are ready to eat in 2 mins.  The range, which includes four savoury recipes and one dessert are a delicious meal-time staple.   Three of the recipes are made using wholegrain basmati as its been developed with healthy eating in mind and includes recipes for Khichdi, Mushroom Hakka, Hyderabadi Masala, Biryani and Kheer – a traditional Indian rice pudding all of which are under 170 calories per portion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="font-weight:normal; margin: 0 2px 0 2px;"&gt;Each variety is gluten free, suitable for vegetarians and free from any artificial colours, flavours or preservatives.  Now available at Sainbury’s World Food aisle and good Asian independent stores.  For more info visit &lt;a href="http://www.tilda.com/humara" target="_blank"&gt;www.tilda.com/humara&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="right"&gt;Advert &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Sep Satsang – Saturday 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; September&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Hari Sundaresan and Jaysree Sundaresan have kindly volunteered to host the September Satsang at their residence on Saturday, the 7th of September at their residence. Please RSVP by sending an e-mail to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or calling Mr. Hari or Ms. Jayasree on 01494 729832 by 6th of September. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt;5 Deep Acres, Amersham, Bucks, HP6 5NX&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Deepavali and Silver Jubilee Celebrations – 9th November 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please mark your calendar for the SIS Deepavali Celebrations and the Silver Jubilee Celebrations on the 9th of November.  More details to follow….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;The Website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, we have uploaded several articles, which we hope you will find interesting and useful. We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, i.e., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>