<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20120823054019</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - August 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society August 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>  
  <Heading>Newsletter August 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-09-5</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>August</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;It is pouring gold over Great Britain.  Yes.  It all started to pour 7 years back, for winning the bid to conduct Olympics; For a sterling preparation in all areas so far; For the world class opening ceremony; For developing champions to win several medals; and finally for winning number of medals;  It has been a stupendous job all round.  We would like to extend hearty congratulations from all of us at SIS! Please click here to read about &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/others/london-2012-olympics-why-this-hype-20120808060817.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Olympics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week just passed, was a very important week for all of us. The key factors are Rig / Yajur Upakarma and Gayathri Japam. To quote the current SIS chairman Mr. N Sundar, who spoke in a well attended SIS Satsang on the 4th of August. ““Upakarma is a ceremony performed as a prelude to vedaadyayana, or, the beginning of the annual cycle of learning and teaching one’s veda.  It begins with ‘kamokarsheetmanyurakarsheet’ japam, wherein one atones for failure to do one’s karmas due either to lust and greed or anger. The Mahasankalpam that follows is an elaborate listing of all sins one may have committed in mind, words or deeds and atoning for them and reiteration of one’s determination as to the future. Poonal is yagnaupaveedam, ie, a most sacred symbol, or ‘paramampavitram’ and its wearing, or ‘dharanam’, is for the purposes of  performing various yagnas or prescribed karmas, and, pursuing all the yogas as per Gita: bakthi, karma and gyanam. By reciting gayathri 1008 times the following day, one begins to walk the talk.” You may like to read the full version of the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/religion/significance-of-upakarma-20120808051510.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;speech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Jayanthi of Sri Jayendra Saraswathi Sankaracharya fell on 3rd August, Mr. Sundar also recited guru vandanam and swastivachanam and offered, on behalf all at SIS, obeisance to all gurus, beginning with adi the guru of all, SriDakshinamoorthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, Krishna Janmashtami falls on the 9th of August. Krishna means celebrations, dance, colour, happiness etc. etc.  We at SIS wish you all a very happy Krishna Janmashtami and may Lord Krishna shower all happiness to all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS August Carnival - Saturday, the 18th of August &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;RSVP Required&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The countdown has begun for the much awaited SIS Carnival. The excitement is climbing by the day.  Non-stop calls for information and confirmation. &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Awesome prizes to be won!!!! Apple TV / iPOD Shuffle / Gear 4 Portable Speaker iPOD Dock / Gift Hampers&lt;/span&gt;. Spicy Alu Tikkis and chaats to tickle your taste buds, sinfully rich cakes and pastries, Rice and Curry, Arts &amp; crafts shops with ethnic flavour and many more stalls available. &lt;span style="color:blue;"&gt;Please come in large numbers with your family and friends and spend generously&lt;/span&gt;. Please remember, the carnival is in aid of Shooting Stars Children Hospice &amp; Great Ormond Street Hospital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our moment to show London.  We Care. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 18th August 2012&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm and 7 pm&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; St Andrews Church, 89 Malvern Avenue, Harrow, Middlesex, HA2 9ER&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Entry:&lt;/strong&gt;  Free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP on or before Sunday the 12th of August by send an e-mail to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the line-up of SIS events for the rest of the year. Apart from the monthly Satsang, we have lined-up number of interesting events for the rest of the year. E-mails will be sent and details will be made available on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;, closer to the event.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18th Aug:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Carnival 2012 &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;22nd Sep:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Career Event (Career guidance event to SIS youth)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;17th Nov:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Deepavali&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;15th Dec:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Youth Event (An event organised by SIS youth)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please mark your calendar and we request you to participate in all the SIS events&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Youth – &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Youth Volunteers invited&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we have two events for the next generation SISites.  Yes they are the youth events. More information will follow regarding the SIS Career Event shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The December event is the SIS Youth Event.  We would like that event to be organised and run by SIS Youth. Yes! &lt;span style="color:blue;"&gt;YOU ARE HIRED!&lt;/span&gt; You conceptualise; You look after the logistics and execute it well. We will guide you if required. It will be the typical BBC apprentice style with one difference.  &lt;span style="color:blue;"&gt;No one will be fired!&lt;/span&gt;  It will be a great opportunity and experience for our SIS Youth. A must thing to be on ones CV and SIS need more youth involvement.  How can we find a better win-win deal? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be a 10 member team (boys and girls) to run a grand gala show. Please send in nominations for your children (age between 14 and 20), with a brief write-up (not more than one page) by the nominee on &lt;strong&gt;"How can you make a difference"&lt;/strong&gt;.   Please send the nominations to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; with the write-up on or before the 1st of September 2012. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; is being redesigned. The website with the new layout will be launched as soon as possible. We trust that the articles being published on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone up multi-fold. Please visit our website to read the articles and kindly let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie, South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>