<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20110807061300</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - August 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society August 2011 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter August 2011</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2011-09-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>August</NMonth>
  <NYear>2011</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;August, one of the best months in the United Kingdom with fabulous weather, great chance for barbeque parties, beaches, holidays and some great cricket.  It is the Aadi-Aavani months, according to Tamil calendar, kick-start of festival season for Hindus, Varalakshmi Nonbu, Avani Avittam, Krishna Jayanthi, Vinayakar Chathurthi and so on….Whatever is the festival, great food is the highlight of all Indian festivals.  We at SIS wish you all a great festival season ahead in the great British summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We won’t be truthful if we don’t talk cricket especially when the Indian team is here in England.  Without going too controversial, India may have lost two test matches, but the team has won the “World Sportsmanship Award” for the great gesture of getting Ian Bell back in the crease in the second test match. We salute the sportsmanship of the great Indian team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Remarkable Reunion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;SIS was instrumental in re-uniting a son, who was homeless in London and was suffering from a mental condition, with his mother in India.  With the help of personal details given by his  friends and relatives in India, he was located and, after liaison with the various authorities, was admitted to a specialist hospital where he received appropriate treatment.  While in the hospital, he was provided with food, moral and parental support.  Ultimately, after nearly five months and with the help of authorities concerned, he has now been sent back to his mother in India where he continues to receive treatment.  It was a satisfying moment when an email was received from his mother in India thanking the SIS profusely.  We as an organisation can rightfully be proud of our humanitarian achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forthcoming Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Sri Vasudeva Battar, who has learnt to perform upanyasam in Sri Anantharama Dikshadar style, will give a discourse on “Krishna Leela and Rukmini Kalyanam” on the 7th of August at Church of Ascension Hall on Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB. Some of the members have listened to his Upanyasam a few times and his depth of knowledge and his command on the subject is outstanding. We request you to bring your children along as well and they will get exposed to the original Indian culture in a British environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we get closer to Dasara, it is time for Kolattam. Yes 17th of September evening will be a Kolattam and Karaoke evening. SIS will celebrate Deepavali on the 29th of October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details of all the events are available under the Events Section on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Members are requested to attend these events with your family and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepavali Recipes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a preparation for Deepavali, we would like to publish snacks and sweets recipes on our website. We welcome recipes of new types of snacks and sweets and the recipes of our traditional ones that contain special tips. Please write to us of the recipes that you have tried and you want to share with your friends. We will upload it in September.  Recipes will be uploaded after review by the editorial committee. Guidelines for articles are given below.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We are confident that you enjoyed the webcast of the kumbabishegam of Govindapuram Dakshina Pandari Puram Sri Krishna temple between 12th and 15th of July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13th of August is Yajur Upakarma. We have uploaded in our website the sankalpam (customised  to London) to help our members perform Avani Avittam rituals at home with ease. We have also listed a couple of locations where a gurukkal will assist you to perform Aavani Avittam rituals.  We have uploaded other interesting articles this month: some that have relevance to Avani Avittam, like ‘Mahaperiaval on Subrahmanyaya Namaste and Gayathri Mantra’ and other interesting articles on on Varalakshmi Poojai, Sri. Lalgudi Jayaram experience in London etc. Please visit &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;., read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie., south Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success of Charity Drive so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, SIS committee initiated a charity drive to support Raja Veda Patasala in Kumbakonam, one of the oldest Veda Patasalas in India dating back to 1542. We are extremely pleased that we have collected over £800 so far. For those willing to donate, details provided in the website.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May we request those of you who have not yet paid your annual membership of (£20), to please do so at the earliest? You can send your cheque in the name of "South Indian Society" and mail it to the address below or alternatively make the payment via bank transfer to SIS Account (details given below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mailing address&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No 7 Erroll Road&lt;br /&gt;
Romford&lt;br /&gt;
Essex&lt;br /&gt;
RM1 3DJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bank account details&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bank Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
A/c Name:  South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
A/c No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Membership
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the summer and see you all at the Upanyasam on the 7th of August.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>