<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20121220073300</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - December 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society December 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter December 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2013-01-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>December</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We take this opportunity to wish you all a very happy festive season. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 
Tamil month Margazhi begins on the 16th of December. Sri Krishna Bhagavan says in Bhagavat Gita "Masaanaam Margaseershohum" - “among the months, I am Margazhi”.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;
We have taken the opportunity of this newsletter to briefly narrate the story of Sri Andal, considered as an avatar of Bhumi Devi and her great work, Tiruppavai, considered as the Veda in Tamil. As in the last few years, we will upload every day of Margazhi one Thiruppavai  verse on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;.  May we all listen, recite and get the blessings of Sri Krishna.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
The SIS Annual General Meeting is scheduled to be held on the 19th of January 2013. A formal notice will be sent separately to all the paid members.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style="border-style:solid; border-width:1px;"&gt;


&lt;h2 align="center"&gt;Andal and Thiruppavai&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;Andal, considered as one of the twelve Alvars (Gurus of Vaishnavaits), was a Tamil poet from the 10th century from a village Srivilliputhur in the southern parts of India. Among the twelve Alwars, Andal is the only woman.  She is also believed to be an incarnation of Sri Bhumi Devi, the Divine Consort of Sriman Narayana (a manifestation of Lord Vishnu).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;Andal composed two poetic works both in Tamil. Even though compiled in her teenage years, they display a high level of literary and religious maturity. Thiruppavai is considered Veda in Tamil in a condensed form. It is also believed that Bumi Devi, decided to give the Vedas in such a format, so that common man can chant it every day and attain the blessings of Sriman Narayana. Andal’s second work is Nacciyar Tirumoli, consisting of 143 verses. Through this poem, she disclosed her passionate yearning for Lord Vishnu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;Andal was believed to have been found under a Tulsi plant Sri Vishnuchittar’s garden. Sri Vishnuchittar had the title of “Periazhwar” meaning “the most enlightened one who could rule over the Lord Himself”. Periazhwar raised Andal with great love, affectionately calling her as “Godai” (child of the Earth) or “Kodai” (garland of flowers) and enchanting her with stories of Krishna. In turn, Andal developed deep love for “Krishna” and blossomed into a beautiful girl who considered herself as God’s bride. This love for her Lord was transmitted through the creation of “Thiruppavai”.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;Andal was so profoundly enthralled by the bhakti of gopis and the deeds of Krishna in Mathura and Brindavan that she too wanted desperately to immerse in the divine experience. While still in Srivilliputur, Andal transformed herself into a yadava girl of Mathura and beseeched the Lord for His love. She undertook a vrat,  similar to the “Karthiyayani” vrat,  beginning on the first day of the month of “Margazhi” and adorning each day of the month with a new pasuram, an eight-lined verse. The thirty verses collectively form “Thiruppavai”. In the first five verses, Andal dwells on the appropriateness of the vrat and the method to be followed, invokes varuna deva for timely rains and emphasizes that all obstacles for performing the vrat will be eliminated if everyone sings and reflects on the name of the Lord (“Namasankirtanam”). True to her nature as the “Bhumata” with utmost love for one and all, Andal invites each one of us to transform into a gopi and join her in awakening the ever awake Lord, from the sixth to the fifteenth verse of Thiruppavai. From the sixteenth to the twenty-ninth verse Andal reminds the seemingly forgetful Lord of His earlier promises to grant “salvation” to His devotees, alternatively seeking His pardon for earlier trespasses, worshiping Him for His superior qualities and surrendering unto Him unconditionally (“Charanagathy” tatvam/philosophy). The depth of Andal’s desire to become the “gopi” of dwarkapuri is explicit in her complete identification with the “ayarpadi” or cowherd community in words and deeds until the thirtieth verse in which she introduces herself as the daughter of “Periazhwar” in grateful reference to his role as her acharya/teacher.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;In the thirtieth verse Andal acknowledges the fulfilment that would arise from the observance of the “marghazhi vrat” of the Gopis and declares that those who recite Her Thiruppavai verses would become the objects of Her Lord's grace and would be filled with bliss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;It is said that if Bhagavad Geetha is "Geethopanishad", Andal's thiruppavai can be referred as "Godhopanishad". Parasara Bhattar, a great spiritual teacher and philosopher has also revealed to us that the grace of the merciful Lord is sure to fall on us from His listening to our recitation of His Piratti's (Devi’s) Thiruppavai. Thiruppavai can of course be recited any time of the year to invoke the blessings of the Lord Narayana, but, the month of Margazhi is particularly auspicious.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>