<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20111207095840</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - December 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society December 2011 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>  
  <Heading>Newsletter December 2011</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-01-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>December</NMonth>
  <NYear>2011</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Let us start the last newsletter for the year 2011 with yet another famous hymn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lead, kindly Light, amid th’encircling gloom, lead Thou me on!&lt;br /&gt;
The night is dark, and I am far from home; lead Thou me on!&lt;br /&gt;
Keep Thou my feet; I do not ask to see&lt;br /&gt;
The distant scene; one step enough for me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Henry Newman may have written this hymn for a different reason, however, it is the nature of poetry that we can interpret it to our convenience.  I think this hymn is appropriate to be mulled-over in this month of Karthigai. When we think of Karthigai, the first thing that comes to our mind is Deepam. This is the month of light and it is worth for us to spend a few moments, to offer prayers to the Lord in the form of light / Jothi.  It is on this full moon day at Thiruvannamalai, Lord Shiva took the form of Jothi (fire) to end an egoistic conflict between Brahma and Vishnu on “Who is superior”. All of us may have a similar conflict among ourselves in some form or the other.  Even if one doesn’t believe in these stories, the moral of the story still remains it is “He” who is supreme and all of us are equally tiny in front of “Him”. Fire is one of the Panchabootham and Lord Shiva is in the form of fire at Thiruvannamalai and hence it is one of the Panchasthalams. On this big occasion of Karthigai deepam, we at SIS sincerely pray the Lord of light to show the light for a wonderful new year to all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Annual General Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is this time of the year when the committee has to reflect on the activities and accomplishments of SIS in the year just passed.  The SIS Annual General Meeting will be held on the 28th of January 2012.  A formal notice will be sent to all the paid members in the next few days. We request all members to attend the AGM and contribute with your feedback.  Your feedback matters a lot to the organization and it is the only constructive way to take the organization to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May we request those who have not paid your 2011 membership to transfer the £20/- to SIS as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, we had to reschedule the event “SIS - Paattu Paada Vaa, Aattam Poda Vaa” to a later date.  We now have penciled this for the month of February, when most of the patrons will be available to attend. More information will be made available as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details of all the events are available under the Events Section on the website. Members are requested to attend these events with your family and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also confident that the articles that we are publishing on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone-up multifold.  This month, we have uploaded more interesting articles, the fourth in series on “My understanding of Philosophy” by one of our members Mr. Sukumar Panchapakesan.  This month, the subject he has chosen is “Need for Self Knowledge and the path to Realisation”. There are other articles on “Karthigai Deepam” and “Maadhangalil Aval Maargazhi” by N Sundar, “Acceptance in it’s fullest form” by an young writer Ms. Sowmya, “Hindu Magical Numbers” by Santhanam Swaminathan to name a few. We hope you will enjoy reading all the articles on the website. Please visit our website and read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success of Charity Drive so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, SIS committee initiated a charity drive to support Raja Veda Patasala in Kumbakonam, one of the oldest Veda Patasalas in India dating back to 1542. We are extremely pleased that the collection has exceeded £1500 so far. We sincerely thank everyone who has participated in this charity drive. We will be closing the collection for this charity end of this year.  We will announce the objective for the next drive early next year. For those willing to sponsor, details provided in the website .&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt; ]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>