<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20131220034218</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter December 2013</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS December 2013 Newsletter. Information about SIS AGM 2014, Monthly Satsang and December Music festival live webcasts etc</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter December 2013</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2014-01-20</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>December</NMonth>
  <NYear>2013</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;“Maasanam Margasheershoham,” says Sri Krishna in the Vibhuti Yoga of the
Bhagavad Gita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; In this chapter Sri Krishna speaks of everything that is the best, in the form of which he is manifest and among the 12 months of the year, the best month is Margazhi, from mid December to mid January of the lunar calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes the Margazhi season special for devotion? It is the time of the winter solstice when the days are shorter and the nights are longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the spiritual significance? It is believed, for the Gods, one year of ours isa day and the period of Margazhi is the pre-dawn moment when Ushas, the deity of dawn, is just about to emerge which forms an ideal time for meditation and contemplation on one’s divine self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the scientific significance? It has been proven scientifically that the OZONE layer will be closest to the earth during the month of Marghazi,so breathing the fresh early morning air adds to healthy living in the margazhi month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chanting, singing and fasting are all different forms of Yoga that keep us in synchrony with that divinity which is a part of us. It is believed to be one of the reasons for the great music season in Chennai and early morning Bhajans in almost all temples. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we have been doing in the last few years, one verse of Thiruppavai is uploaded on the website on a daily basis.  Let’s hear and chant Thiruppavai and get the blessings of Andal (Maha Lakshmi Swaroopam) and Maha Vishnu.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS January Satsang – 11th January 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. TG Krishnamurthy and Mrs. Susheela Krishnamurthy have kindly volunteered to host the first Satsang of 2014 at their their residence on Saturday, the 4th of January 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address&lt;/strong&gt;: 64 Ingleby Road, Ilford, IG1 4RY&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSVP by sending an e-mail to sisnambalava@gmail.com or by contacting Mrs Susheela Krishnamurthy on 020 8220 4289  by the 10th of January 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you all at the Satsang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table border="1"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style="font-weight:normal;"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch December Music Season from your home&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;Warm greetings from Team Kalakendra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;We are proud to present for this music season a series of webcasts you to view from the comforts of your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 2013 Music Festival - 20 Concerts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;&lt;a style="border:none 0px white;" target="_blank" href="http://www.kalakendra.com/shopping/december-2013-music-festivals-season-pass-p-3350.html"&gt;&lt;img border="0" src="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/images/Music-festival-webcast.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;Kalakendra.com for the first time ever, brings to you 20 concert of December Music festival in webcast! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;Technology Meets Tradition. Powered by Amazon Cloud they have use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Namasankeertana Vizha 2013&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;&lt;a style="border:none 0px white;" target="_blank" href="http://www.kalakendra.com/shopping/devotional-c-123_136.html"&gt;&lt;img border="0" src="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/images/Namasankeertana-Vizha-2013.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;Continuing in our effort to bring the best of Classical and Devotional music to the comforts of your home, we present a series of over 11 Namasankeertanams as a Free Webcast&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="font-size:11px;margin: 5px 2px 0 2px;"&gt;Contact Kalakendra Team: +91-44-24984050&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Annual General Meeting – 18th January 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SIS Annual General Meeting is scheduled to be held on the 18th of January 2014. A formal notice will be sent separately to all the paid members.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>