<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20120206064959</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - February 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society February 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter February 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-03-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>February</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;புது வெள்ளை மழை இங்கு பொழிகின்றது&lt;br /&gt; 
இந்தக் கொள்ளை நிலா உடல் நனைகின்றது..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you all enjoyed the first snow for the year in London.  All of us turn several years younger when we build snowman or any other sculptures that we like or play with our friends and kids throwing snow at each other. We sincerely wish you safety and less hurdles to your daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thaipoosam, is celebrated on the Poosam (star) in the month of Thai. This day is the when Goddess Paarvathi gave the Velayutham to Lord Muruga, to conquer evils. It is for this reason, several devotees across the globe carry பால் குடம் (Milk Pot) and  காவடி (Kaavadi) to express their gratitude to Lord Muruga. Several devotees also carry-out extreme acts like piercing their body with அலகு(alagu) as a cleansing act. Thaipoosam is celebrated in all Murugan temples across the vlobe.  It is celebrated particularly in a very big way in arupadai veedu in South India, Srilanka, Singapore, Malaysia and Mauritius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we head to the Tamil month of Maasi, Mahashivarathri falls on the 20th of February.  Mahashivarathri is one of the most important days for Lord Shiva when most of the temples perform 4 kaala abhishegam to Lord Shiva throughout the night.  It is an opportunity to pray Lord Shiva the whole night. To recollect the story when Lord Shiva gave dharshan and salvation to a hunter who picked and dropped vilva leaves on a Shiva Lingam, through Shiva Rathri. The hunter was not even aware that he was doing Shiva Pooja. He was doing so, because he had to climb the vilva tree to save himself from a tiger. In order to keep himself engaged and not fall asleep, he was doing so. But Lord Shiva was pleased even by that act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take the opportunity to greet you well and continue with the updates from us./p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Annual General Meeting Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Annual General Meeting of SIS was held on 28th January 2012. A well attended AGM, first discussed the Income and Expenses statement, Balance Sheet and approved the same. The committee then presented the activities of the Society in 2011 and proposed a plan for the new committee for 2012. Two members offered to step down giving way for three new nominations that was received earlier in January.  The resignations and nominations were accepted by the members by taking a vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The new committee took charge and got into action almost the same day. One of the new initiatives proposed at the AGM was to conduct SIS Monthly Satsang in different parts of London at the residence of members who offer to volunteer. The first of such event was conducted on the 4th of February at the residence of Mr. and Mrs. Chandrasekaran in Hornchurch. Over 20 people attended the Satsang to create a divine environment. The event concluded with a brief discourse on Bakthi by Dr. Chadrasekharan followed by Aarthi and Prasadam.  More details of the event with some photographs are available on the website. We welcome volunteers for the SIS Monthly Satsangam scheduled on 3rd March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Aattam Paattam Kondaatam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As announced earlier, SIS we have scheduled an event for the 11th of February.  இது ஒரு காதலர் தின சிறப்பு நிகழ்ச்சி.. We take Valentine's Day as an opportunity to get together and start this year's events at SIS with a festive note. We have tried to tailor this event to lovers of all ages. We invite you to come, participate and enjoy. Three days left to enjoy early bird price advantage. RSVP and pay by 8th Feb.  For more details visit www.sisnambalava.org.uk .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Forthcoming events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;With the introduction of the monthly SIS Satsang and monthly events, we have more opportunity to meet and build a strong society. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3rd March a SIS Monthly  Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10th March a Health and Fun Afternoon.  A talk on Cardio related issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7th April a SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;21st April a SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next monthly Bhajans sponsored by SIS is scheduled for the 18th of February at the Sindhi Mandhir. More details are available on the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details of all the events are available under the Events Section on the website. Members are requested to attend these events with your family and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We believe that the articles that we are publishing on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone-up multifold. This month, we have uploaded more interesting articles. We hope you will enjoy reading all the articles on the website. Please visit www.sisnambalava.org.uk., read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;


 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt; ]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>