<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20120116035211</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - January 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society January 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter January 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-02-5</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>January</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We take this opportunity to wish you a very happy and prosperous New Year 2012. Whatever are the New Year vows you have taken, we sincerely wish that you fulfill all of them and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In December 1927, with the inauguration of Music Academy in Chennai, the music season started.   84 years have passed and the Chennai Music Festival is going strong, with over 2000 participants in over 300 concerts in around 53 different Sabhas. To all the music lovers, this is one of the greatest carnivals.  To those who have been there, we are pretty confident that you had a wonderful time there and welcome back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12th of January is the 27th day of Maargazhi which is Koodarai Valli.  It is a very important day as Aandal breaks her Maargazhi fast. It is a common practice to make Akkaravadisal for neivedyam and share it with family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tamil month of Thai which begins on 15th January, 2012, is an important month. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sun's movement toward the northern hemisphere, or Uttarayana, is counted from this day. It is actually called Uttarayana punyakalam.  In the Mahabaratha epic, Bheesma, who was felled in Dakshinayana chose to remain alive on a bed of arrows made by Arjuna until Uttarayana punyakala began and then only actually left this world. The last day of Dakshinayana is also considered to be day to wash off the previous year's sins and on the last day of Margazhi the houses are cleaned and unwanted things thrown out - some believe that it is the Tamil world 'pokki; or removal, which got changed over time to Bhogi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margazhi is a month of prayers. While two of the most important temple functions - vaikunta ekadesi in Srirangam and arudra darshan in Chidambaram - take place during the month, there are no festivals celebrated at home. So even on Bhogi day there are really no pujas. &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Come Thai - bang start festivals: Pongal on the first day of Thai is primarily thanks giving to Sun. The religious puja that accompanies this is called Suryanarayana puja as on this day Surya or Sun is considered to be Sri Vishnu or Narayana himself. Mattu pongal the next day is also part of thanksgiving to cows specifically, but cattle generally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish you all a very happy Pongal !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Annual General Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is this time of the year when the committee has to reflect on the activities and accomplishments of SIS in the year just passed.  The SIS Annual General Meeting will be held on the 28th of January 2012.  A formal notice has been sent to all the paid members. We request all members to attend the AGM and contribute with your feedback.  Your feedback matters a lot to the organization and it is the only constructive way to take the organization to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;It is generally the custom for the new committee to plan the events for the year and announce. The new committee will take charge at the AGM on the 28th of January and the event for the month of February will be announced soon after they take charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monthly Bhajans that generally happens on the 3rd Saturday of the month are due to start for this year on 21st of January at the Sindhi Mandhir.  More details are available on the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also confident that you continue to enjoy the daily Thiruppavai on our website. We also believe that the articles that we are publishing on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone-up multifold. This month, we have uploaded more interesting articles. We hope you will enjoy reading all the articles on the website. Please visit our website and read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;


 &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt; ]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>