<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20110711054943</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - July 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society July 2011 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter July 2011</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2011-08-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>July</NMonth>
  <NYear>2011</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to compile this newsletter with two success stories. The first is the Sampradhaya Bhajanai at East London that was held on the 12th of June at Saiva Munnettra Sangam.  The Bhajanai was led extremely well, with great song selection and was conducted with military precision. A divine afternoon that was well attended and thanks to Mr. Balasubramanian for creating an atmosphere of ecstasy. Click &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/sisnambalava/SISLondonBhajanai?authkey=Gv1sRgCMymq_Kys4a3mwE" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view the photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was SIS Cricket Galatta at Harrow Country club cricket club on the 9th of July, Essex Eagles and Bucks Bears played two matches in the same day. Essex Eagles won the championship of the year. It was a good treat for all SIS cricket lovers and a great day out for everyone who could make it to the event. Click &lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/sisnambalava/SISLondonCricketGalatta2011?authkey=Gv1sRgCNiWoe_DiaDaDQ" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view all the photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sponsors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that DialtoSave a company that provides facility to make calls to India and other countries at an economical rate joined HDFC London as sponsors. We look forward for a long standing relationship with DailtoSave and HDFC London.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forthcoming Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Sri Vasudeva Battar, who has learnt to perform upanyasam from Sri Anantharama Dikshadar will give a discourse on “Prahladha Charitram” on the 7th of August at Church of Ascension Hall on Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB. Some of the members have listened to his Upanyasam a few times and his depth of knowledge and his command on the subject is outstanding. We request you to bring your children along as well and they will get exposed to the original Indian culture in a British environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we get closer to Dasara, it is time for Kolattam. Yes 17th of September evening will be a Kolattam and Karaoke evening. SIS will celebrate Deepavali on the 29th of October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details of all the events are available under the Events Section on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Members are requested to attend these events with your family and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;
13th of August is Yajur Upakarma.  We will upload (in the next day) the sankalpam to help our members carry-out their duties with ease.  Other interesting articles are uploaded for this month including, a wonderful Kavidhai, Great Engineers of Ancient India, Guru Pooja, etc... to our website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Please visit the website, read the articles and let us know your views.  We also welcome articles from all our members and will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an advance preparation for Deepavali, we would like to publish snacks and sweets recipes on our website. We welcome recipes of new types of snacks and sweets and the recipes of our traditional ones that contain special tips.  Please write to us of the recipes that you have tried and you want to share with your friends. We will upload it in September.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success of Charity Drive so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, SIS committee initiated a charity drive to support Raja Veda Patasala in Kumbakonam, one of the oldest Veda Patasalas in India dating back to 1542. We are extremely pleased that we have collected over £700 so far. We have set ourselves an aggressive target of £5000/- for this year. We are committed to this cause and wish to assure you that the entire proceeds from this charity drive will be donated to the Veda Patasala once the target is achieved, or at least when the amount collected is close to the target,  so that they could use this as corpus amount and get return from this for their expenses. We will keep you informed periodically.   The Committee requests you all to donate generously to this noble cause.  You can easily transfer the money as a lump sum to be added to the corpus amount or set up standing order through your bank to the following SIS account: &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Name: South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
Sort Code:   20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
Account No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Patasala&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

Please do not forget to mention ‘Patasala’ in the reference section of the transfer form. 
For more information on the Patasala please visit &lt;a href="http://www.rajapatasala.in" target="_blank"&gt;www.rajapatasala.in&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May we request those of you who have not yet paid your annual membership of (£20), to please do so at the earliest?  You can send your cheque in the name of "South Indian Society" and mail it to the address below or alternatively make the payment via bank transfer to SIS Account (details given below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mailing address&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No 7 Erroll Road&lt;br /&gt;
Romford&lt;br /&gt;
Essex&lt;br /&gt;
RM1 3DJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bank account details&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bank Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
A/c Name:  South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
A/c No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Membership
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country.  We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the summer and see you all at the Upanyasam on the 7th of August.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>