<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20120609081859</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - June 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society June 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter June 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-07-8</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>June</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;The four day long Queen’s diamond Jubilee celebrations are just over. We are confident that you all had fun whatever you were doing. Witnessing the event directly in the city; Watching the events live on tele; Participating in the street parties in your area; Having your own parties with family and friends; For those who are continuing their holidays for the rest of the week, we wish you lots of fun and good luck.  We had a brief spell of sunshine but rain has taken control again. But brighter days are yet to come. The mantra for happier life is “Hope”.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;We at SIS had a very well attended Satsang on the 2nd of June at Ilford. Final preparations are being done for the most awaited SIS Sunset Cruise in Thames.  We can’t wait but dive into the cruise event directly 'pun intended'...&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;h2&gt;SIS Sunset Cruise on Thames - Saturday, the 16th of June&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;SIS Sunset Cruise on Thames is set to sail.  The cruise is houseful and we thank you all for the overwhelming support. Tickets and other information will be mailed to those who have confirmed and paid. We have absolutely no tickets to be sold and the cruise operator has confirmed that they can’t take any more.  &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;color:Red"&gt;So our sincere request is not to bring any additional guests for whom you have not already paid.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;h2&gt;SIS Cricket Galatta 2012 – Saturday the 7th of July&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;On the 7th of July, Essex Ekambaram XI, Harrow Sendamarai XI, Middlesex Mailvaganam XI, Bucks Balakrishna XI will meet each other at Hatch End Playing fields, to decide the strongest team yet again. Do we have a Tendulkar, Dhoni, Kohli, Raina, Sehwag, Badrinath or Chris Gayle disguised in our society? We don’t know yet. That will be revealed on Saturday the 7th of July at the annual SIS Cricket Galatta.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Yes. Trustees of SIS proudly announce the most awaited SIS Cricket 2012. After a grand success of SIS Cricket event in the last two years and due to popular demand, we have organised the event for this year on the Saturday the 7th of July 2012. &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Admission&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;As an incentive to encourage early confirmations and payments whilst simultaneously attempting to keep costs and food wastage down to the minimum, the entrance fee has been restructured as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Reduced fee for Members Confirming &amp; Paying in advance (by 1st July): £7 (Preferred option)&lt;br /&gt;
                Members paying at the venue: £10&lt;br /&gt;
                Non members : £12&lt;br /&gt;
                Children (between 5 and 10) : £4&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Agenda&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;9:00 am to 10:00 am: Assembly and practice&lt;br /&gt;
                10:00 am to 12:30 pm: Cricket&lt;br /&gt;
                12:30 pm to 1:30 pm: Lunch&lt;br /&gt;
                1:30 pm to 4:30 pm: Cricket
                &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;PS: Other fun activities to happen outside the cricket pitch.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; Hatch End Playing fields, 171 Uxbridge Road, Hatch End, HA5 4EA&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Thanks for those who have already confirmed and sent in your expertise. We request you to register yourselves for the event at the earliest, by sending an e-mail to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; stating your expertise (bowling / batting / wicket keeping / cheering). The SIS cricket 2012 count starts now...&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;h2&gt;SIS Charity Drive Continues...&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Last year, we ran a charity drive to sponsor Raja Veda Patasala in Kumbakonam India.  We had an overwhelming response for the drive which showed the true character of the members of SIS. The Trustees of SIS are pleased to inform you that we have completed last year’s project, by donating a sum of Rs. 150,000/- (Rupees One Lakh and Fifty Thousand only).  This money we donated will help sponsoring one child’s Veda education at the Patasala year on year.  We would like to pass on the Patasala’s gratitude to every member of SIS.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;h2&gt;SIS Carnival 2012&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:Blue;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Contributing back to the society while having fun!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt; How does it sound? Very interesting isn’t it? By August, we should have successfully completed two major milestones in this year, The Queen’s Diamond Jubilee celebrations and the Olympics 2012. We thought, it may be a good opportunity for SIS to celebrate by having an SIS Carnival, have fun and contribute back to the society. &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 18th August 2012&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 pm and 7 pm&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; St Andrews Church, 89 Malvern Avenue, Harrow, Middlesex, HA2 9ER Roxbourne, Harrow&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;What will we have at the SIS Carnival? We are planning to have number of food stalls, mehandi stall, jewellery stalls, books, paintings, face painting, games and many more….. We guarantee that, it will be a perfect day out on a beautiful August afternoon where we as SIS family with our friends can contribute something back to the society while having food and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;More details on the carnival will be sent in a separate e-mail.  &lt;span style="color:red; font-weight:bold;"&gt;We invite volunteers to set-up stalls&lt;/span&gt;.  Please send an e-mail to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; and we will contact you directly.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This is an initiative with an intention to donate money to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.shootingstarchase.org.uk/" targe="_blank" &gt;Shooting Star Children’s Hospice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gosh.org/" targe="_blank" &gt;Great Ormond Street Hospital &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. All funds mobilised through the event will be contributed equally to the two organisations.  We think this is a perfect way to pay something back to the society in which we live in this year when the Queen celebrates the Diamond Jubilee.  We request you to make all sincere efforts to participate in this carnival and donate generously.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Here is the line-up of SIS events for the rest of the year. Apart from the monthly Satsang, we have lined-up number of interesting events for the rest of the year.  E-mails will be sent and details will be made available on the website www.sisnambalava.org.uk, closer to the event. &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7th July:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Cricket Galatta&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;strong&gt;18th Aug:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Carnival 2012&lt;br /&gt; 
                &lt;strong&gt;15th Sep:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Career Event (Career guidance event to SIS youth)&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;strong&gt;20th Oct:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Musical Galatta &lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;strong&gt;17th Nov:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Deepavali&lt;br /&gt;
                &lt;strong&gt;15th Dec:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Youth Event (An event organised by SIS youth)
                &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Please mark your calendar and we request you to participate in all the SIS events&lt;/p&gt;
                
                &lt;h2&gt;The Website&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;The website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; is being redesigned. The website with the new layout will be launched in the middle of July. We trust that the articles being published on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone up multi-fold. Please visit our website to read the articles and kindly let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie, South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
                
                &lt;h2&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/h2&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

                ]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>