<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20110313023354</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - March 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society March 2011 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter March 2011</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2011-04-1</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>March</NMonth>
  <NYear>2011</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Greetings All.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to compile the 2nd Newsletter for the year 2011. We are able to do this, because of the encouragement that we have been receiving from you. We request you to continue supporting us on all the initiatives that we take to the benefit of the South Indian Society Nambalava Community.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil months of Maasi and Panguni&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tamil months of Maasi and Panguni are two important months in Tamil calendar.  Maha Shivarathri, All Maasi Tuesdays are important (It has been a practice to observe uppu illa vridham i.e have food without salt and maintain silence for the whole day (most difficult things for us)), Maasi Magam, Kara Adaiyar Nonbu, Panguni Uthiram, Sri Rama Navami etc.  etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have uploaded articles on a few key events in Maasi and Panguni to our website sisnambalava.org.uk.  We are confident that there will be number of new things to learn / recollect to tell our children / grand children about our religion and their significance. We have added a recipe for delicious adai (sweet and salt).  Hope you will try the recipe and observe the noonbu on Monday the 14th of March.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Health and Fun afternoon in March&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We have scheduled a health and fun afternoon on 20th of March. Dr. Maheshwar an ENT specialist has volunteered to give a talk on his area of speciality that afternoon.  Common ENT related issues, early identification and prevention (where possible) will be the focus of his talk.  This will be followed by a Bingo with a difference by Smt. Raji Rajagopal (To know more about the difference in this version of Bingo, you have to come and experience).  We will wind-up with some nibbles and tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And all this is for FREE FOR MEMBERS AND THEIR FAMILIES !!! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details of venue can be found at the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please send RSVP by 15th of March, by sending an e-mail to sisnambalava@gmail.com.  You can also send your questions to Dr. Maheshwar to the same e-mail address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please mark your calendar for the Tamil New Year's day celebrations on the 30th of April and for the May monthly event on the 29th of May. Full details of all these events will be sent  via email to members shortly and also made available on the website under upcoming events. Members are most welcome to come up with any suggestions for these events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success of Charity Drive so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, last month SIS committee kick started a charity drive to support Rajapatasala in Kumbakonam, one of the oldest Veda Patasala in India started way back in 1542. We are extremely pleased with the response we have got to support the drive. We have collected over £400 so far. We are committed for this cause and we assure that the entire proceeds from this charity drive will be donated to the Veda Patasala.  The Committee requests you all to donate generously to this noble cause.  You can easily transfer the money / set standing order through your bank to the following SIS account:  Name: South Indian Society&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
Account No. 50284645&lt;br/ &gt;
Ref: Patasala&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on the Patasala please visit &lt;a href="http://www.rajapatasala.in"&gt;www.rajapatasala.in&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you all know, we re-vamped the sisnambalava website in November. Since then we have uploaded several interesting articles and useful information like gurukkal contacts, London Temple information, Panchangam etc.. We have had huge number of hits on our website and positive feedback about the quality of contents. This month, we have uploaded a number of new articles relating to religion, cricket and a recipe on our website http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/ Please visit the website, read the articles and let us know your views.  We welcome articles from all our members.  The articles will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several vetarans of our community in this country.  We sincerely thank every one who has contributed for the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation cannot grow. For those who have not paid the annual membership, can we request you pay your membership (£20/-) at the earliest? You can send your cheque in the name of "South Indian Society" and mail it to the address or through bank transfer details given below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mailing address&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No 7 Erroll Road&lt;br /&gt;
Romford&lt;br /&gt;
Essex&lt;br /&gt;
RM1 3DJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bank account details&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bank Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
A/c Name:  South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
A/c No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Membership&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you all at  the next event on 20th March.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>