<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20140311055448</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter March 2014</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS March 2014 Newsletter. Information about Tamil New year celebrations 2014, Monthly Satsang and Yoga workshop etc.,</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter March 2014</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2014-04-14</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>March</NMonth>
  <NYear>2014</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Bhagavat Gita the ultimate guide to proper living, tells us how we should speak. ‘Anudvegaram, sathyam, priya-hitham vakhyam’ XVII-15: speech that causes no annoyance, truthful, loving and beneficial. It emphasises self-control – ‘a wandering mind carries away reason, much the same way gale blows away a ship on the ocean’, II-67. In particular, Gita, points to ‘kama and kroda’, lust and anger, as our greatest enemies, III-37. Meditation, sustained and regular, is the surest way to help achieve self-control. Observing regular mouna vritham is another way of improving one’s self-control and being able to speak properly and wisely. Mahatma Gandhi used to practise it regularly. Kanchi Mahaswamigal used to observe, not just mauna vratam, but, kasta mauna vratam, where he did not even communicate through hand signals on chosen days! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we are entering the Tamil month of Maasi, it may be useful to remind ourselves that during Maasi, our forefathers used to practise mouna vritham on all Tuesdays.  Might be, we can all try to observe mouna vritham at least for one hour on each maasi Tuesdays!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maasi is significant for another reason. On the 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; night/14&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; day in the Krishna Paksham in the Tamil month of Maasi, Mahasivarathri is observed. This year, Mahasivarathri falls on Thursday, the 27&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of February. It is not just a day for prayers, but, for fasting. Fasting is an important aspect of self-control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one explains the significance of Mahasivarathri with greater authority or clarity than Kanchi Mahaperiaval: do read what he said about &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/religion/significance-of-sivarathri-20110212031357.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Mahasivarathri&lt;/a&gt; in our website: You may also read another interesting article about &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/religion/maha-shivaratri-20130219155205.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Mahasivarathri&lt;/a&gt; by a SIS member, Mr. Rajja Rajagopalan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mahasivarathri day devotees fast and perform pooja to Lord Shiva and visit Shiva temples. Let’s all do Shiva Pooja on Shivarathri and get the blessings of Lord Shiva.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Yoga for All – 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; March 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; March 2014&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 5 pm (Assembly @ 2:30 pm for a 3 pm start)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; Victoria Hall, Sheepcote Rd, Harrow, Middlesex HA1 2JE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FREE ! ! ! ALL ARE WELCOME!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RSVP:&lt;/strong&gt; Please send RSVP by sending an e-mail to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; by 9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; March to help us plan the logistics and also give more detailed instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;About the trainer:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shyamala alias Sam is a self-motivated and passionate yoga instructor, who has been inspired by her guru Sri Asana Andiappan who practices and lives the yogic philosophies until today in his 80's.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She qualified as a Yoga therapist at the renowned Andiappan college of Yoga and research, Chennai, India, successfully completing an intensive Yoga Therapy course and basic principles of Ayurveda. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is certified to instruct Yoga in corporate circles, community centres, sport and leisure and schools.  She has developed her own style of teaching that combines Vinyasa and Ashtanga delivered with a touch of Iyengar Yoga making it suitable for all ability levels and those with particular health issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam has actively participated and volunteered to travel in her groups for yogic and meditation courses and workshops conducted in India, Malaysia and Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS March Satsang – 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; March 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Chandrasekharan and Mrs. Bhanumathi Chandrasekharan have kindly volunteered to host the March Satsang at their their residence on Saturday, the 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; of March 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 Bonington Road, Hornchurch, RM12 6TH&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP can be sent by replying to this e-mail or by calling Mr. Chandrasekharan and Mrs. Bhanumathi on 01708 471242&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Forthcoming Events&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Trustees held their first meeting after the AGM. Mr Sundar was elected as the Chairman and the portfolios and responsibilities of all the Trustees agreed. Mr Sathish will be the Secretary and Treasurer. The Trustees confirmed the immediate key-events for the year.  Details of the events line-up till July are as below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; March&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; March&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Yoga for All – A Yoga Workshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; April&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; April&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Vaanavil – SIS Kids Event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; June&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; July&lt;/strong&gt; SIS Sports Event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details on all our events are posted in our &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;The Website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We trust that the articles that we are publishing on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone up multifold. This month, we have uploaded more interesting articles. We hope you will enjoy reading all the articles on the website. Please visit &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;., read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our patrons that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines. &lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>