<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20130318113345</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>Newsletter - March 2013</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS March 2013 Newsletter. Information about SIS 25th Anniversary, Swami Vivekananda's 150th Birth Anniversary, Tamil New year 2013 celebrations etc.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter March 2013</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2013-04-13</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>March</NMonth>
  <NYear>2013</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Spring time is in the air&lt;br /&gt;
you can see signs everywhere&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 

flower buds are blooming &lt;br /&gt;
songs of birds are tuning &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

mothers teach their newborn young &lt;br /&gt;
that their lives have just begun &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

listen, listen, for the sweet sounds &lt;br /&gt;
music, it is all around &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

I feel so free now...or &lt;br /&gt;
is it me? &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

watch new animals tumble &lt;br /&gt;
then fumble... &lt;br /&gt;
smell flowers &lt;br /&gt;
see spring showers, &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

isn't it grand... &lt;br /&gt;
to hold spring in the palm of your hand? &lt;br /&gt;
--Lindsay 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like to start the newsletter with this beautiful poem by Lindsay. After a harsh winter, we all look forward for a wonderful Spring.  Also in life, we always look for some green-shoots.  We sincerely pray the almighty we all have a wonderful spring in all aspects of life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year it is an important year for every Indian, as India celebrates the 150th Birth Anniversary of Swami Vivekananda.  It is also a very important year for every SIS member, as this happens to be the 25th Anniversary year for SIS.  We take the pride in celebrating these two important milestones.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS - 25th Anniversary Year&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is 25 years since SIS started. That an institution has thrived and grown over a quarter of a century, run entirely by volunteers, is remarkable. Throughout 2013, we plan to celebrate this great achievement, with nostalgic memories of the past and hopes for an even greater future, and, with the involvement of as many members and past trustees of the society as possible. Our Diwali celebrations will in particular focus on this.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;150th Birth Anniversary Year of Swami Vivekananda&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many regard Swami Vivekananda as a modern day Sankaracharya: deeply rooted in Hindu culture, a great scholar, and yet a modernist, he has done more than anyone else to revive Hinduism in the late 19th century and make it relevant for the present days. Like Adi Sankara himself and the great mathematician Ramanujam, Vivekananda fulfilled his life's mission before he reached the age of 40. During 2013 we in SIS plan to celebrate his 150th birth anniversary, with competitions for our youngsters, special articles posted in our website etc., 'From Madras to Chicago – the Epochal Journey of Swami Vivekananda' - will be the first of such articles."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations – April 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, Tamil New Year falls on Sunday the 14th of April 2013. We at SIS plan to celebrate Tamil New Year (Vijaya Varuda Pirappu Kondattangal) on the 27th of April 2013. The Tamil New Year Celebrations is one of the key events for SIS, because, 25 years back, this was the maiden event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:red; font-weight: bold; text-decoration:underline; font-size:14px;"&gt;As usual we would like to showcase the talent in us and we therefore request volunteers to please contact one of the committee members or send an e-mail to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; with your contact details by Sunday, the 24th of March. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the committee members will contact you. Please visit the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/" target="_blank"&gt; events&lt;/a&gt; page to find out more about the event.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS April Satsang – 6th April 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Padmanabhan and Mrs. Lalitha Padmanabhan have kindly volunteered to host the April SIS Satsang at their residence on the 6th of April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt; 17 Marsh Hall, Talisman Way, Wembley, HA9 8JJ&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;span style="color:red; font-weight: bold"&gt;RSVP by 5th April&lt;/span&gt; either by e-mailing &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or contacting Mr. Padmanabhan or Mrs.Lalitha Padmanabhan directly on 020 8930 4131. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Events Line-up&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is the list of events lined-up for April and May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6th April - SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;27th April -  SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;04th May - SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;26th May - SIS Sunset Cruise on Thames&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events.  Details on all our events are posted in our &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;The Website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, we have uploaded several articles, which we hope you will find interesting and useful. 
We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, i.e., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>