<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20120314054322</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - March 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society March 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter March 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-04-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>March</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Daffodils and butterflies,&lt;br /&gt;
are dancing in the breeze,&lt;br /&gt;
The tulips rebirth,&lt;br /&gt;
Makes my heart feel so free.&lt;br /&gt;
As I wander through the vale&lt;br /&gt;
smelling the freshness of the earth&lt;br /&gt;
My heart feels a'ready to burst&lt;br /&gt;
Taking all of life and love in to my own&lt;br /&gt;
So open up your heart,&lt;br /&gt;
Let your blessing flow,&lt;br /&gt;
to lift the spirit of someone you know.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 
-- Author not known (Inspirational Poems)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the biting cold, we enter a well deserved spring with some excellent sunshine, slightly better economic news, UK celebrating the Queen’s Diamond Jubilee and London getting ready for the 2012 Olympics.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;In Hindu religion, every month is important and we always have something to look forward to. Maha Sivarathri, Maasi Magam, Kaaradayar Nonbu fall in the month of Maasi (மாசி). This year, Karadayar Nonbu (காரடையார்நோன்பு) falls on Wednesday the 14th of March.  On that day, also celebrated as Sathyavan Savithri Vritham, it is the custom for the ladies to cook Kara adai (கார அடை)and Uppu adai (உப்பு அடை), present it to Lord Parvathi and tie the nonbu saradu (நோன்புசரடு)around the right wrist. Recipe for Kara adai and Uppu adai are available on the website. With this nonbu, which is also known as maasiyum Panguniyum koodugira noonbu (மாசியும்பங்குனியும்கூடுகிறநோன்பு) we nicely enter the last month of the year, Panguni (பங்குனி).  Panguni is another important month with Sri Rama Navami and number of car (தேர்) festivals across different temples in Tamil Nadu.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Initiatives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The new committee for the year 2012, which took its office end of January, had their first meeting in February. Portfolios for the committee members were agreed. A new initiative, SIS monthly Satsang, was started in February with the first Satsang volunteered by Mr and Mrs Chandrashekaran.  We are pleased with the response and several members have expressed their interest in hosting future Satsangs. The next available ‘free’ slot is September and we will be delighted to hear from members wanting to host it.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We had a very informative SIS Health event on Saturday the 10th of March and extend our sincere thanks to Mr. Amarendra Vasireddy who spoke on Cardio Vascular diseases.  Mr. Amar made the subject very interesting, simple and easy to understand and answered questions with patience and involvement.  Please keep an eye on the website www.sisnamblava.org.ukfor a summary of the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Youth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that starting this month we will carry articles to cater to our youth giving career and other relevant advice in the SIS website. Dr Mythili Venkateswaran, a seasoned educationalist, has kindly contributed tips that could help our SIS youth in taking career directions.  This month, her message is “Be sold on yourself”.  This will be an ongoing series.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we are planning to conduct a careers afternoon in May. We aim to arrange for talks from experienced professionals in field of education, provide counselling, one-to-one sessions, mock interviews etc.  We will also bring in some senior students and alumni from eminent colleges to share their experiences. Details will be published in due course. We welcome suggestions and recommendations for this event and also volunteers to contribute. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Forthcoming events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;SIS Tamil New Year celebration (Nanthana Varuda Pirappu Kondattangal) is scheduled for Saturday the 21st of April. As always, the evening will be packed with entertainment with number of exciting programmes that would cater to people of all age groups. More details available on the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/tamil-new-year-celebrations-2012-20120214092237.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We request all members to send RSVP and pay by the Thursday, the 19th of April to enjoy discounted price.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Events line-up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14th April SIS Monthly Satsang (rescheduled from the earlier planned 7th April due to Easter break)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;21st April SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5th May SIS Monthly Satsang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;19th May SIS Careers Event (tentative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next monthly Bhajans sponsored by SIS is scheduled for Saturday the 17th of March at the Sindhi Mandhir between 3 pm and 5 pm.  More details are available on the website.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendars for all SIS events. Details of all the events are available under the Events Section on the website www.sisnambalava.org.uk. Members are requested to attend these events with your family and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We trust that the articles being published on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone up multi-fold. Please visit our website to read the articles and kindly let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie, South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>