<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20130529081513</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter May 2013</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS May 2013 Newsletter. Information about SIS Alaigal Oyivathillai 2013 celebrations, Monthly Satsang, South Indian Society next events etc</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter May 2013</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2013-06-20</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>May</NMonth>
  <NYear>2013</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;வாழ்க்கை பூட்டியே கிடக்கிறது&lt;br&gt;
சிரிப்புச் சத்தம் கேட்கும்போதெல்லாம்&lt;br&gt;
அது திறந்து கொள்கிறது&lt;br&gt;

வாழ்வின்மீது இயற்கை தெளித்த&lt;br&gt;
வாசனைத் தைலம் சிரிப்பு&lt;br&gt;

எந்த உதடும் பேசத் தெரிந்த&lt;br&gt;
சர்வதேச மொழி சிரிப்பு

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We would like to start this month newsletter with the beautiful words of Vairamuthu.  Let’s remind ourselves to keep smiling all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer is round the corner and exciting times lie ahead.  With IPL knock-outs and finals this weekend, the Champions Trophy in UK and Tennis season yet to begin, we at SIS also have exciting next few months, with Alaigal Oivadhillai in May followed by Bakthi Navarathri in July. While planning is in full swing for the key events, you can enjoy the &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=En0MQTBwfUs" target="_blank"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; of the SIS Tamil New Year’s day celebrations with some good &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/others/the-king-of-all-fruits-mangoes-20130521024533.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Mangoes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Alaigal Oivadhillai – 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; May 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:red; font-weight: bold"&gt;Thanks for the overwhelming response. The boat is now fully booked. We have absolutely no tickets to be sold. So our sincere request is not to bring any additional guests for whom you have not already paid.&lt;/span&gt; For those who have booked and paid, details about parking and other information will be sent later this week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS June Satsang – 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; June 2013&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Swaminathan and Mrs. Usha Swaminathan has kindly volunteered to host the June SIS Satsang at their residence.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt; 51, Shimbrooks, Great Leighs, Chelmsford, Essex, CM3 1SG&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;span style="color:red; font-weight: bold"&gt;RSVP by 31&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; May&lt;/span&gt; either by e-mailing &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or by contacting Mrs. Usha or Mr. Swaminathan directly on 01245 360409.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to seeing you all at the Satsang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Bakthi Navarathri (5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; July to 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; July)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIS proudly announces organizing a series of discourses in Tamil in various locations in London by Smt Desa Mangayarkarasi during 5th to 13&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; July, 2013. Smt Mangayarkarasi was a child prodigy. She won her first Kural recitation contest when she was hardly 4 years of age. Her father rarely missed an opportunity to take her to Variar Swamy’s discourses and when she was 6 years of age, Variar asked her to speak in one of his discourses: something he continued to do so long as he was alive.  Click &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/religion/smt-desa-mangayarkarasi-in-london-during-july-2013-20130501055928.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read more about Mangayarkarasi..
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please click &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/images/events/sis-bhakti-navarathri.jpg" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the event, topics covered at various locations and tickets information.


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;The Website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, we have uploaded several articles, which we hope you will find interesting and useful. 
We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, i.e., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>