<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20120510050132</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - May 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society May 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter May 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-06-08</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>May</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We are fortunate to be in the United Kingdom when the country is celebrating one of the most significant events in the history of the British Monarchy.  The Diamond Jubilee marks 60 years of the Queen’s reign.  The Queen is the only British Monarch to celebrate a Diamond Jubilee other than Queen Victoria in 1897.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;There are celebrations all over the United Kingdom and more importantly it is a Bank holiday weekend.  We wish you fun and good luck with what ever you are planning to do over the long weekend in June. &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Back in India, Madurai celebrated the famous Chithirai Thiruvizha last week.  This year Chithirai Thiruvonam  falls on the 12th of May.  It is a tradition to perform abishegam to Lord Natarajar and Sivakamasundari on that day. For those who are not aware, this is one of the only six abishegams performed at Chidambaram in a year.  Lord Shiva is Abishega priyan and it may be a great idea to visit Natarajar temple witness abishegam and participate in the pooja on that day and get the blessings of Lord Natarajar.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forth coming events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We had a very well attended and successful SIS Tamil New Year event in April.  For those who could not make it to the event, I am sure you had a chance to take a look at the photos and video of the event. After the big success, we thought to give a slight pause this month, only to prepare for the next mega events planned in June and July.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS June Satsang -- Saturday, the 2nd of June&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Nagarajan and Mrs.Anandhi Nagarajan have kindly volunteered to host the June month’s SIS Satsang at their residence.  It is Sani Pradosham on that day and attending Satsang is probably one of the best things to do.  Majority of those who participate in the Satsang will be driving to London Sri Murugan temple to witness the special abishegam done and participate in the poojato Lord Shiva.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Address: 8, Glenham Drive, Ilford Essex, IG2 6SG&lt;br /&gt;
Time: 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP by 1st June either by e-mailing sisnambalava@gmail.comor contacting Mrs. Anandhi Nagarajan  directly on 020 8518 2652.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Sunset Cruise on Thames - Saturday, the 16th of June&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The last few seats are available to grab.  One more day to go…….&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The last few seats are available to grabfor the SIS Sunset Cruise on June 16, Saturday. Cruising will never be the same again!!! An unforgettable evening with namma crowd. A life time of cherished memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s just one more day to go folks for the discounted rates to close. Experience the magic of River Thames as the Queen and her family are planning to do during the Jubilee celebrations.
The rush is like the Boxing Day shopping at Lakeside or Westfield!!!! Don’t miss out and be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An intoxicating evening is just a click away. Make sure you are there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date                 : Saturday the 16th of June 2012&lt;br /&gt;
Venue              : Will be announced closer to the date&lt;br /&gt;
Registration - 5:00 pm&lt;br /&gt;
Check-in - 5:15 pm&lt;br /&gt;
Start sailing – 6:00 pm (sharp)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reduced fee for Members Confirming &amp; Paying in advance (by 10th May): £15 (Preferred option)&lt;br /&gt;
Non-Members paying in advance: £20&lt;br /&gt;
Members and Non-members paying at entrance: £25&lt;br /&gt;
Children between 5 and 10: £10&lt;br /&gt;
Children (below 5): FREE.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Cricket 2012 – Saturday the 7th of July&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The Indian Premier League season is hot in India which can be felt even here where we get glued in front of the tele watching nail biting finishes. The English players are back in England preparing for their big summer season before their T20 world cup in Sri Lanka.  As they prepare themselves, we prepare for the SIS Cricket 2012. &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday the 7th of July 2012&lt;br /&gt;
Venue: TBD&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We request you to register yourselves for the event at the earliest, by sending an e-mail to sisnambalava@gmail.comstating your expertise (bowling / batting / wicket keeping / cheering).  The SIS cricket 2012 count starts now ……&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We trust that the articles being published on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone up multi-fold. We have uploaded Pambu Panjangam on the website for ready reference. Please visit our website to read the articles and kindly let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie, South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>