<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20110509102324</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - May 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society May 2011 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter May 2011</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2011-06-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>May</NMonth>
  <NYear>2011</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIS celebrated Tamil New Year function (welcoming Kara varusham) on the 30th of April at the Church of Ascension Hall. Tamil New Year celebration is very important to SIS for the fact that the first function SIS had celebrated after its formation was Tamil New Year (welcoming Vibava varusham).&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights of Tamil New Year Programme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The programme started at 6 pm sharp with Prayer song, Panchangam Padalam followed by excellent high quality entertainment.  The programme was presented and received well to the fullest satisfaction of all participants and attendee and finished at about 8:15 pm as planned followed by some tasty food.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are all aware, a new pricing model was introduced this time. This worked very well. It was a win-win situation for everyone.  Members got to enjoy high quality entertainment and food at a subsidised rate as the trustees could plan well.  We are pleased to say that there was absolutely no wastage or shortage of food, which was what all of us wanted to achieve. We thank everyone who could make it for the event and thank every participant for giving a high class performance. We wish you all good luck and for a bright future. SIS is committed to provide a stage to showcase your talents. We have posted a brief summary of the event and photographs on our website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; Trustees are open for feedback.  Please send your comments to sisnambalava@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forthcoming Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The next Monthly Meeting will be held on Sunday the 29th of May between 1-4 p.m. at the Church of Ascension Hall, Beaufort Road, London W5 3EB (off North Circular Road, A406).  At this meeting, Mr Vedanarayanan, a long-standing member, will present a slide show of temples of South India with brief narrative about each temple. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the June Monthly Meeting on 12th Sampradhaya Bajanai will be held at Ilford, by Mr. Balasubramanian and his group.  Details to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the grand success of the SIS Cricket Event last year, we have scheduled to hold this year's cricket event on the 9th of July in Harrow.  In order to help us plan better, we request you to send in your participation and your area of expertise in cricket (could be bowling, batting, wicket keeping, umpiring or all of them) as soon as possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details of all the events are available under the Events Section on the website.  As we update them with details of events as and when they are finalised, please keep visiting the Nambalava website.  Members are requested to attend these meetings and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions. &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you may have already noticed, we are taking all possible efforts to provide interesting and useful articles on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; We are encouraged by the number of visits on our website globally, which is only increasing multi-fold every month. We have uploaded soft copy of Kara Varuda Paambu Panchangam, names of 60 Tamil years, Hanuman Chaleesa with meaning, relevance of Upanishad to business management and many more. Please visit the website, read the articles and let us know your views.  We also welcome articles from all our members.  The articles will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success of Charity Drive so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, last month the SIS committee initiated a charity drive to support Raja Veda Patasala in Kumbakonam, one of the oldest Veda Patasalas in India dating back to 1542. We are extremely pleased that we  have collected over £500 so far. We have set ourselves an aggressive target of £5000/- for this year. We are committed to this cause and wish to assure you that the entire proceeds from this charity drive will be donated to the Veda Patasala once the target is achieved, or at least when the amount collected is close to the target,  so that they could use this as corpus amount and get return from this for their expenses. We will keep you informed periodically.   The Committee requests you all to donate generously to this noble cause.  You can easily transfer the money as a lump sum to be added to the corpus amount or set up standing order through your bank to the following SIS account: &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;
Name: South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
Sort Code:   20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
Account No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Patasala&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

Please do not forget to mention ‘Patasala’ in the reference section of the transfer form. 
For more information on the Patasala please visit &lt;a href="http://www.rajapatasala.in" target="_blank"&gt;www.rajapatasala.in&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to inform there has been a sharp increase in the number of new members this year and a number of existing members have paid their annual subscriptions.  May we request those of you who have not yet paid (£20), please do so at the earliest.  You can send your cheque in the name of "South Indian Society" and mail it to the address below or alternatively make the payment via bank transfer to SIS Account (details given below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mailing address&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No 7 Erroll Road&lt;br /&gt;
Romford&lt;br /&gt;
Essex&lt;br /&gt;
RM1 3DJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bank account details&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bank Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
A/c Name:  South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
A/c No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Membership
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country.  We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed. &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the Summer and see you all on the next monthly meeting on the 29th of May.&lt;/p&gt;
 
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>