<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20141121050112</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter November 2014</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS November 2014 Newsletter. Information about 2014 Diwali celebrations, Monthly Satsang etc.,</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter November 2014</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2014-12-21</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>November</NMonth>
  <NYear>2014</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;In Indian culture, light represents knowledge that dispels ignorance.  Light makes it possible to see things clearly..  Light is also considered as a symbol of true auspiciousness, prosperity and abundance which is due to manifestations of inner light and wisdom.  Wisdom is symbolized as light and is said to culminate in infinite happiness.  By lighting lamps in our house, everyday and particularly during Karthigai, let us remind ourselves, that we can be victorious over our impulses and come to illumine for the world around the lamp of wisdom from the land of spiritual light. The lighted lamp symbolizes wisdom that alone leads to happiness.  Would like to quote two important slokas on Diipam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shubham Karoti Kalyaannam-Aarogyam Dhana-Sampadaa |&lt;br&gt;
Shatru-Buddhi-Vinaashaaya Diipa-Jyotir-Namostute ||&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer salutations to the light of the lamp, which brings auspiciousness, health, prosperity and destroys inimical feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diipa-Jyotih Para-Brahma Diipa-Jyotir-Janaardanah |&lt;br&gt;
Diipo Haratu Me Paapam Diipa-Jyotir-Namostute ||&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer salutations to the light of the lamp, which represents Supreme Brahman, Janardhana (other name of Lord Maha Vishnu) and let the light of the lamp remove my sins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lord Shiva is worshiped in Jyothi in Thiruvannamalai.  The Annamalaiyaar Diipam is on 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of December.  People who hail from close to Thiruvannamalai would know that it is a custom to fast on that day till the evening until diipam is witnessed in the evening.  We pray the almighty that this kaarthigai, we light the spiritual light (internal light) and enjoy eternal happiness and enjoy auspiciousness, good health, prosperity and destroy all inimical feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Deepavali event – Update&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIS Deepavali, the flagship event for the SIS Family, witnessed an attendance of over 300 people, was celebrated on the 25th of October.  The event, as always, in line with Indian culture, was well appreciated... and of course the wonderful food, Deepavali marundhu and sweet boxes were welcomed.  The full length video is uploaded on the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/photos.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Souvenir launch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was at the stage of the SIS Deepavali event, SIS silver jubilee souvenir was launched.  The contents of the Souvenir had the range of topics around the Hindu Culture and Ethos, allowing the best of the talents to contribute their opulence of knowledge written by people from all ages. Mr. Raman &amp; Mr. Govindan took the honours of passing the mantle to the next generation, by handing over the Souvenir to the young children, who incidentally had contributed to the contents of the Souvenir.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A copy of the souvenir was given to every family attended the event.  For those who could not come to the event, please feel free to request for your personal copy, by sending a reply to this e-mail.  We will arrange for a copy to reach you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS December Satsang – 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; December 2014 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Balarubramanian and Mrs. Padma Balasubramanian have kindly volunteered to host the SIS December Satsang at their residence on Saturday, the 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of December 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt;198 Limes Avenue, Chigwell, Essex, IG7 5LT&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP by sending an email to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or by contacting Mrs. Padma Balasubramanian directly on 07801517032 by the 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of December 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Annual General Meeting – 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; January 2015&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The SIS Annual General Meeting is scheduled to be held on Saturday, the 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of January 2015. A formal notice will be sent separately to all the paid members.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>