<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20111111060610</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - November 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society November 2011 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter November 2011</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2011-12-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>November</NMonth>
  <NYear>2011</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Let me start this month newsletter with a famous quote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every leaf speaks bliss to me,&lt;br /&gt;
Fluttering from the autumn tree.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Emily Bronte&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all had a great festival season.  It is time when birds hibernate, leaves turn gold and red, for us to sit back and enjoy the occasional autumn sunshine, time to reflect, wither the habits that we always wanted to get rid of and get ready to welcome the New Year.  The shopping malls are all lit-up as shops woo their customers to do their Christmas shopping and the festival mood is set across the country.  That is the advantage of living in Western world as we get a flavor of both East and West.  The trustees of SIS wish you a wonderful festival season ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepavali Celebrations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of SIS did celebrate Deepavali on the 29th of October.  The event started almost on time at 6 pm with number of variety programmes, a prayer song, children fashion show, dance numbers, andha naal nyaabagam  to the grand finale with a short violin concert concluding as usual with food, including deepavali marundhu and a pack of sweets and savouries to everyone who attended.  We tried our best to give the feeling of being in India for Deepavali.  More details about the events, photos and video (2 hr video covering the whole event) are available on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS - Paattu Paada Vaa, Aattam Poda Vaa&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;10th of December members of SIS are going to rock the floor again.  After the Musical Galatta evening in September, we have had number of requests from several of our members to organise a dinner dance evening to end the year on a very high note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;தமிழ் பாட்டு போட நாங்க ரெடி.  பாட்டு பாட, ஆட்டம் போட நீங்க ரெடியா.........?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you all on the 10th of December.. More details will be circulated soon…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details of all the events are available under the Events Section on the website. Members are requested to attend these events with your family and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st Anniversary for the Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; is completing its first year this month in the current format. Since the website was launched same time last year, the website has been kept very active with a number of interesting articles and very useful information.  Photographs and videos of events have also been uploaded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you had an opportunity to try sweets and savories from the recipes published on the website for Deepavali.  We are also confident that the articles that we are publishing on the website are interesting and useful.  We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone-up multifold. This month, we have uploaded more interesting articles, the third in series on “My understanding of Philosophy” by one of our members Mr. Sukumar Panchapakesan.  This month, the subject he has chosen is “Human Goals – Role of Science and Self Knowledge”. There are other articles on update on SIS deepavali celebrations, “Three apples that changed the world”, Thiru Kailai”, “Rediscover Yourself” an experience to Thiru Kailai by Mr. Rajja Rajagopal to name a few. We hope you will enjoy reading all the articles on the website. Please read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success of Charity Drive so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, SIS committee initiated a charity drive to support Raja Veda Patasala in Kumbakonam, one of the oldest Veda Patasalas in India dating back to 1542. We are extremely pleased that we have collected exceeded £1000 so far. For those willing to sponsor, details provided in the website.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;See you all at the SIS Paattu Paada vaa.. Aattam Poda vaa.. evening on the 10th of December.&lt;/p&gt;
 ]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>