<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20121112035724</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - November 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society November 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter November 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-12-7</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>November</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Dear Patrons,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  படபட படவெனப் பட்டா சின்ஒலி!&lt;br&gt;
  பரபர பரவெனப் பட்டா டைஒளி!&lt;br&gt;
  எழுவீர்! எழுவீர்! எங்கும் மகிழ்ச்சி!&lt;br&gt;
  ஏற்றிய தீப ஒளியில் மகிழ்ச்சி!&lt;br&gt;
  -- மீ. ராஜகோபாலன்
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'Festival of Lights' or Deepavali is a festival which has the potential of unifying entire India and everyone of Indian origin, where ever one lives.  It is merely because of the charisma and splendour surrounding this festival. Deepavali has been given the traditional name of 'festival of lights' because of the hundreds and thousands of small oil lamps lighted by many households. The burning of these lights are considered to be the lighted pathway of a person's expression of happiness and also a manner of paying obeisance to God, the Supreme power for attainment of health, prosperity, knowledge, financial security and peace in one's life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beliefs are different in different parts of India.  Some celebrate this as homecoming of Lord Ram, after defeating the evil Ravana; Some celebrate this as victory of Lord Krishna over evil Narakasura; Some celebrate this as Lakshmi Kubera Pooja; In Bengal this relates to Goddess Kali etc. etc.. to name a few. Though everywhere, it is celebrated with the same spirit and signifies the renewal of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought it would be appropriate to wish you this Deepavali with an extract from one of the interesting speeches from Kanchi Maha Periyaval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="border-style:solid; border-width:1px;"&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The True Message of Deepavali&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;There are many books that do teach about true knowledge. More than all of them, a distinction has arisen for the Bhagavad Gita. In the battlefield, when the Bhagavad Gita Upadesam took place, no one knew what was going to happen the next moment. Whether Arjuna was going to survive or Dhuriyodhana was going to survive. It was not certain even if Krishna was going to survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;Even if we get two minutes before our soul departs, within that time we can get to understand true knowledge, and purify our soul. The &lt;strong&gt;jnAnopadesham&lt;/strong&gt; took place because it was important to get &lt;strong&gt;jnAnam&lt;/strong&gt; even if the soul is to depart; and that took place in battlefield.  Since our life is a perfect battlefield and we are all Arjunas in some way and hence every aspect of Gita provides &lt;strong&gt;jnAnopadesham&lt;/strong&gt; to all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;Deepavali can be seen as younger brother of Bhagavad Gita. Just as Bhagavad Gita is more renowned than all others Deepavali too has attained more significance than all other festivals.
This is the only festival that is celebrated all over the country irrespective of religions. Even those who follow Budhism or Jainism celebrate Deepavali. Irrespective of the manner in which the festival is celebrated, to all those who reside in the North and South, the day of Deepavali is one and the same.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;There was a king called &lt;strong&gt;NarakAsura&lt;/strong&gt; who was the son of &lt;strong&gt;bhUmidevI&lt;/strong&gt;.  He was indulging in evil deeds, towards women and Sages. Although he had done several penances, obtaining boons characterised by the quality of ignorance, he caused several evil deeds.  Sri Krishna himself took avatar, adopted many artifices / devices, and destroyed him.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;When the &lt;strong&gt;saMhAram&lt;/strong&gt; took place, grief did not arise to &lt;strong&gt;bhUmidevI&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead, 'To him liberation resulted at the hands of Lord Krishna! To him was given the fortune of seeing Lord Krishna in person! Only by doing great tapas should Lord Krishna be seen! With such penances he got this gift!'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;She also prayed to Lord Krishna. 'That my son is gone be on one side. By the sorrow of losing my son happening to me, no sorrow should arise for the people in the world. On this day my son was gone, everyone should celebrate it with sesame oil bath, wearing new clothes and with a good feast!'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;Like Lord Krishna did Gita Upadesam in the battlefield, when &lt;strong&gt;bhUmidevI&lt;/strong&gt; was weeping in grief due to loss of son, she has sought welfare for the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;'Irrespective of what happens to us, the welfare of the world is important’. Such thought was that of the mother of NarakAsura. That is why we celebrate Deepavali. Instead of dismissing it as some story, people of our country have been nourishing it for generations together, celebrating it as Deepavali festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;What is the real gain for the soul by celebrating this festival?  It is important for us to develop the mental frame of thinking &lt;strong&gt;'May the world be in welfare, even if we suffer'&lt;/strong&gt;.  This is the purpose of celebrating Deepavali.  This is the moral. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="margin-left:5px; margin-right:5px;"&gt;On this day of Deepavali, let us pray for the welfare of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We take this opportunity to &lt;strong&gt;Wish you all a very Happy Deepavali with all the wealth, good health, happiness and prosperity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to seeing you all at the SIS Deepavali Celebrations on Saturday, the 17th of November.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>