<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20111010055919</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - October 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society October 2011 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter October 2011</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2011-11-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>October</NMonth>
  <NYear>2011</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We are confident that you are having a wonderful festive season with colourful new clothes, prayers, Dandia, visiting family and friends and of course plenty of delicious food. The peak of festivity which is Deepavali is just a few weeks away.  Whether we celebrate it as return of Lord Rama to Ayodhya for coronation or as Laksmi Pooja or as victory over darkness it is an opportunity to celebrate, which certainly will bring an upbeat to our spirits and that will only help the economy which is very much required in the current economic climate. We at SIS take this opportunity to wish you all a very happy and bright Deepavali.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepavali Celebrations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIS as it always would like to add colour to the Deepavali celebrations.  We would like to celebrate Deepavali with every one of you. SIS invites you all for Deepavali celebrations on the 29th October at Church of Ascension Hall, The Avenue, Wembley HA9 9QL. As always, you will be guaranteed with loads of fun, excellent food and a great opportunity to socialize. More details are available on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;  Early bird discount for members who confirm and pay in advance closes on the 25th October.  Please confirm and send in your payment at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;5.30 p.m : Registration&lt;br /&gt;
6.00 p.m (sharp) : Cultural Evening&lt;br /&gt;
8:30 p.m : Dinner&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;As an incentive to encourage early confirmations and payments whilst simultaneously attempting to keep costs and food wastage down to the minimum, the entrance fee has been structured as follows:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Reduced fee for Members Confirming &amp; Paying in advance (by 25th October) : £7 (Preferred option)&lt;br /&gt;
Members (at entrance) : £10&lt;br /&gt;
Non members : £12&lt;br /&gt;
Children (between 5 and 10) : £4&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mailing address&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No 7 Erroll Road&lt;br /&gt;
Romford&lt;br /&gt;
Essex&lt;br /&gt;
RM1 3DJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bank account details&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bank Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
A/c Name:  South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
A/c No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Mem and /or Deepavali
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please don’t forget to e-mail sisnambalava@gmail.com regarding your transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details of all the events are available under the Events Section on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Members are requested to attend these events with your family and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepavali Recipes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We are pleased with the response for Deepavali recipes.  We have published a number of tried and tested snacks and sweets recipes on our website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Please try these recipes, enjoy and share it with your friends and relatives and make this Deepavali not just colourful but a tasteful one as well. We thank everyone who contributed with your Deepavali recipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We are confident that you enjoyed the photographs and video uploaded just after the SIS Musical Galatta. We are also confident that the articles  we are publishing on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone-up multi-fold. This month, we have published more interesting articles, the second in series on “My understanding of Philosophy” by Mr. Sukumar Panchapakesan.  This month, the subject he has chosen is  “Fundamentals of Hinduism”. There are other articles on “Deepavali”, “Are you a Brahmin”, “Bad is Good”, Skanda Sashti to name a few. We hope you will enjoy reading all the articles on the website. Please visit &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;., read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success of Charity Drive so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, SIS committee initiated a charity drive to support Raja Veda Patasala in Kumbakonam, one of the oldest Veda Patasalas in India dating back to 1542. We are extremely pleased that the collection has exceeded £1000 so far. For those willing to sponsor, details provided in the website.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;See you all at the SIS Deepavali evening on the 29th of October.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Due to operational difficulties, we operate on a no refund policy. Thanks for your understanding and cooperation&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>