<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20141023072458</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter October 2014</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS October 2014 Newsletter. Information about 2014 Diwali celebrations, Monthly Satsang etc.,</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter October 2014</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2014-11-20</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>October</NMonth>
  <NYear>2014</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;First of all, Happy Diwali: in fact we can do no better than carry in our website, sisnambalava.org.uk, a special video Deepavali-message to SIS from Kanchi Kamakoti Sankarachaya, Jagatguru Sri Vijayendra Saraswathi Swamigal. We are sure you will hear the Anugraha Bhasan in full so as to understand its full import.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His holiness is very pleased that through the South Indian Society, those of us living in the UK, help spread ‘samaya, samudaya, sastriya’ messages – ‘religious, social and traditional’ aspects of our great culture and at the same time lead successful lives with a sense of community pride. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deepavali, HH says, literally means ‘a string of lamps’.  Deepam, or a lamp, is of particularly great significance in our tradition – we worship it: ‘Deepa Mangala Jyoti Namo Namaha’. There is a sloka that begins ‘Tamoharam Bahyam Athantharancha’ – so, we are talking of a deepam that not only removes darkness outside – bahyam – but also inside – antharam cha. ‘Light that shows not just the path we should take but gives us peace within.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His Holiness also explains the Puranic significance of Deepavali. It was the day when Naragasura was killed by Lord Krishna, but his mother, Bhooma Devi obtained a boon. As a result, the chathurthasi day when he was slain is celebrated in his memory.  An oil-bath at dawn that day – arunodaya thaila snanam – is deemed a bath in the holy waters of Ganges: ‘thailo lakshmi’ and ‘jale Ganga’. That is the reason we ask each other, “have you had ‘Ganga-snamam’?” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We take great pleasure in conveying the blessings of His Holiness. May this Deepavali be: sarvapara kshamapanartham – forgiveness for all our sins and sarva mangala prapyartham – Happiness, Peace and Prosperity for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Deepavali Celebrations - Saturday, the 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt;Canons High School, Shaldon Rd, Edgware, Middlesex HA8 6AN&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October 2014&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:Red; font-weight: bold"&gt;We thank you for the overwhelming response to celebrate Deepavali with SIS.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="color:Red; font-weight: bold"&gt;Two days left to RSVP and to Pay! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="color:Red; font-weight: bold"&gt;Free Raffle tickets (T and C apply)! &lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style="color:Red; font-weight: bold"&gt;Exciting Prizes to be won!. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reduced fee&lt;/b&gt; for Members Confirming &amp; Paying in advance (by 22&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; October) : &lt;b&gt;£12&lt;/b&gt; (Preferred option)&lt;br&gt;
Members at entrance: &lt;b&gt;£15&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Non members : &lt;b&gt;£17&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Children (between 5 and 10) : &lt;b&gt;£6&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mailing address&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br&gt;
No 7 Erroll Road&lt;br&gt;
Romford&lt;br&gt;
Essex&lt;br&gt;
RM1 3DJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bank account details&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Bank Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br&gt;
A/c Name:  South Indian Society&lt;br&gt;
A/c No. 50284645&lt;br&gt;
Ref: Your FULL NAME
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please don’t forget to e-mail &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com "&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; regarding your transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/2014-diwali-celebrations-london-20140507081112.aspx"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you on Saturday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS November Satsang – 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; November 2014 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Srikanth  and Mrs. Mrs. Geetha Srikanth have kindly volunteered to host the November SIS Satsang at their residence on the 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; of November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt;3, Shelly Avenue, Manor Park, E12 6 SP&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP by 31&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; October either by e-mailing &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or by contacting Mrs. SriGeetha Srikanth directly on 078 8521 5962. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;The Website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, we have uploaded several articles, which we hope you will find interesting and useful, including one on the ‘Maitheem Bhajatha’, a historic song composed by Mahaperiaval and sung by Smt M S Subbulakshmi, on the UN day, 23&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; October, 1966.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, i.e., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>