<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20121014061340</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - October 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society October 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter October 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-11-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>October</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;It was 3rd Saturday of the Tamil month Purattasi on the 6th of October and SIS had a very well attended Satsang at Harrow.  The highlight of this month Satsang was a brief pravachanam about form and formlessness of the supreme goddess by one of our long term members Mr. Rajja Rajagopal. The speech nicely laid a foundation for the Navaratri celebrations that is to start on the 16th of October. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Navaratri, we invoke the energy aspect of God in the form of the universal mother, commonly referred to as “Durga”, which literally means the remover of miseries of life. She is also referred to as "Devi" (goddess) or "Shakti" (energy or power). Navaratri is divided into sets of three days to adore different aspects of the supreme goddess. On the first three days, the Mother is invoked as powerful force called Durga in order to destroy all our impurities, vices and defects. The next three days, the Mother is adored as a giver of all forms of wealth, Lakshmi, who is considered to have the power of bestowing on her devotees the inexhaustible wealth. The final three days we  worship the mother as the goddess of wisdom, Saraswati. In order have all-round success in life, we need the blessings of all three aspects of the divine mother; hence, the worship for nine nights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at SIS wish you all a very happy Navaratri and we wish that the Supreme Goddess bestows with all the required Shakti that gives all the wealth and happiness for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:blue;"&gt;SIS Deepavali Celebrations &lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;(Volunteers invited)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, Deepavali falls on Tuesday, the 13th of November.  We at SIS plan to celebrate Deepavali with traditional gusto on Saturday, the 17th of November.  In SIS we always have a number of members joining the Trustees in making our functions a success. We have booked a new venue and expect huge attendance for this year’s Deepavali event and we therefore need as many volunteers as we can get to make this year’s Deepavali event a grand success. May we therefore request the volunteers to please contact one of the committee members or send an e-mail &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; with your contact details by Sunday, the 14th of October and one of the committee members will contact you. Please visit the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/&lt;/a&gt; to find out more about the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIS events line-up for the rest of the year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;3rd of November:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Satsang&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;17th of November:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Deepavali Celebrations&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;1st of December:&lt;/strong&gt;	SIS Satsang&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;15th of December:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Youth event (Event organised by SIS youth)&lt;br&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please mark your calendar and we request you to participate in all the SIS events&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:blue;"&gt;SIS Sloka Classes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In several discourses Kanchi Maha Swamigal has emphasized the significance of Nithya Karma.  We at SIS have carried an article on our website in August and a few earlier. Some of our members and their children, keen to perform their nithya karma, have approached us for help and guidance. As a start, we are pleased to offer Sandhyavandhanam classes (age no bar). For more information, please visit the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;.  Also, please await details about Vishnu Sahasranam / Lalitha Sahasranamam classes that will start soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:blue;"&gt;The Website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We trust that the articles being published on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone up multi-fold. Please visit our website to read the articles and kindly let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie, South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style="color:blue;"&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt; ]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>