<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20120906032637</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - September 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society September 2012 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter September 2012</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2012-10-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>September</NMonth>
  <NYear>2012</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We thought it would be very appropriate to start the newsletter with two Thirukkurals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
தாளாற்றித் தந்த பொருளெல்லாம் தக்கார்க்கு &lt;br&gt;
வேளாண்மை செய்தற் பொருட்டு 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
All the wealth that toils give&lt;br&gt;
Is meant to serve those who deserve
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
ஈதல் இசைபட வாழ்தல் அதுவல்லது &lt;br&gt;
ஊதியம் இல்லை உயிர்க்கு
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
They gather fame who freely give&lt;br&gt;
The greatest gain for all that live
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at SIS have understood and are living-up to the verses of Thiruvalluvar.  Contributions came-in from several SIS members in different forms in cash, kind and selfless service.  This helped us to mobilise substantial funds through the SIS Carnival.  We are pleased to say that the donations have been sent to Great Ormond Street Hospital and to Shooting Stars CHASE Children’s hospice. Once again, we take this opportunity to thank all volunteers and participants for your contribution, without which it would have been impossible to have achieved this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the twinkling of an eye, we are already in the month of Aavani.  With autumn setting very well, festival season for Indians starts. Srijayanthi is celebrated in some parts of India on the 8th of September, followed by Vinayaka Chadurthi on the 19th of September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take this opportunity to wish you all a great festive season ahead.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Career event - Saturday, the 22nd September &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;RSVP Required&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event is aimed at providing specific, 'supplementary' guidance to students (and their parents) about to make their higher educational choice - specific, in the sense, it is aimed at children of the SIS family; supplementary to the guidance provided by their schools. The ambit is to provide guidance on both making the right choice, in terms of universities, subjects, etc., and how to go about navigating the selection process and put one's best foot forward. What to choose and how to make it click!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The target audience is children about to make their UCAS application this year or next year; but, children, at a slightly earlier academic stage, will also benefit. Parents are particularly invited as they can constructively help their children. Whilst it is meant for children of the SIS family, we will be delighted to have children of non-member Indian families. It is important that we have advance registration from all the children who want to participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aim to make the event interactive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have engaged the services of a professional career's guide &lt;strong&gt;David Scales Career Adviser (Dip CG, PGCE)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have organised eminent speakers - young graduates and professionals with multifarious  background (medicine, engineering, science, law, finance and accounting, dentistry, arts, etc.) - to share their thoughts about their career choices  and experiences &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr N Sundar&lt;/strong&gt; of SIS will draw on his industry-academic experience to handle a brief session on what makes people succeed as students and as professionals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mrs Mythili Venkateswaran&lt;/strong&gt; has kindly agreed to compere the whole event in her inimitable style, along with providing guidance on oral and written communication. Students will have an opportunity to have a brief one on one chat with the professional advisor at the end of the event. We will also circulate some useful material and web links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are others whom we have approached and a final list of confirmed speakers will be sent out later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the event is aimed at students and their parents, all other SIS members are invited to attend and interact. On a one on one basis they will be able to share their own experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; Church of Ascension Hall on Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Saturday, 22nd September, 2012.  2:30 pm to assemble; 3:00 pm sharp 			the actual event will start. Please be on time.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Entry:&lt;/strong&gt; Free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, we will have snacks and drinks at the end of the event. We plan to finish by 5:30 pm latest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:red;"&gt;Due to nature of the event and to ensure that participants gain maximum benefit, we would like to know the number of participants, their profile and what they are looking to gain from this event in advance. Hence we kindly request you to RSVP before Sunday the 16th of September by sending an e-mail to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the line-up of SIS events for the rest of the year. Apart from the monthly Satsang, we have lined-up number of interesting events for the rest of the year. E-mails will be sent and details will be made available on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk, closer to the event.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17th Nov:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Deepavali&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;15th Dec:&lt;/strong&gt; 	SIS Youth Event (An event organised by SIS youth)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please mark your calendar and we request you to participate in all the SIS events&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Youth – &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Youth Volunteers invited&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we have two events for the next generation SISites.  Yes they are the youth events. More information will follow regarding the SIS Career Event shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The December event is the SIS Youth Event.  We would like that event to be organised and run by SIS Youth. Yes! &lt;span style="color:blue;"&gt;YOU ARE HIRED!&lt;/span&gt; You conceptualise; You look after the logistics and execute it well. We will guide you if required. It will be the typical BBC apprentice style with one difference.  &lt;span style="color:blue;"&gt;No one will be fired!&lt;/span&gt;  It will be a great opportunity and experience for our SIS Youth. A must thing to be on ones CV and SIS need more youth involvement.  How can we find a better win-win deal? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be a 10 member team (boys and girls) to run a grand gala show. Please send in nominations for your children (age between 14 and 20), with a brief write-up (not more than one page) by the nominee on &lt;strong&gt;"How can you make a difference"&lt;/strong&gt;.   Please send the nominations to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; with the write-up on or before the 1st of September 2012. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We trust that the articles being published on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits that have gone up multi-fold. Please visit our website to read the articles and kindly let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie, South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>