<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20140922072527</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter September 2014</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>SIS September 2014 Newsletter. Information about 2014 Diwali celebrations, Monthly Satsang etc.,</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter September 2014</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2014-10-22</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>September</NMonth>
  <NYear>2014</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Purattasi is the sixth month in the Tamil calendar and is dedicated to Lord Perumal (Lord Venkateswara), as it is believed that Lord Venkateswara appeared on the earth during this month. Devotees gather in large numbers at Lord Vishnu temples and special prayers are offered and flags with Garuda emblem are hoisted. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Purattasi Vrat is observed by devotees of Lord Venkateswara. Some people observe partial fasting on all days in Puratassi whilst others limit it to Saturdays. A few observe strict fast called Nirjala Vratam on Saturdays which involves not even drinking a drop of water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mahalaya Paksham that started on the 9th of September, on the full moon day of Aavani, completes with Mahalaya Ammavasai on the 24th of September.  Why is Mahalaya Paksham so important?  Why we do not perform any Subha Karyam during this time?  What is the basic dhatham (offering) that we should do?  All these are briefed in the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/religion/mahalaya-paksha-20140921034428.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Navarathri&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the most important festival celebrated this month is Navaratri, which starts on 25th September. Navratri is a nine day festival dedicated to worship of the goddess in the three forms of Durga, Lakshmi and Saraswathi and the tenth day is celebrated as Vijayadashami.   Whether we worship Devi in the form of Durga, Lakshmi or Saraswathi, we really worship the ultimate Sakti – ‘Parasakti’. In Lalitha Sahasranamam Devi is at once described the creator (Shrishtikarthee and brahmarupa), the preserver (gopthri, govindarupini) and destroyer (samharini, rudrarupini). In both Lakshmi and Saraswathi astothrams, we call Her ‘brahma-vishnu-sivathmikaaya’, signifying that Durga, Saraswathi and Lakshmi are one and the same.  Please click &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/religion/significance-of-navarathri-20131006031951.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a very interesting and useful article on Navarathri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saundarya Lahari, the thirty-two names of Durga and all the other Navaratri chants and practices are designed to awaken the human psyche. Just as there is a mental level, an emotional level, a pranic level and a physical level, so there is a vibratory level to our life as well. This vibratory level is the most subtle of the bodies and the only thing it responds to is frequency. Mantras create such frequencies in the body, in the personality, which stimulate and awaken the subtle personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opening up of the subtle personality is also opening up of the heart. Logic governs life up to a point. After logic, buddhi, comes faith, bhavana, and after faith comes fusion, tadatmya. When this fusion takes place in us at a subtle psychic level, a spiritual level, we become more sensitive to the universe, life, spirit, creation. We learn to live life in a more responsible way, appreciating and applying the wisdom that has been gained through the ages. Mantras are definitely the keys to finding this inner awakening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Siva Sukhap Peruvellam’ is a Tamil translation of ‘Shivanandalahari’ by Bhagavan Adi Sankara. This book comprises of 100 Sanskrit verses praising ‘Parabrahmam’ (the union of Shiva and Shakti). The main emphasis of Shivanandalahari is portraying the perspectives of a sincere aspirant, seeking the benign grace of God. One of our members is publishing a book on Soundaryalahari and on Lord Dakshinamurthy on the 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of October. Details on the&lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/other-events/book-release-function-20140916095309.aspx" target="_blank"&gt; website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wish you a happy Navarathri and pray the almighty to shower blessings to all of us. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Isle of Wight Trip Update&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100 people attended a trip to Isle of Wight on Saturday 13th of September. With a double-decker bus full, the day was a resounding success. The day consisted of a chair-lift ride, a river cruise around the famous Needle Rocks &amp; Lighthouse and a fun time at Sundown beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our article on our trip on the SIS website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/others/a-day-out-to-isle-of-wight-20140915062653.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/others/a-day-out-to-isle-of-wight-20140915062653.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS Deepavali Celebrations - Saturday, the 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; of October&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIS Deepavali.... The Ultimate show of the year is on the 25th of October 2014. After the Silver Jubilee celebrations last year, SIS will be launching the SIS souvenir this year at the Diwali celebrations. So it is SIS Deepavali Double Damakha... Let's participate and celebrate....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;தீபாவளி...தீபாவளி தான் .... இது sis தீபாவளி தான்..... &lt;br&gt;
ஆண்டுக்கு ஆண்டுக்கு வித்தியாசம் கொண்டாட்டம்... கும்மாளம்.... சந்தோஷம்..... இதுதான் sis தீபாவளி ....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don't miss a bit....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt;Canons High School, Shaldon Rd, Edgware, Middlesex HA8 6AN&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 25&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October 2014&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 4:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details visit the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/2014-diwali-celebrations-london-20140507081112.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;SIS October Satsang – Saturday, the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Balaji have kindly volunteered to host the SIS October Satsang at their residence on Saturday, the 4&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; October 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Address:&lt;/strong&gt;7, Abbey Lodge, Park Road, St. John's Wood, London NW8 7RJ&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3.30 pm to 5:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP by Friday, 3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; of October either by e-mailing &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; or contacting Mrs. Hema Balaji directly on 078 7259 9644.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt; Recipe of the month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Recipe of the month is Beetroot halwa.  Read, cook, share and enjoy..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/recipes/beetroot-halwa-recipe-20140921032248.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/articles/recipes/beetroot-halwa-recipe-20140921032248.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt;The Website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We trust that the articles that we are publishing on the website are interesting and useful. We are encouraged by the number of hits thathave gone up multifold. This month, we have uploaded more interesting articles. We hope you will enjoy reading all the articles on the website. Please visit &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk" target="_blank"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;., read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>