<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Newsletter>
  <NletterID>20110912060009</NletterID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Newsletter - September 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society September 2011 Newsletter.</MetaDescription>
  <Heading>Newsletter September 2011</Heading>
  <ExpiryDate>2011-10-6</ExpiryDate>
  <NMonth>September</NMonth>
  <NYear>2011</NYear>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;We would like to start this newsletter remembering Dr. MS. Subbulakshmi  - ‘MS’’, as she was popularly known, on the legend’s 95th Birthday which falls  on 16th Sep. MS was the first musician to be awarded Bharat Ratna, India’s highest civilian honour  and the first Indian musician to receive Ramon Magsaysay award, Asia's highest civilian award. MS, the iconic name of Indian music has filled the puja rooms of millions of Indians with her famous Vishnu Sahasranamam, Bhajagovandam, Venkateswara Suprabatham, and Hanuman Chaleesa, just to name a few.  Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru once said  "Who am I, a mere Prime Minister, before a Queen, a Queen of Music".  Everyone of us at SIS remembers MS for her contribution to Carnatic music and a few of our veteran members will have ever lasting memories of hosting her, when the Nightingale of Carnatic music visited London in 1982 to sing in the inaugural concert at the Festival of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Few Related Events in London&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To mark the 95th Birthday of Dr. MS Subbulakshmi, London Sri Murugan temple has organised a music concert by Smt. Manorama Prasad on the 16th of September at 7:30 pm at the temple . Smt Manorama Prasad is known for her traditional and technical rendering. Her powerful voice has adorned her inborn gift of rendering pure music in an inimitable way. The control she has on the ragas and very complicated talas is  something every music listener will appreciate and will be a true remembrance of Dr. MS with some popular notes of MS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rasikalaya that brings Nadam of London has organised the concert of Malladi Sreeramprasad and Malladi Ravikumar.  Popularly known as Malladi brothers, they are here in London for the first  time to perform in front of some passionate Carnatic lovers. The event is on the 1st of October at Church of the Ascension Hall, Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB. More details are available on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/other-events/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIS Events&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Dandia also known as Kolattam is a folk dance that traditionally features in the evenings during  Krishna Janmashtami and Navrathri. We at SIS will have karaoke as well to add to the fun. SIS hosts 2011 Musical galatta evening where everyone gets an opportunity to sing and dance. The event will be on the 17th September at Church of Ascension Hall on Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB. More details are available on the &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/sis-events/sis-musical-galatta-evening-20110630064643.aspx"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Early bird discount for members who confirm and pay in advance closes on the 15thSeptember.  Please confirm and send in your payment at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIS will celebrate Deepavali on the 29th of October. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please block your calendar for all SIS events. Details of all the events are available under the Events Section on the website &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt;. Members are requested to attend these events with your family and send in their much valued feedback and suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deepavali Recipes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As a preparation for Deepavali, we would like to publish snacks and sweets recipes on our website. We welcome recipes of new types of snacks and sweets and the recipes of our traditional ones that contain special tips. Please write to us of the recipes that you have tried and you want to share with your friends. We will upload it in September.  Recipes will be uploaded after review by the editorial committee. Guidelines for articles are given below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Website&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We are confident that the upakarma upload on the website and the information we provided regarding the venues in London for upakarma was useful.  We have uploaded some useful information about upakarma in this newsletter. Starting this month, we will upload a series on “My understanding of Philosophy” by one of our members Mr. Sukumar Panchapakesan, who shares his understanding of philosophy, after listening to speeches from great Gurus like Sri Ramana Maharishi, Mahaperival and others.  There are other articles on health, Garbarakshambigai, Navarathri etc. We hope you will enjoy reading all the articles on the website. Please visit www.sisnambalava.org.uk., read the articles and let us know your views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome articles written by our members that are relevant to the objectives of SIS, ie., South Indian arts, culture and vedic religion and these will be uploaded after review by the editorial panel. Please feel free to ask for detailed guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Success of Charity Drive so far&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;As you are aware, SIS committee initiated a charity drive to support Raja Veda Patasala in Kumbakonam, one of the oldest Veda Patasalas in India dating back to 1542. We are extremely pleased that we have collected over £850 so far. For those willing to sponsor, details provided in the website.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Membership and Participation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May we request those of you who have not yet paid your annual membership of (£20), to please do so at the earliest? You can send your cheque in the name of "South Indian Society" and mail it to the address below or alternatively make the payment via bank transfer to SIS Account (details given below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mailing address&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No 7 Erroll Road&lt;br /&gt;
Romford&lt;br /&gt;
Essex&lt;br /&gt;
RM1 3DJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bank account details&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bank Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
A/c Name:  South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
A/c No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Membership
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;South Indian Society as an organisation has come to shape with lots of hard work and contribution from several veterans of our community in this country. We sincerely thank each and every one who has contributed towards the growth of this organisation. This organisation runs for YOU and without YOUR involvement, contribution and participation it cannot succeed.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;See you all at the SIS Musical Galatta evening on the 17th of September.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Newsletter>