<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20130402063350</EventID>
  <PageTitle>Saakshee Shilaa - A Sanskrit Play - London, April 2013</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>sanskrit play, sanskrit play in london, sanskrit play in UK</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan London presents Saakshee Shilaa, a Sanskrit play in London, United Kingdom. Don't miss this opportunity to witness a Sanskrit play in a traditional way.</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>Saakshee Shilaa - A Sanskrit Play - London - 2013</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2013-04-13</EventDate>
  <EventTime>4:00 PM</EventTime>
  <Address>Queen Elizabeth Hall Foyer, Southbank Centre, Belvedere Road, London, SE1 8XX </Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admission:&lt;/strong&gt; Free (First Come First Served: so, please come early)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nearest Tube: &lt;/strong&gt; Southbank Centre is minutes from the Waterloo, Charing Cross and Embankment London Underground and British Rail stations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During April 2013, the Iconic South Bank Arts Centre in London is holding its three week long annual Alchemy Festival of music, dance, literature, design and debate from India, the UK and South Asia. There are dazzling events for everyone ranging from music from Susheela Raman, Hariharan and Anoushka Shankar to circus and aerial performances. One can also literally enjoy Indian flavour in the ‘Roti Chat and Chair Bar’ open at the venue during the festival. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of Alchemy events the Bhavan has been specially commissioned to put up a rare event: a play in Sanskrit! Originally written in Kannada, Saakshi Shilaa has been translated into Sanskrit as a play by Dr HVS Shastry, formerly the head of Bhavan’s Sanskrit Department. Another eminent Sanskrit scholar, Dr Nanda Kumara, Director of the Bhavan, is the lead actor. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format is that of a typical folk theatre style street drama, or ‘theru koothu’, commonly performed during temple festivals in villages in Tamilnadu.  There is a narrator (a role played by the director of the play, none other than Dr Shastry himself) who introduces the theme and links the various scenes with a running commentary, with musical and dance support. Dialogue delivery is spontaneous with effective use of humour.  The characters in the play all speak conversational Sanskrit that most Indians can follow but English scene summaries are provided in between the scenes so that everyone can follow the play. The duration of the play is under one hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is a rare, not-to-be missed opportunity to witness a Sanskrit play 
in a traditional therukoottu format in an iconic London location.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>