<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20140916095309</EventID>
  <PageTitle>Book Release Function</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>Book Release Function, Shivanandalahari, Sri Dakshinamurthy Stotram</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Shivanandalahari, Sri Dakshinamurthy Stotram - new book release function at London Murugan temple</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>Book Release Function</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2014-10-5</EventDate>
  <EventTime>2:30 PM - 6 PM</EventTime>
  <Address>London Murugan Temple, 78-90 Church Rd, London E12 6AF</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;‘Siva Sukhap Peruvellam’ is an inspired Tamil translation of ‘Shivanandalahari’, a
monumental work by Bhagavan Adi Sankara. This book of 100 beautiful Sanskrit
verses, that adores the ‘Parabrahmam’ as the union of Shiva and Shakti, is another
testimony for the mastery and the unparalleled position of Sankara, both as a poet and
philosopher of the highest caliber. The main emphasis of Shivanandalahari is ‘Bhakti’
and the verses portray the perspectives of a sincere aspirant, seeking the benign grace
of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second book is also an inspired translation of Sankara’s ‘Sri Dakshinamurthy
Stotram’. With only 10 verses, Sri Dakshinamurthy Stotram is a small book in
comparison, yet is an extremely intricate work that brings out essence of entire
Vedanta. Here the main emphasis is ‘Gyana’, the true knowledge about the Self and its
non-duality with the Universal-Self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two great works of Sankara are enchanting to read and revealing when
understood, which are hopefully brought out in the Tamil renderings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third book, Sri Adiguru Dakshinamurthy Vazhipadu, is a revised-print of an earlier
work, consisting of Tamil verses and pictures of rare forms of Sri Dakshinamurthy,
sketched by Smt. Jaya Chandrasekaran by the instruction of Sri Kanchi Maha Periva.
As a book of prayers, it contains verses that seek the benign grace of Adiguru, for
attaining perfection in all our physical, respirational, mental, intellectual and causal
embodiments,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the blessed release of these books at Kanchi Kamakoti Mutt on 11th Sep
2014, these are to be introduced to our community in London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All proceeds from these books are dedicated to ‘Veda samrakshana’ and charitable
causes. Please do attend the function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mee. Rajagopalan (RSVP: &lt;a href="mailto:rajjag@gmail.com"&gt;rajjag@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;, Ph: 0208 427 8600)&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>