<?xml version="1.0"?><Article><ArticleID>20101129033941</ArticleID><category>others</category><PageTitle>South Indian Society 20-20 Cricket, Harrow</PageTitle><MetaKeywords>sis sports, sis cricket</MetaKeywords><MetaDescription>A report on South Indian Society, UK annual sports event. 20-20 Cricket analysis.</MetaDescription><ArticleHeading>SIS 20-20 Cricket</ArticleHeading><ArticleDate>2010-08-7</ArticleDate><Author>SIS Trustees</Author><MiniDescription>On the 10th of July 2010, mercury rising to new heights in London, SIS had it's sports event.</MiniDescription><Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Trust you are enjoying the summer holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;On the 10th of July 2010, mercury rising to new heights in London, SIS had it's sports event.  Yes it was the most awaited SIS T20 Cricket match.  Without breaking the Indian tradition, members gathered between 9:30 and 11 am for a match that was to start at 10 am.  Never mind, that gave plenty of time for the players to practice.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Two teams were formed with Rajasekar and Karthik as captains and the match referee was none other than Venkat.  The referee decided to name the teams (for reasons known only to him) as Bonda (captain Karthik) and Bajji (captain Raj).  The teams went to the centre of the pitch for the toss.  Karthik won the toss and the Bonda team decided to bat first.  With star batting in the Bonda team by Magesh, Adithya Raj, Sanjeev, Karthik and others, Bonda team scored 82.  The Bajji team gave 30 runs as extras and set a huge chasing target of 113.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the lack of depth in bowling, the Bajji team had a great batting line-up.  Great innings from Harish, Niranjan and Anirudh took the score to 95.  Two overs to go and 18 runs to win.  Magesh in his last over took two wickets giving just 4 runs.  Pressure on both the teams. The last over was bowled by Ram and got Harish bowled.  The innings of Bajji team sadly came to an end and Bonda won Bajji team by 13 runs.  Excellent stumping by Adithya Raj, a great Murali Vijay style catch by Vijay and the final wicket by Ram were the key factors for Bonda team's victory. What a match. Nail biting finish that was.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Young and beautiful girls grabbed the opportunity and displayed great batting / fielding talents on the field. Paddy and Vijay displayed their commentary skills taking us 15 years back and reminded of the All India Radio commentary for a Chennai test match. Professional scoring by Mythili Venkat and Lalitha Paddy, photography by Raji Vijayakumar and the IPL style cheering by the SIS cheer girls were the highlights of the match.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;It was an excellent day out and everyone who came-in enjoyed.  Great food from Chennai Dosa, cold beer and wine was a perfect choice for the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;SIS that always gives high quality and variety programs to its members, has done it again.  Three cheers to the organisers and all the participants who made this event a grand success.  SIS is committed to do more of these in the future and welcome participation from all members.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription><AMonth>August</AMonth><AYear>2010</AYear></Article>