<?xml version="1.0"?><Article><ArticleID>20101125023931</ArticleID><category>others</category><PageTitle>Vande Mataram to Mother India by Aditya Vijay &amp; Aditya Rajasekar</PageTitle><MetaKeywords>sis independence celebrations</MetaKeywords><MetaDescription>South Indian Society Independence celebrations in London and Interesting article about Vande Mataram to our Mother India.</MetaDescription><ArticleHeading>First of all VANDE MATARAM to Mother India</ArticleHeading><ArticleDate>2010-11-25</ArticleDate><Author>Aditya Vijay &amp; Aditya Rajasekar</Author><MiniDescription>On August 15th, Indians all over the world celebrate India’s independence, from the British Rule in 1947.  This day commemorates the birth of an independent country, which carries a vast heritage and culture. Many significant events are conducted on this day.</MiniDescription><Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;On August 15th, Indians all over the world celebrate India’s independence, from the British Rule in 1947.  This day commemorates the birth of an independent country, which carries a vast heritage and culture. Many significant events are conducted on this day. The main event, taking place in New Delhi, happens when the Prime Minister (currently Dr. Manmohan Singh) hoists the flag at the Red Fort and gives a televised national speech. He also pays tribute to all freedom fighters and gives awards to civilian and military achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many freedom fighters fought for India’s freedom from 1857 to 1947. Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi (who was lovingly called Bapu) was the pinnacle figure in this battle for freedom. He convinced vast amounts of Indians to join him using Ahimsa- fighting for freedom in a non-violent manner. Soon after many boycotts and non-violent protests Gandhi was successful and drove India to victory. Jawaharlal Nehru, who became the first Prime Minister of our country, was another important individual in the formation of Indian freedom.  He made a famous speech on the midnight of 14th August 1947 declaring the end of India’s struggle for Independence – "At the stroke of the midnight hour, when the world sleeps, India will awake to life and freedom. A moment comes, which comes but rarely in history, when we step out from the old to the new, when an age ends, and when the soul of a nation, long suppressed, finds utterance...we end today a period of ill fortune, and India discovers herself again."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does all this mean to us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should feel proud of our nation because of the many brave people who have sacrificed their lives for its birth. This hard found freedom should not be wasted and Indians should try their best to improve India in every way possible.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription><AMonth>November</AMonth><AYear>2010</AYear></Article>