<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20110509095256</ArticleID>
  <category>religion</category>
  <PageTitle>Sri Hanuman Chaleesa With Meaning</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>hanuman, Sri Hanuman, Sri Hanuman Chaleesa, Hanuman Chaleesa meaning</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>An interesting article about the meaning of Sri Hanuman Chaleesa from Sivasankaran.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Sri Hanuman Chaleesa With Meaning</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2011-05-9</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Sivasankaran</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Read this article to understand the meaning of Sri Hanuman Chaleesa.</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Shree Guru Charan Saroj Raj, Nij Man Mukar Sudhari, 
Barnau Raghuvar Bimal Jasu, Jo dayaku Phal Chari &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the dust of Guru's Lotus feet, I clean the mirror of my mind and then narrate the sacred glory of Sri Ram Chandra, The Supreme among the Raghu dynasty. The giver of the four attainments of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Budhi heen Tanu Janike, Sumirow, Pavan Kumar, 
Bal Buddhi Vidya Dehu Mohi, Harahu Kalesh Bikaar &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing myself to be ignorant, I urge you, O Hanuman, The son of Pavan! O Lord! kindly Bestow on me strength, wisdom and knowledge, removing all my miseries and blemishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Jai Hanuman Gyan Guna Sagar 
Jai Kipis Tihun Lok Ujgaar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Victory of Thee, O Hanuman, Ocean of wisdom and virtue, victory to the Lord of monkeys who is well known in all the three worlds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Ramdoot Atulit Bal Dhamaa, 
Anjani Putra Pavansut naamaa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You, the Divine messager of Ram and repository of immeasurable strength, are also known as Anjaniputra and known as the son of the wind - Pavanputra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Mahebeer Bikram Bajrangi, 
Kumati Nivaar Sumati Ke Sangi.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! You are valiant and brave, with a body like lightening. You are the dispeller of darkness of evil thoughts and companion of good sense and wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Kanchan Baran Biraaj Subesaa, 
Kanan kundal kunchit kesa.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Shri Hanumanji's physique is golden coloured. His dress is pretty, wearing 
'Kundals' ear-rings and his hairs are long and curly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Hath Bajra Aur Dhvaja Birjai, 
Kandhe Moonj Janeu saage. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shri Hanumanji is holding in one hand a lighting bolt and in the other a banner with sacred thread across his shoulder. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Shankar Suvna Kesari Nandan, 
Tej Pratap Maha Jag Vandan. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! You are the emanation of 'SHIVA' and you delight Shri Keshri.  Being ever effulgent, you and hold vast sway over the universe. The entire world proptiates. You are adorable of all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Vidyavaan Guni Ati Chatur, 
Ram Kaj Karibe Ko Atur &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh! Shri Hanumanji! You are the repository learning, virtuous, very wise and highly keen to do the work of Shri Ram, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Prabhu Charittra Sunibe Ko Rasiya, 
Ram Lakhan Sita man basyia. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are intensely greedy for listening to the naration of Lord Ram's lifestory and revel on its enjoyment. You ever dwell in the hearts of Shri Ram-Sita and Shri Lakshman. &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11. Sukshma roop Dhari Siyahi Dikhwana, 
Bikat roop Dhari Lank Jarawa &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You appeared beofre Sita in a diminutive form and spoke to her, while you 
***umed an awesome form and struck terror by setting Lanka on fire. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12. Bhim roop Dhari Asur Sanhare, 
Ramchandra Ke kaaj Savare. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He, with his terrible form, killed demons in Lanka and performed all acts of Shri Ram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13. Laye Sajivan Lakhan Jiyaye, 
Shri Raghubir harashi ur laye. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Hanumanji made Lakshman alive after bringing 'Sanjivni herb' Shri Ram took him in his deep embrace, his heart full of joy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14. Raghupati Kinhi Bahut Badaai, 
Tum Mama Priya Bharat Sam Bahi. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shri Ram lustily extolled Hanumanji's excellence and remarked, "you are as dear to me as my own brother Bharat"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15. Sahastra Badan Tumharo Jas Gaave, 
Asa kahi Shripati Kanth Laagave. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shri Ram embraced Hanumanji saying: 
"Let the thousand - tongued sheshnaag sing your glories" &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16. Sankadik Brahmadi Muneesa, 
Narad Sarad Sahit Aheesa &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sanak and the sages, saints. Lord Brahma, the great hermits Narad and Goddess Saraswati along with Sheshnag the cosmic serpent, fail to sing the glories of Hanumanji exactly &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17. Jam Kuber Digpal Jahan Te, 
Kabi Kabid Kahin Sake Kahan Te &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to talk of denizens of the earth like poets and scholars ones etc even Gods like Yamraj, Kuber, and Digpal fail to narrate Hanman's greatness in toto. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18. Tum Upkar Sugrivahi Keenha, 
Ram Miali Rajpad Deenha &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanumanji! You rendered a great service for Sugriva, It were you who united him with SHRI RAM and installed him on the Royal Throne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19. Tumharo Mantro Bibhishan Maana, 
Lankeshwar Bhaye Sab Jag Jaana. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By heeding your advice. Vibhushan became Lord of Lanka, which is known all over the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20. Juug Sahastra Jojan Par Bhaanu, 
Leelyo Taahi Madhur Phal Jaanu &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanumanji gulped, the SUN at distance of sixteen thousand miles considering it to be a sweet fruit.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21. Prabhu Mudrika Meli Mukha Maaheen, 
Jaladhi Langhi Gaye Acharaj Naheen. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carrying the Lord's ring in his mouth, he went across the ocean. There is no wonder in that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22. Durgam Kaaj Jagat Ke Jeete, 
Sugam Anugrah Tumhre Te Te. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! all the difficult tasks in the world are rendered easiest by your grace. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23. Ram Duware Tum Rakhavare, 
Hot Na Aagya Bin Paisare. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! You are the sentinel at the door of Ram's mercy mansion or His divine abode. No one may enter without your permission. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24. Sab Sukh Lahen Tumhari Sarna, 
Tum Rakshak Kaahu Ko Darnaa. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By your grace one can enjoy all happiness and one need not have any fear under your protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25. Aapan Tej Samharo Aapei, 
Tanau Lok Hank Te Kanpei &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you roar all the three worlds tremble and only you can control your might. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26. Bhoot Pisaach Nikat Nahi Avei, 
Mahabir Jab Naam Sunavei. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great Brave on. Hanumanji's name keeps all the Ghosts, Demons &amp; evils spirits away from his devotees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27. Nasei Rog Hare Sab Peera, 
Japat Niranter Hanumant Beera &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On reciting Hanumanji's holy name regularly all the maladies perish the entire pain disappears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28. Sankat Te Hanuman Chhudavei, 
Man Kram Bachan Dhyan Jo Lavei. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who rembember Hanumanji in thought, word and deed are well guarded against their odds in life.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29. Sub Par Ram Tapasvee Raaja, 
Tinke Kaaj Sakal Tum Saaja &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! You are the caretaker of even Lord Rama, who has been hailed as the Supreme Lord and the Monarch of all those devoted in penances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30. Aur Manorath Jo Koi Lave, 
Soi Amit Jivan Phal Pave. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! You fulfill the desires of those who come to you and bestow the eternal nectar the highest fruit of life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;31. Charo Juung Partap Tumhara, 
Hai Parsiddha Jagat Ujiyara. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! You magnificent glory is acclaimed far and wide all through the four ages and your fame is radianlty noted all over the cosmos. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32. Sadho Sant Ke Tum Rakhvare, 
Asur Nikandan Ram Dulare. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! You are the saviour and the guardian angel of saints and sages and destroy all the Demons, you are the seraphic darling of Shri Ram. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;33. Ashta Siddhi Nau Nidhi Ke Data, 
Asa Bar Din Janki Mata. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanumanji has been blessed with mother Janki to grant to any one any YOGIC power of eight Sidhis and Nava Nidhis as per choice. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34. Ram Rasayan Tumhare Pasa, 
Sadaa Raho Raghupati Ke Dasa. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! You hold the essence of devotion to RAM, always remaining His Servant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;35. Tumhare Bhajan Ramko Pavei. 
Janam Janam Ke Dukh Bisravei. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Hanumanji! through devotion to you, one comes to RAM and becames free from suffering of several lives. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;36. Anta Kaal Raghubar Pur Jai, 
Jahan Janma Hari Bhakta Kahai. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After death he enters the eternal abode of Sri Ram and remains a devotee of him, whenever, taking new birth on earth. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;37. Aur Devata Chitt Na Dharai, 
Hanumant Sei Sarva Sukh Karai &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need not hold any other demigod in mind. Hanumanji alone will give all happiness. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;38. Sankat Kate Mitey Sab Peera, 
Jo Sumirei Hanumant Balbeera &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh Powerful Hanumanji! You end the sufferings and remove all the pain from those who remember you.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;39. Jai Jai Jai Hanuman Gosai 
Kripa Karahu Gurudev Ki Naiee &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hail-Hail-Hail-Lord Hanumanji! I beseech you Honour to bless me in the capacity of my supreme 'GURU' (teacher). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;40. Jo Sat Baar Paath Kar Koi, 
Chhutahi Bandi Maha Sukh Hoi. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One who recites this Hanuman Chalisa one hundred times daily for one hundred days becames free from the bondage of life and death and ejoys the highest bliss at last. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;41. Jo Yah Padhe Hanuman Chalisa, 
Hoy Siddhi Sakhi Gaurisa &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Lord Shankar witnesses, all those who recite Hanuman Chalisa regularly are sure to be benedicted &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;42. Tulsidas Sada Hari Chera, 
Keeje Nath Hriday Mah Dera. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tulsidas always the servant of Lord prays. "Oh my Lord! You enshrine within my heart.! &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Chopai&lt;/u&gt;
Pavan Tanay Sankat Haran , Mangal Murti Roop. 
Ram Lakhan Sita Sahit, Hriday Basahu Sur Bhoop. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O Shri Hanuman, The Son of Pavan, Saviour The Embodiment of 
blessings, reside in my heart together with Shri Ram, Laxman and Sita .&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>May</AMonth>
  <AYear>2011</AYear>
</Article>