<?xml version="1.0"?><Article><ArticleID>20110311051407</ArticleID><category>religion</category><PageTitle>Panguni Uthiram</PageTitle><MetaKeywords>Panguni Uthiram</MetaKeywords><MetaDescription>A write up about Panguni uthiram, celebrated in the montn of Panguni.</MetaDescription><ArticleHeading>Panguni Uthiram</ArticleHeading><ArticleDate>2011-03-11</ArticleDate><Author>C.Vedanarayanan</Author><MiniDescription>Panguni Uthiram is celebrated on 19th March 2011. Panguni Uthiram is an important day for practising Tamil Hindus. On this day,  in the month of PANGUNI, the full moon coincides with Uttara phalguni nakshatram.</MiniDescription><Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Panguni Uthiram is an important day for practising Tamil Hindus. On this day, in the month of PANGUNI, the full moon coincides with Uttara phalguni nakshatram (ie uthiram).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This festival is associated with various deities in the Hindu pantheon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/temples/Ettukudi-Murugan-temple.jpg" alt="Ettukudi Murugan temple" title="Ettukudi Murugan temple" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10px; text-align:center;"&gt;Ettukudi Murugan temple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the day Goddess Parvathi (Gowri) married  the Lord of Kanchipuram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lord Murugan  married Valli amman in Vallimalai (near Walajapet in Vellore district ). After the marriage, the couple settled in Thiruthani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/temples/Vallakottai-Murugan-temple.jpg" alt="Vallakottai Murugan temple" title="Vallakottai Murugan temple" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10px; text-align:center;"&gt;Vallakottai Murugan temple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Villiputhur Aandaal (Soodi kodutha sudar kodi/Kothai) joined Srirangam Ranganatha perumal. According to Valmiki ramayanam, Sita's marriage with Rama took place on this day. This is the day when Mahalakshmi appeared from the ocean of milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also the janma dhinam of Lord Ayyappan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is believed that on Panguni Uthiram day, all the sacred waters meet at Thumburu theertham in Tirupathi Tirumalai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murugan devotees throng to Murugan temples carrying pooja materials in KAVADIs. They also practise other kind of religious vows like shaving  the head and having needles (ALAKUs) inserted in their bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/temples/Ilayanar-Velur-Murugan-temple.jpg" alt="Ilayanar Velur Murugan temple" title="Ilayanar Velur Murugan temple" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10px; text-align:center;"&gt;Ilayanar Velur Murugan temple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only on this day, at Srirangam, Lord Ranganatha and Ranganayaki share the same stage in Panguni Uttara mandapam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/temples/Srirangam-Rangavimanam.jpg" alt="Srirangam Rangavimanam" title="Srirangam Rangavimanam" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10px; text-align:center;"&gt;Srirangam Rangavimanam&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special poojas and rituals are performed in Sabarimala Ayyappan temple in Kerala, as elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My early memories still linger….this is some sixty years ago…. Every year Pithukuli Murugadas visited Lalgudi and held Bhajanai throughout the night, in a devotee's house.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription><AMonth>March</AMonth><AYear>2011</AYear></Article>