<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20110710085225</ArticleID>
  <category>others</category>
  <PageTitle>SIS Cricket Galatta 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>South Indian Society Cricket Galatta 2011</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society Cricket Galatta</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>SIS Cricket Galatta 2011</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2011-07-10</ArticleDate>
  <Author>SIS Trustees</Author>
  <MiniDescription>SIS had it's annual cricket event on 9th July.  A Good treat for cricket lovers and a great day out in a perfect weather with good food and drinks.</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;On the 9th of July, Essex Eagles and Bucks Bears tested their cricketing strengths at Harrow country club cricket grounds in two matches. Two matches were played, first a T20 and the second a 15 overs match. In the first match, after winning the toss, Bucks Bears chose to field first. Essex Eagles scored 118 runs in 20 overs.  Bucks Bears gave a very tough fight but just started losing wickets at constant intervals, and managed to score 95 runs.  Hari Sundaresan put-up a great innings for Essex Eagles and was declared the man-of-the-match. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second match was a 15 over match, Bucks Bears decided to bat first. Some early good strikes from Karthik Raghavan and Vinod, Bucks Bears scored 88 in 15 overs. Aditya Rajasekar played a winning innings for Essex Eagles and won the match for Essex, becoming the man-of-the-match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trophies were presented to the winning team Essex Eagles by Mr. Krishnan one of the long standing members of SIS. Mr. Krishnan also recognized Master Abhinand Sundaram, a 8 year old boy with “STAR OF THE DAY AWARD” for his style of fielding and his classic batting.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;The ladies had a lot of fun outside the field, cheering the cricketers and playing cricket. Adhesh and Savitha entertained the rest of the players with some great music. Over all, it was a great day for SIS members with nice food and cold drinks in a mild weather, perfectly suited for a day out. Watch all the fun at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;table align="center" style="width:194px;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align="center" style="height:194px;background:url(https://picasaweb.google.com/s/c/transparent_album_background.gif) no-repeat left"&gt;&lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/sisnambalava/SISLondonCricketGalatta2011?authuser=0&amp;authkey=Gv1sRgCNiWoe_DiaDaDQ&amp;feat=embedwebsite" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/-hkizCTnpaw8/ThYSKElG_9E/AAAAAAAAAdU/gqOgMfSESOI/s160-c/SISLondonCricketGalatta2011.jpg" width="160" height="160" style="margin:1px 0 0 4px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="font-size:10px;margin-left:10px;" class="more_txt"&gt;SIS London Cricket Galatta 2011&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>July</AMonth>
  <AYear>2011</AYear>
</Article>