<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20110806074519</ArticleID>
  <category>others</category>
  <PageTitle>India Before Independence</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>india, independence day</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>An interesting article about India before Independence from Ram Nagarajan.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>India Before Independence</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2011-08-6</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Ram Nagarajan</Author>
  <MiniDescription>India also known in those days as the East Indies has a reputation of mainly portraying itself as poverty hit nation.  However, it may not have deserved this fate..</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;India also known in those days as the East Indies has a reputation of mainly portraying itself as poverty hit nation.  However, it may not have deserved this fate.  One of the factors that made India a densely populated poor country is the loss of the immense wealth looted by the British.  To many people Indian Independence Day can be seen as a joyful event. But on the other hand it could also be seen from a different perspective. Many people mourn for the deaths of the fighters who laid down their lives for their country. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, in those days India was a very multicultural country. Migrations, violence and slaughter occurred on both sides of the border. Sources show that 7,226,000 Muslims went to Pakistan from India, and 7,249,000 Hindu’s and Sikhs vice-versa. It is also thought that the death rate may be between 500,000 and 1,000,000 people.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The British from 1858 to 1947 ruled India. During this period many benefits have occurred also. The British were the first to build a railway system, they introduced the English language, and also they brought India western education and created a new educated class. But all this came with a cost, because of the British involvement: tensions between Hindu’s and Muslims still exist, dowry and poverty.  Dowry became most common in India after independence. This is because the British looted most of India’s wealth. Money became very scarce and people began to use dowry as a method to gain more wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main historical figures that were deeply involved in the Indian independence involvement were Mahatma Gandhi, Jawaharlal Nehru, and Mohammad Ali Jinnah. Jawaharlal Nehru became India’s first prime minister after independence. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of people spend this day in India celebrating and singing the national anthem. However, this should not be the case. The death rate itself shows the impact of the British invasion of India. This day should be a memorial day for all the freedom fighters who died for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>August</AMonth>
  <AYear>2011</AYear>
</Article>