<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20111109073804</ArticleID>
  <category>others</category>
  <PageTitle>How Old is Indian Civilization?</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>india, indian, indian civilization</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>An interesting article about Indian Civilization from Mr. Santhanam Swaminathan.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>How Old is Indian Civilization?</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2011-11-9</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Santhanam Swaminathan</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Western scholars always underestimate anything Indian. They would give all credits to anything Greek or Roman. After the excavations in Egypt, Sumerian and Babylonia they slowly shifted the credits to the Middle East. </MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;“We owe a lot to the Indians, who taught us how to count, without which no worthwhile scientific discovery could have been made” -Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If there is no one place on the face of the earth where all the dreams of living men have found a home from the very earliest days when man began the dream of existence, it is India”- French scholar Romaine Rolland&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Western scholars always underestimate anything Indian (of course except a few like Einstein, Romiane Rolland, Max Muller). They would give all credits to anything Greek or Roman. After the excavations in Egypt, Sumerian and Babylonia (Iraq &amp; ,Syria) they slowly shifted the credits to the Middle East. When Indians point out that they were all in Indian books, they say that they were all written later and we borrowed from them. We have a long list of Indian kings in the Puranas and Ithihasas (Mythologies and Epics). But they simply ignore them.  Indian scholars who always long for foreign trips and foreign awards must play second fiddle to them otherwise they will be rejected or dubbed as extremists. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have very clear proof in Tamil and Sanskrit literature to show that we lived for thousands of years on the same soil and we never said anywhere in our literature that we came from outside. But westerners say that the Tamil/ Dravidians came from the Mediterranean and the Northern Aryans came from Central Asia. According to them Indian History begins from 2500 BC in the Indus valley and the first king they say historical belongs to sixth century BC. Bimbisaran ruled  around 600 BC. That means we did not have any king for 1900 years from the beginning of the Indus period. Though we have a long list of kings in our scriptures they did not consider them historical. Indus valley has no King!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following proofs are enough to say that we have history supported by literature:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Kapila, the greatest of the Tamil Cankam (Sangam) poets, sings about a king called Irunkovel in Purananuru poem 201.He praises him as the 49th king in the lineage of kings who have migrated from Dwaraka after Krishna’s death. Even if we give 20 years for one generation according to western calculations, it will take us back to nearly 1000 years. Kapila lived around 100 AD. That means the first king of Irunkovel’s dynasty must have ruled around 1000 BC&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tamil and Sanskrit books always use the simile of stars in the sky and sand particles on the sea shore to compare with the kings who ruled the earth. This shows their historical sense.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;Siru Ven Theraiyar who composed poem 363 in Pura Nanuru says that the kings who ruled this earth are more than the number of sand particles on the sea shore. He also lived around first century AD. When he sang this song he must have studied Indian History or heard from his fore fathers.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Brihad Aranyaka (Big Forest ) Upanishad, which is dated by the westerners to eighth century BC ,gives a long list of teachers explaining who taught to whom ,generation after generation. They were not kings. They were all sages, around sixty names. So they wouldn’t have died young like kings in the battle fields. They would have lived for at least fifty to sixty years. Even if we allocate thirty year period for each teacher that would take us back by another 1800 years from 8th century BC. i.e 2600 BC&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A Greek writer who visited India around 3rd century BC says that India had over 140 kings before his time. Probably he was talking about the Magadha dynasty (Bihar area). Even if we have allocated 20 years each it would take us back to 2800 years from his time i.e. the day kali yuga started.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tamil and Sanskrit sources give the date of Kaliyuga without any doubt. Parthivasekapuram Copper plates of Ay Dynasty in Tamilnadu was dated 865 AD. The inscription says that it was written in the Kali year 3967. The beauty of the inscription is, it mentions the Kali year in days 14,49,087. This shows the mathematical genius of Tamils and their strong belief in Kali Yuga calculations.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Panini was the first grammarian of the world. The greatest genius the world has ever seen. He wrote a grammar for Sanskrit which made Sanskrit the fittest language for computers. With every addition of a prefix or suffix to a word the meaning changes. He was not a Brahmin. But yet Patanjali who wrote a commentary on his grammatical treatise Ashta Adhyaye (Eight Chapters) praised him as Baghavan (God) Panini. Panini in his Sutra 2.1.19 explains a custom in India. Talking about the lineage and number he gives examples as “Eka Vimsathi Bharatwajam” meaning 21st generation of Bharatwaja, “tri panchasat Gowthamam meaning 53rd generation of Gowthama. This custom is followed in all the Mutts in India. When they say who heads Sringeri or Kanchi at the moment, they always say his lineage.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Brahmin priests who perform puja on important days start it with a sankalpa (Intention to do---) where in they clearly say which part of the world they do it, when they do it and for what purpose they do it. They clearly say the year in Kali yuga under which Manvantara even today. This historical and geographical sense has no parallel in any part of the world.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The entire Indian history is balancing on a single rock-the date of Buddha’s death. Western scholars calculate everything from this back and forth. If one can tilt this balance everything will change. That is to say Indian history is on shaky grounds. But even the date of Buddha  differs from country to country. In Sri Lanka 483 BC, in Burma 544 BC ,in Tibet 835 BC and in China 11th century BC is the date of death (nirvana) for Buddha. If anyone can prove one is better or truer than others, we have to rewrite the Indian history. The shame is present day Indians have no time to do all these. They are happy to earn more and enjoy life and leave all the research to jaundice eyed western scholars.  
I can give many more examples from other epigraphs (Aihole Incription) and scriptures.Scholars like Bala Gangadhara Tilak ,Jacobi have used astronomical calculations to date our scriptures.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Over forty thousand year old human remains have been discovered in
various parts of India. Human beings have been living here for thousands of years.
I want to remind you of two Tamil proverbs before concluding. “For a scared person anything dark is a ghost” (Arandavan Kannukku Irundathu Ellam Pey). “For a person afflicted with jaundice, everything he looks at is yellow”. (Kaamaalai kannanukku kandathu ellam manjal)
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When India becomes a super power and gets a seat in the UN Security Council they will listen to us. Unless one has political or economic power nobody listens to that person.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>November</AMonth>
  <AYear>2011</AYear>
</Article>