<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20110409123319</ArticleID>
  <category>art</category>
  <PageTitle>A Simple Guide to Carnatic Music - Part III</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>carnatic music, carnatic kutchery, carnatic ragam, thaalam</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>The 72 melakarta raagas are split into 12 groups called chakras, each containing 6 raagas. The raagas within the chakra differ only in the dhaivatham and nishadham.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>A Simple Guide to Carnatic Music - Part III</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2011-04-9</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Srilatha Vijay</Author>
  <MiniDescription>The 72 melakarta raagas are split into 12 groups called chakras, each containing 6 raagas. The raagas within the chakra differ only in the dhaivatham and nishadham.</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chakras&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 72 melakarta raagas are split into 12 groups called chakras, each containing 6 raagas. The raagas within the chakra differ only in the dhaivatham and nishadham. The name of each of the 12 chakras suggest their ordinal number as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indu &lt;/strong&gt;stands for the moon, of which we have only one - hence it is the first chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netra &lt;/strong&gt;means eyes, of which we have two - hence it is the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agni &lt;/strong&gt;is the third chakra as it denotes the three divyagnis (fire, lightning and Sun). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Veda&lt;/strong&gt; denoting four Vedas is the name of the fourth chakra. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bana&lt;/strong&gt; comes fifth as it stands for the five banas of Manmadan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rutu&lt;/strong&gt; is the sixth chakra standing for the 6 seasons of Hindu calendar.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rishi&lt;/strong&gt; meaning sage, is the seventh chakra representing the seven sages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vasu&lt;/strong&gt; stands for the eight vasus of Hinduism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brahma&lt;/strong&gt; comes next of which there are 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disi&lt;/strong&gt; denotes the tenth chakra after the ten directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rudra&lt;/strong&gt; denotes the 11 Rudras.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Aditya&lt;/strong&gt; is the Twelfth which denotes the twelve suns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rules for Melakarta&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several characteristic a raaga must follow in order to qualify as Melakarta raaga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; They are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sampoorna raaga - which means they contain all seven notes (swara's) of the octave in both ascending and descending scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Krama sampoorna raaga - the sequence is strictly ascending and descending in the scales, without any jumps or zigzag notes is followed &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The upper shadjam is included in the raaga scale (ragas like Punnagavarali is not melakarta as they end with nishadham). The ascending and descending scales must have the same notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Determining the Melakartha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; A hundred years after Venkatamakhin's time the Katapayadi sankhya (The Katapayadi sankhya is a way of determining the number of a melakarta raaga from the first two syllables of the name of the raaga) rule came to be applied to the nomenclature of the melakarta raagas. below is the table of Katapayadi sankhya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table cellspacing="0" cellpadding="4" border="1" style="background-color:#FFFFFF;border-color:#000000;border-width:1px;border-style:solid;border-collapse:collapse;"&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Kadi nava&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ka&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;kha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ga&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;gha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;nga&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ca&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;cha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ja&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;jha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;nya&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Tadi nava&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ta&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;tha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;da&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;dha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ta&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ta&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;tha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;da&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;dha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;na&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Padi pancha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;pa&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;pha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ba&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;bha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ma&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Yadi ashta&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ya&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ra&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;la&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;va&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;s'ha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;sha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;sa&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;ha&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version of sankhya is based on the Roman alphabets. The digits corresponding to the first two syllables of the name of a raaga, when reversed, give the index of the raga. For example, Ramapriya raaga starts with syllables Ra and ma, which have numbers 2 and 5 associated with them. If you reverse them, you'll get 52. Hence, Ramapriya is the 52nd melakarta raga&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>April</AMonth>
  <AYear>2011</AYear>
</Article>