<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20120509083150</ArticleID>
  <category>religion</category>
  <PageTitle>108 the holy number</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>holy number, hindu holy number</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>An interesting article from Dr. Chandrasekhar titled "108 the holy number". Read and enjoy!</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>108 the holy number</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2012-05-9</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Dr R.Chandrasekhar</Author>
  <MiniDescription>The number 108 is very auspicious for Hindus. It is the number of beads of a rosary and of many other things in Indian cosmology. </MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;108 the holy number&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number 108 is very auspicious for Hindus. It is the number of beads of a rosary and of many other things in Indian cosmology. But why is this number considered to be holy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cosmology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- Distance between earth and sun = 108 times sun-diameter, &lt;br /&gt;
2- Distance between earth and moon = 108 times moon-diameter, &lt;br /&gt;
3- Diameter of the sun = 108 times the earth diameter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Astrology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 12 rasi (sun signs) of 30 degrees each in the zodiac. These rasi are connected to the Adityas (12 Sun gods) and the rasi are said to give the results of the Sun. The Sun is karaka (significator) for the 1st and the houses 9th houses. When you take each rasi and divide it into nine amsas (divisions) it creates the Navamsa (9th divisional chart). 30 degrees divided by nine gives 9 signs of 3 degrees and 20 minutes each. With each of the 12 signs containing 9 amsas there is 108 amsas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Navamsa shows the inherent qualities of the soul, a native’s dharma (purpose), bhagya (luck), and one’s spouse. The Navamsa is the 108 sign chart held in high esteem in Vedic astrology and a Vedic astrologer doesn’t read a birth chart without the navamsa sitting next to it.&lt;/p&gt;


]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>May</AMonth>
  <AYear>2012</AYear>
</Article>