<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20120709074945</ArticleID>
  <category>religion</category>
  <PageTitle>Raama Naamam</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>lord rama, raama naamam</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Read and enjoy this article titled "Raama naamam".</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Raama Naamam</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2012-07-9</ArticleDate>
  <Author>	Dr Chandrsekhar</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Once a Guru or teacher was teaching Vishnu sahasra naamam  to a group of boys aged between 8 and 12 years..</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Once a Guru or teacher was teaching Vishnu sahasra naamam  to a group of boys aged between 8 and 12 years. Guru chanted the slokam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sri Raama Raama Raamethi Rame Raame Manorame&lt;br /&gt;
Sahasranaama Tathulyam Raama Naama Varaanane&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;and told the students " if you chant Raama naamam three times, it is equivalent to chanting the whole Vishnu Sahasranaamam or chanting Lord's Naamam 1000 times. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the boys was very naughty and always had questions about everything the teacher said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately he asked " Guro, how can three times become equal to 1000 times,  I do not get the logic. Please explain to us how that equation of 3 naamams =1000 naamams works". &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guru was not only smart, but was a great devotee of Lord Raama. In one moment, Guru knew how to explain the validity of the unusual equation. He said: Lord Shiva says that the name of Lord Rama is the sweetest of all the words &amp; chanting this name would be equivalent to chanting the whole Vishnu Sahasranama or thousand names of Vishnu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the interesting calculation by which we can prove that 3 times chanting of Rama naamam becomes equivalent to 1000 times chanting or chanting the whole 
Vishnu Sahasra naamam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the name Rama. It has two letters RA and MA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you take the consonants in Sanskrit alphabet,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RA is the second consonant in the group of five consonants&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ya, RA, La, Va, Sha and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MA is the fifth in the group of five consonants Pa, Pha, Ba, Bha, MA. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you substitute the value of RA and MA as 2 and 5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RAMA is equivalent to 2x5= 10. Then,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sri Rama Rama Rama (iti) is equivalent to 2x5 x 2x5 x2x5= 10x10x10= 1000. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy was happy with the answer and started learning Vishun Sahasranaamam with full concentration and devotion. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Jai Shri Ram! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sree Seetha Lakshmana Bharatha Shathrugna Hanumath &lt;br /&gt;
Sametha Sree Ramchandraswamine Namaha&lt;/p&gt;

]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>July</AMonth>
  <AYear>2012</AYear>
</Article>