<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20120809090054</ArticleID>
  <category>recipes</category>
  <PageTitle>Vella Seedai Receipe</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>vella seedai, vella seedai receipe</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Vella Seedai Receipe!!</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Vella Seedai Receipe</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2012-08-9</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Padma Krishnamurthy</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Recipe for Vella Seedai usually made on Krishna Jayanthi!</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Rice flour(Refer above for the process): 1 Cup&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Urad dal flour: 2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Ghee/butter: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds: 1 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Jaggery: 1/4 tsp&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Water:  as needed&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Oil: For deep frying&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Grated coconut: 3 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Salt: A pinch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare rice flour as mentioned above and repeat the same process in roasting both the flours and coconut grating. Also sieve together the flours as mentioned above &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat jaggery with 1/4 cup water and boil until it dissolves.  Filter it to remove any impurities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it to light paagu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now pour the paagu, to the flour, add coconut, ghee, sesame seeds well and then add water if needed to make a dough.  Please do not add the floor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make goose berry sized balls and arrange in a dry clean cloth spread or in a news paper. Give 15 mins standing time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep fry in low flame to ensure cooking inside properly. Stir in between. Drain in paper towel and store in airtight container after it cools down completely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips for avoiding seedai burst: Do not roll tightly with pressure, do roll smooth &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you sieve the flours properly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make in small batches. Prick the seedais with a tooth pick or pin &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please fry the flours until it turns in colour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can add a tsp of coconut oil while making the dough for extra flavour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding coconut grating enhance the flavour. The seedais smell and taste best from the next day… &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The colour of the seedai will be in lighter side if you reduce urad dal flour. If you add more the colour will turn darker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just roast the flours lightly as mentioned without changing the colour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>August</AMonth>
  <AYear>2012</AYear>
</Article>