<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20120808060817</ArticleID>
  <category>others</category>
  <PageTitle>London 2012 Olympics - Why this hype?</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>london olympics, london olympics 2012</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Why this hype? - An interesting article about London 2012 Olympics.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>London 2012 Olympics - Why this hype?</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2012-08-8</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Ram</Author>
  <MiniDescription>The Olympics is an extraordinary event. Great Britain has spent millions on the bid to win Olympics...</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;The Olympics is an extraordinary event. Great Britain has spent millions on the bid to win Olympics.  In 2005, the delegation supporting London 2012 flew out to Singapore to try and win the bid to host the summer Olympic games. Great Britain was against tough competition. However, after a well laid out presentation led by Lord Coe, the Olympic committee accepted the London 2012 bid. This surprise came as great news to the whole nation and was welcomed with celebrations across the nation. Plans for hosting the Olympics soon came underway and the country has spent billions on the project, building a world class stadium, aquatics centre etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were over 200 countries lined-up in the opening ceremony. Every sportsperson has gone through rigorous training and the countries have spent billions over several years to get their sports person ready just for this event. It is not about winning a medal but it is just participation that brings pride to every sportsperson and the country he represents as a whole. It may be appropriate for us to think a bit about the history of the game and why it makes the whole world perceive this event a prestige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Olympics has a 2,700 year history.  Unbelievable Isn’t it? Yes. It is believed that the ancient Olympic games originated in Greece 2700 years back and they took place in the city of Olympia, after which the name Olympics. At that day and age, the Olympics were held to display the physical ability and aptitude of the individuals that took part. The games were dedicated to the Greek god Zeus in the belief that good relations will remain between the main cities of Greece. The games were discontinued in 393 AD due to the fact that the Emperor of Greece at the time did not think they were suitable for his ever-growing Christian empire.  The torch and the torch relay both have traditional and cultural significance, as the lighting of the torch is subsequent to a very precise ritual. The torch was lit so that a truce would form between the neighbouring cities for the extent of the games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years later, in 1894 a Frenchman named Baron Pierre de Coubertin set up the modern Olympic games. These games would follow the same layout of the ancient games with the torch, torch relay etc. He believed that the games were of great significance as they united many countries and brought together sport, culture and education. Two years after his petition for the Olympics, the first modern games took place in 1896 at Athens, Greece. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, every time the Olympics take place, an aura of excitement and enthusiastic deportment clouds the host city. The eager wait for the opening ceremony by the world signifies the importance the games have on each country. Every host country has always tried to beat the expectations in having a grand opening ceremony. Hosting the games helps as a catalyst for the economy as billions are spent on infrastructure, increased employment rate, tourism, to name a few. Additionally, the host country gets on the spotlight and becomes the centre of attraction to the world which makes the entrepreneurs more competitive and makes them easy to do business with the rest of the world. The host nation becomes a part of history, as they will be remembered for hosting the Olympic games. More than anything, people are happy and they have something to look forward. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London is very lucky to be hosting the Olympics because it will not only bring significant exposure to the world, but also prosperity and the limelight for the duration of the games. Millions of people all over the world watch the Olympics and it is simply wonderful that London is playing a major part towards it. I would like to wish good luck to all the participants of the games, especially to Team GB. In the hope that Britain will obtain a great haul of gold medals. No pressure.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>August</AMonth>
  <AYear>2012</AYear>
</Article>