<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20121015055418</ArticleID>
  <category>religion</category>
  <PageTitle>Navaratri - Day 0</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>navarathiri, navaratri</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Detailed information of Navaratri day 0.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Navaratri - Day 0</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2012-10-15</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Padma Balasubramanian</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Navaratri is an important Hindu festival which essentially symbolises the triumph of the good over the evil. Navarathri begins the day after the Mahalaya Amavasya </MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;''யா தேவீ ஸர்வ பூதேஷ§மாத்ரூ ரூபேண ஸம்ஸ்திதா நமஸ்தஸ்யைநமஸ்தஸ்யை நமஸ்தஸ்யை நமோ நம:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navaratri is an important Hindu festival which essentially symbolises the triumph of the good over the evil. Navarathri begins the day after the Mahalaya Amavasya in the Tamil month of Purattasi. The festival is celebrated as Saradha Navarathri while some call it the Saradh Navarathiri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/articles/nav-durga.jpg" alt="Nav Durga" title="Nav Durga" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nine divine days of celebration of Goddess Durga leads to spiritual growth of a person. Every human being in this universe requires power, wealth and knowledge for survival. The first 3 days of the festival is dedicated to Goddess Durga to invoke the strength within us to lead an emotionally strong life and to fight the inner demons and vices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align="center"&gt;&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_ITcJD11Q5w?list=PL5D060CB5A87C818D&amp;amp;hl=en_GB" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The next 3 days are dedicated to Goddess Lakshmi to bestow us with wealth and prosperity. There is a saying in Tamil `Porul illarkku arul illai’. Strength and wealth should be put to use wisely and we dedicate the last 3 days of the festival in worship of Goddess Saraswathi to bestow us with knowledge and spiritual enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ayi giri nandini, nanditha medini, visva vinodini, nanda nuthe |&lt;br /&gt;
Giri vara vindhya shirodhini vasini vishnu vilaasini jisnu nuthe |&lt;br /&gt;
Bhagavati he shiti kanta kutumbini bhoori kutumbini bhoori kruthe |&lt;br /&gt;
Jaya jaya he mahishaasura mardhini ramyaka pardhini shaila suthe |&lt;br /&gt;
We pray to the Supreme Mother to elevate us spiritually and attain enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>October</AMonth>
  <AYear>2012</AYear>
</Article>