<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20120809085620</ArticleID>
  <category>recipes</category>
  <PageTitle>Uppu Seedai Receipe</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>uppu seedai, uppu seedai receipe</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Uppu Seedai Receipe!!</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Uppu Seedai Receipe</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2012-08-9</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Padma Krishnamurthy</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Recipe for Uppu Seedai usually made on Krishna Jayanthi!</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Raw rice: 1 Cup&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Urad dal flour: 2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Ghee/butter: 4 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds: 2 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Asafoetida: 1/4 tsp&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Salt &amp; water:  as needed&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Oil: For deep frying&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Grated coconut: 3 tablespoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soak the rice for at least 2 hours and drain the water, spread it in a clean cloth or news paper to absorb the excess water. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grind it to a fine powder in a mixer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sieve the flour (you can add the remaining coarse rice to the next batch grinding).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat a pan and fry the flour in medium flame until the flour changes colour..&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fry the urad dal flour until nice aroma wafts. (You can fry the urad dal and powder, sieve it too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give a fry for coconut gratings too. Just fry till excess moisture is gone. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now sieve again both the roasted flours together. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix rice flour, urad flour, coconut gratings, sesame seeds, ghee, asafoetida and salt well. Add water and make it to a soft pliable dough. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take small pinch and make into ball, try not to make it perfect round or not to give pressure while rolling. Do it gently.&lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;li&gt;Repeat until you finish all the dough and arrange in a news paper or dry clean cloth. Let it be for 15 minutes.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat oil in kadai and add the seedais. For safety stand away from the stove for the first batch.Divide and cook in 3-4 batches. Cook in medium flame. stir in between to ensure even cooking. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook until the shh…sounds ceases.Drain in paper towel.Store in airt tight container after cooled down. The flavour is in its best when eaten from the next day.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crisp and flavourful seedai, ready to munch on…..&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>August</AMonth>
  <AYear>2012</AYear>
</Article>