<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20121109061522</ArticleID>
  <category>religion</category>
  <PageTitle>Pazhaiya Seevaram</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>Pazhaiya Seevaram</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>An interesting article titled "Pazhaiya Seevaram". Please read and enjoy.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Pazhaiya Seevaram</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2012-11-9</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Padma Balasubramanian</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Pazhaiya Seevaram is a small village located about 20 kms from Kanchipuram on the road going towards Chengalpattu. </MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Pazhaiya Seevaram is a small village located about 20 kms from Kanchipuram on the road going towards Chengalpattu. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pazhaya Seevaram has an ancient temple for Sri Lakshmi Narasimhar, amidst picturesque location. This temple is located on a small hill on the banks of the river Palar. It is said that 3 rivers namely, Palar (Ksheera Nadhi), Cheyyar (Bahu Nadhi) and Vegavathi (Saraswathi) merge here to become one and it is called Triveni Sangamam. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hill on which the temple is located is called Padmagiri. According to the Sthala Puranam, once in Naimisaaranyam, Vishnu Siththar enquired with the other Rishis about a best place where he can get the Dharshan of Lord Vishnu as result of penance. &lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Mareecha Muni, another Rishi guided Vishnu Siththar to Padmagiri and narrated the story of Athri Maharishi who got the Darshan of Sri Lakshmi Narasimhar as fruitful result of his severe and dedicated penance. It is said that, Athri Rishi, after having Dharshan of the Lord, prayed the Lord to stay in this place and bless the people worshipping here. The Lord accepted his wish and stayed here in the same form to bless the mankind.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The main deity, Lord Sri Lakshmi Narasimhar is having the Goddess Lakshmi seated on his lap and go by the Thirunamam, Saanthamurthy. Though the temple is facing east, the Lord in the sanctum is facing west towards Kanchipuram.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The Goddess here has a separate shrine on the southern side of the sanctum and is called Sri Ahobilavalli Thaayaar.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Sri Aandal shrine is located on the north western side facing east.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;There are shrines for Nammaazhvaar, Thirumangai Aazhwaar and Vishnu Chiththar together at the Praakaaram.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;According to the legend, there is a link between this temple and Kanchipuram Sri Varadaraja temple. Every year, during the Thamizh month of ‘Thai’, on Kaanum Pongal day, the Lord Sri Varadharaja Perumal from Kanchipuram is brought to this hill temple which is popularly called ‘Paarvaettai’ or ‘Malai Urchavam’ (hill festival). On that day, the Urchavar of Sri Varadharajar from Kanchi, is kept in a stone Mandapam on top of the hill, from where he gives dharshan to the people. This event is very popular here. There are steps to reach the top of the hill from the place where the temple is located. It is said that the stone Mandapam too is facing towards Kanchipuram on the west. &lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>November</AMonth>
  <AYear>2012</AYear>
</Article>