<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20120413112036</ArticleID>
  <category>others</category>
  <PageTitle>Super Star Rajinikanth in London</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>super star rajinikanth, rajinikanth in london</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Super star Rajinikanth in London for Tamil Movie Kochadayyan!! Karthik Raghavan and Sathish Duraiswamy met him during his stay in London.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Super Star Rajinikanth in London</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2012-04-13</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Padma Krishnamurthy</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Kochadayyan count down starts. Super Star was in London towards end March to shoot for the animation movie, Kochadayyan being directed by his daughter, Soundarya Rajinikanth..</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Kochadayyan count down starts. Super Star was in London towards end March to shoot for the animation movie, Kochadayyan being directed by his daughter, Soundarya Rajnikanth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of very lucky SIS committee members who are die-hard fans of Rajnikanth got the opportunity to meet the Batcha at his hotel in West London and exchange a few words. The absolutely crazy fans were short of words and became totally emotional as their dream of 30 years to meet the Super Star came true. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/articles/rajinikanth-london-1.jpg" alt="Superstar Rajinikanth in London" title="Superstar Rajinikanth in London" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10px; text-align:center;"&gt;Karthik Raghavan - Rajinikanth - Sathish Duraisamy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ever humble Rajinikanth exchanged pleasantries and enquired about their career, posed for photos and also accepted their gift of a book and picture of Swami Vivekananda. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2 lucky SIS committee members are our very own Karthik Raghavan and Sathish Duraisamy who was also joined by Revathy Mahadevan. These guys were the first and may be the only fans to meet the superstar in London. They however deserve this Darshan as they keep claiming. Karthik and Sathish have been haunting the Pinewood Studios, Radisson Hotel and several known spots as well as locations based on anonymous phone calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They hit the lottery on 25th March Sunday, Aandavan sodhichan but kai vidallai and there came the superstar with the ace director K.S. Ravikumar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/articles/rajinikanth-london-2.jpg" alt="Superstar Rajinikanth in London" title="Superstar Rajinikanth in London" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10px; text-align:center;"&gt;Sathish Duraisamy - Rajinikanth - Revathy Mahadevan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest is history as their glory has been sung in Facebook and Dinamalar. Director K.S. Ravikumar was stupefied as Rajinikanth staying in Radisson was a well maintained secret. Hats off to these two – they could penetrate where even wind feared to enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super star had lost weight but his magnetic smile and charm remained intact. What was striking according to our members was his humility and gentleness. Rajini Sir, we love you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s all wish the Superstar continued good health and long life besides super fantastic success for Kochadayyan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members – be ready to shake the hands which were held by Rajinikanth and hug the body which was hugged by Rajini. You can hear firsthand the thrilling experience and emotions of Sathish Duraisamy/Revathy Mahadevan and Karthik Raghavan on April 21 at our Tamil New Year’s Day function.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>April</AMonth>
  <AYear>2012</AYear>
</Article>