<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20120607024549</ArticleID>
  <category>others</category>
  <PageTitle>My Sojourn in India - Part 2</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>india, sojourn</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Read and enjoy this article titled "My Sojourn in India" Part 2.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>My Sojourn in India - Part 2</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2012-06-7</ArticleDate>
  <Author>C.Vedanarayanan</Author>
  <MiniDescription>On 17th December there was a musical discourse by Valayappatti  Sri Krishnan and his troupe, in Sitadevi Garodia school at east Tambaram..</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;On 17th December there was a musical discourse by Valayappatti  Sri Krishnan and his troupe, in Sitadevi Garodia school at east Tambaram, arranged by Tambaram Asthika Sabha. This sabha functions under the guidance of Sri N.V.Subramaniam, a retired senior official of Southern Railway. He even served as the general manager of Southern Railway. He is also well known for running Saraswathi Vaggeyakara Trust, an organisation dedicated to promoting Carnatic music. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sri Krishnan’s discourse was about the grace of Lord Muruga. He was very ably, musically supported by Srimathi T.V.Sundaravalli and Smt.Bhavya. Over the years, this group has released many musical cassettes, CDs and books on Lord Muruga.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 18th December, we had a thirumurai recital by an oduvar. This monthly feature is organised by our thiruneri manram at the residence of Sri P.Jayachandran. Every month, we invite an oduvar to east Tambaram for a recital covering all the twelve thirumurais and prayers to Muruga and goddess. Most of the oduvars are in an indigent position and our modest SAMBHAVANAI helps to alleviate his needs, at least temporarily. There is a core audience which is generous. We also get occasional visitors. At the end of the recital, sundal and ragi malt is distributed.  Thanks giving and announcement of the next month’s event is a regular feature. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22nd December saw me at Kanchipuram Kamakoti matam. This was the day when Brahacharanam sect of the smarthas offered biksha to our Gurus. Every year this is undertaken as a KAINKARYAM by Sri R.Venkatasubramaniam of Angarai, known as Lalgudi auditor. There were panchakachchams and madisar sarees everywhere. We had darshan of both acharyas and paid our obeisance to maha periyaval’s  athishtanam.  Both the acharyas made enquiries to my sambandhi and me regarding the forthcoming marriage of Rishi/Uthra and gave their blessings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we went to Orikkai ( Orirukkai ), a few miles from Kanchi,  to see the manimandapam of Maha periyaval. This is nearly complete. You could see the semblance of Pallava and Chola architecture in the construction. The mandapam is fairly huge and beautiful. The moolasthanam is dedicated to maha periyaval. Silence is encouraged to facilitate meditation.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>June</AMonth>
  <AYear>2012</AYear>
</Article>