<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20131021023249</ArticleID>
  <category>recipes</category>
  <PageTitle>Tilda Grand Vegetarian Biryani </PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>Tilda Grand Vegetarian Biryani , Vegetarian Biryani</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Tilda Grand Vegetarian Biryani Recipe!</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Tilda Grand Vegetarian Biryani </ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2013-10-21</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Lena -Tilda</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Recipe for Tilda Grand Vegetarian Biryani..</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p style="float:right;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/articles/tilda-vegetarian-biryani.jpg" alt="Tilda Grand Vegetarian Biryani" title="Tilda Grand Vegetarian Biryani" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10px; text-align:center;"&gt;Tilda Grand Vegetarian Biryani&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the masala paste:&lt;br /&gt;

3 x green chillies&lt;br /&gt;

3 x cloves garlic&lt;br /&gt;

3cm ginger, peeled and roughly chopped&lt;br /&gt;

Pinch of salt&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

For the vegetable mixture:&lt;br /&gt;

100g cubed butternut squash&lt;br /&gt;

100g cauliflower florets&lt;br /&gt;

50g frozen peas&lt;br /&gt;

4 fresh tomatoes chopped&lt;br /&gt;

2 tsp ginger and garlic paste&lt;br /&gt;

2 tsp coriander powder&lt;br /&gt;

1 tsp chilli powder&lt;br /&gt;

1 tsp turmeric powder&lt;br /&gt;

½ tsp fennel seed&lt;br /&gt;

2 tbsp vegetable oil&lt;br /&gt;

½ tsp salt&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

 
For the biryani rice:&lt;br /&gt;

200g Tilda Grand, Extra Long Grain Rice&lt;br /&gt;

100ml vegetable oil&lt;br /&gt;

1 tsp salt&lt;br /&gt;

1 pinch of saffron strands soaked in 5-6 tsp of warm water&lt;br /&gt;

75g melted butter&lt;br /&gt;

½ tsp garam masala&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
Start of by making the masala paste by crushing together the chillies, garlic and ginger with a pinch of salt. Then set aside.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To make the vegetable mixture base, in a deep pan bring to boil 650ml of water, then add the butternut squash and cauliflower and cook for 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Add the peas to the pan and boil for a further 2 minutes. Drain the vegetables in a colander and set aside 650ml of the vegetable cooking water.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Now heat the oil in a pan and add the ginger and garlic paste, the coriander powder, chilli powder, fennel seed and turmeric and stir fry for one minute.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Stir in the tomatoes and salt and cook for a further 5 minutes or until the tomatoes are soft.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Add the remaining cooked vegetables to the pan and mix until all the vegetables are coated in the spices.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;For the biryani rice, rinse the rice three times in cold water and drain well. Heat 100ml of oil in a large pan on medium heat. Add the rice, salt and masala paste from earlier and stir. Pour in the 650ml of vegetable cooking water.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Boil the rice on medium heat for 8-10 minutes then cover with a lid, until the water has evaporated and the rice is cooked.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cool the rice for 10 minutes then mix in the butter and gently combine. Now add the garam masala, salt, saffron and mix well. You now have the 2 parts of the biryani (the biryani rice and the vegetable mixture).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To finish of the dish layer the rice and vegetables. In a heavy lidded pan add a layer of rice (about 2-3cm deep) then add a layer of the vegetables on top of the rice. Repeat this process until you end up with a top layer of rice. Cover with the lid and place on low heat for 30 minutes. Serve piping hot!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>October</AMonth>
  <AYear>2013</AYear>
</Article>