<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20130819112022</ArticleID>
  <category>others</category>
  <PageTitle>A message from a Methodist Guru</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>A message from a Methodist Guru</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Interesting article titled "A message from a Methodist Guru" read and enjoy!</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>A message from a Methodist Guru</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2013-08-19</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Sowmya Murali</Author>
  <MiniDescription>To err is Human, to forgive is Divine...I suppose if anyone had to give justice to the above, it would be paramguru Swami Vivekananda...</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;To err is Human, to forgive is Divine...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose if anyone had to give justice to the above, it would be paramguru Swami Vivekananda. He is one guru, who I feel always spoken in sync to what people wanted to hear. Most people at his time, spoken on the gospels of the religion and the way to attain moksha and divinity. But Swami Vivekananda was among the rare individualist, who with his methodist approach spoken what man needed to hear, rather than what he wanted. 
As someone who is a fan of his teachings, I can safely say that he is the right guru to the current generation of lost and impatient souls. Why so, because we are one impatient lot, and for the age which lives solely on Instant everything, everything from food to advice to even results are expected to be on the fast track and dished out soon as the order is placed. For such a generation, Swami Vivekananda is the right person to turn into for guidance and also for hope. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A message that I hold dear to me from him is the will to not back down even when you lack courage. A excerpt from his life that made a huge impact for me was the time when he went to represent Hinduism in the “Parliament of World’s Religions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a maiden voyage, going to America wasn’t an easy job. He was both broke by the end of first week and almost ended up being homeless. But luck and grace being his forever weapons stayed with him, from which he took his drive to move forward. With the kind help from, Prof John Henry Wright Swami Vivekananda finally made it to the conference. But his battle was not yet over. Placed right next to the stairway riding up the stage was a huge plank-card with the slogan in bold letters,
“Hindu Religion is a Dead Religion”.  Unless for a man, who had greatness and virtue seeped into his bones, such a comment when directed to you, who is representing the same will never be handled well. If you or I or any so called modern generation were to see that slogan, I am sure fists would have flown faster than words. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the present generation comprised of 20 somethings and 30 somethings aren’t entirely a bad sort. We have enough values and have more strength in us to make choice and choose our destiny. We are more in control of our life and possess a clarity where our choices are mostly right. But the same clarity and strength are also our weakness. In such circumstance and confusion, the gospels of Swami Vivekananda are like a cool breeze on a hot day. His messages are direct and straight, with meaning so simple yet very true. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some messages from his gospels:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"In a day where you don't come across problems, you can be sure you are travelling in the wrong path."&lt;br/ &gt;
"It is Fearlessness that brings Heaven even for a moment"&lt;br /&gt;
"We are what our thoughts makes us; so make sure you take care of what you think"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A person is who he makes himself, only if he knows what he has to make of his life. Then again, to be sure that what he is doing is the right, one needs a source to lead. One such person, anybody can follow, though his physical presence is no longer here is Swami Vivekananda. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Swamiji was a man who had great faith in the Youth of India. His one lesson to all were “Arise Awake and Stand up to assert yourself”. He believed that the future rested in such capable hands and we must all we can to take his teachings and ascertain the faith he has on us. A message that one must keep in heart;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"They alone live, who help others; the rest are more dead than alive."&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>August</AMonth>
  <AYear>2013</AYear>
</Article>