<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20130521024533</ArticleID>
  <category>others</category>
  <PageTitle>The King of all fruits - Mangoes</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>mangoes, kinf of all fruits</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>An interesting article about Mangoes - King of all fruits.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>The King of all fruits - Mangoes</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2013-05-21</ArticleDate>
  <Author> Mediamanage.com</Author>
  <MiniDescription>In India, people welcome the summer season despite the scorching heat just to enjoy the delicious summer fruit- mango..</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;In India, people welcome the summer season despite the scorching heat just to enjoy the delicious summer fruit- mango. Mangoes are found in abundance only in the summer season. It is a well-liked fruit and hence it is also known as the ‘King of fruits’. In the Hindu Vedas mango is considered to be the food of the gods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Nutritive values:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangoes are rich in nutrients. It is an excellent source of vitamins, minerals and antioxidants. It also contains traces of magnesium, manganese, selenium, calcium, iron, and phosphorus which are very important for our body. It is high in energy and beta carotene that is an important antioxidant that helps to prevent major illnesses like cancer and tuberculosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mango is a gift of nature in the summer, not only for its delicious taste but also for its numerous health benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangoes contain vitamin A and E which are good for the eyes. Eating mangoes regularly helps to prevent dryness of the eye, night blindness, softening of the cornea, refractive errors, itching and burning in the eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangoes are abundant in minerals like potassium and magnesium and also contain traces of elements like copper. The high potassium content helps to keep blood pressure under control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangoes are a good source of vitamin A and E. They help in relieving clogged pores of the skin. Eating mangoes regularly makes the skin soft and shining and also offers a clearer complexion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangoes contain digestive enzymes that help to break down proteins and helps indigestion. The digestive enzymes also help to combat poor digestion and acidity. Mango also contains high amount of fibre that helps to prevent constipation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangoes are a very good source of vitamin-B6 (pyridoxine) that helps in lowering of homocysteine levels which in turn minimises the possibility of development of cardio vascular diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fruit has high levels of vitamin C. They help in better iron absorption and hence are beneficial to individuals suffering from anaemia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangoes help to develop concentration among children. They contain glutamine acids that keeps the cells active and boosts memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mango can be a good choice for people looking at weight gain because of its high nutritional value. A 100 grams of mango contains about 75 calories, hence it beneficial for people who wish to gain weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phenols in mangoes such as fisetin, astragalin, gallic acid, quercetin, as well as abundant enzymes have cancer preventing capacities.  Mangoes also contain soluble dietary fibre pectin.  It has been studied that there is a strong link between eating lots of fibre and a lower risk of cancer of the gastrointestinal tract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose the best mangoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose the mangoes that are firm but yield to slight pressure.  While choosing mangoes, it is important to check that the skin is unbroken and the colour is changing from green to yellow, orange or red. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ripen a tender green mango, you can place the unripe mangoes in a paper bag with a ripe mango. Do not buy mangoes that have too many black spots as it is an indication that the fruit is over ripe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Store mangoes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although mango is a summer fruit, it is important to store them in a cool place for a longer shelf life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mangoes can be eaten both raw and ripe as they have similar nutritional values. So guys, enjoy the summer season and mangoes the healthy way!&lt;/p&gt;

]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>May</AMonth>
  <AYear>2013</AYear>
</Article>