<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20140428054752</ArticleID>
  <category>others</category>
  <PageTitle>SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations 2014 - Overview</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>2014 tamil new year, tamil new year celebrations, London tamil new year celebrations</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>An overview of South Indian Society London Tamil New Year Celebrations 2014.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>SIS Tamil New Year Celebrations 2014</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2014-04-28</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Divya Sundar</Author>
  <MiniDescription>SIS celebrated the Tamil New Year (Jaya Varusham) on April 26th 2014 at Canons High School, Edgware.</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;SIS celebrated the Tamil New Year (Jaya Varusham) on April 26th 2014 at Canons High School, Edgware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event started at 5.30 PM with an Invocation to Lord Muruga sung by Varun Nathan followed by the Panchagam reading by the SIS Veteran Sivasankaran mama. Then the little girls Sahana Nagasundar,Swastha Shankar,Anusha Choubina,Shruthi Ranjani Murali,Smrithi Karthikkumar &amp; Jahnavi Giridhar in their “ Aruvadai Arumbugal”  show cased beautifully about harvesting with their dance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="float:right; margin:0px 0px 10px 10px;"&gt;
&lt;table style="width:194px;"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td align="center" style="height:194px;background:url(https://www.gstatic.com/pwa/s/v/lighthousefe_241.01/transparent_album_background.gif) no-repeat left"&gt;&lt;a href="https://picasaweb.google.com/108698373308110881418/SIS_TNY_2014?authuser=0&amp;authkey=Gv1sRgCJ6R5_aSqOfuRw&amp;feat=embedwebsite" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-LiYU62pzyT4/U1w8D6cKpeE/AAAAAAAAIFU/-8VGHIFNFsM/s160-c/SIS_TNY_2014.jpg" width="160" height="160" style="margin:1px 0 0 4px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style="text-align:center;font-family:arial,sans-serif;font-size:11px"&gt;Tamil New Year April 2014&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nivedita Narayanan a renowed carnatic vocalist and her troupe Viswanath Sankaran one of the few chitravina artist and the young Branavan Navaneethan who played mridangam gave us a beautiful rendition which made the audience spellbound. Nivedita made the event very lively with her music quiz  and the audience actively participated and 3 prizes were given out to the winners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came our little Bharathiyar Bharathwaj Srinivasan affectionately called as ‘Kuttan’ in SIS circles who sang Kaakai Chiraginile Nandalaala followed by the dance duo of Sahana Sathish and Keerthi Giridhar who with their concept of ‘Andrum Indrum’ danced for the old and new songs creating a bridge for the two generations. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come What May ... We will dance was the motto of the Trio of Vinisha Martin,Anaga Murali &amp; Ananya Govindarajan who in their “Megam Kottattum Aattam Undu” in their stunning blue outfit with matching umbrella danced for a collection of rain songs..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The all new colourful website of SIS – &lt;a href="http://www.sisnambalava.org.uk/"&gt;www.sisnambalava.org.uk&lt;/a&gt; was launched on this special occasion by Karthik Raghavan and Subramanian Gopalakrishnan current committee members. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align="center"&gt;
&lt;table align="center"&gt;
&lt;tr style="margin-top:10px;"&gt;&lt;td&gt;
&lt;iframe width="500" height="275" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/juzREsgbrWk" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Murali Ramadoss and his group of artiste with their drama ‘Marsil's Mangatha’ took all of us in to a different world and filled the audience with laughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event that started with Lord Muruga rightly finished with Lord Krishna with the semi-classical dance by Vinita Suryanarayanan and Asweni Prem for a good mix of Kirshna songs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole event was anchored very well by Vijay Srinivasan and Srilatha Vijay dressed in traditional outfits and kept the whole evening lively with their compering. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Divya Sundar, committee member proposed a formal vote of thanks to everyone present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a feast of the programme all the people had a feast of Indian dinner.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>April</AMonth>
  <AYear>2014</AYear>
</Article>