<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20140221071233</ArticleID>
  <category>religion</category>
  <PageTitle>The Night of Nights of Parameswara -The Supreme Lord Mahashivaratri</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>Nights of Parameswara,Mahashivaratri</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Article about Maha Shivaratri, nights of Parameswara.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>The Night of Nights of Parameswara -The Supreme Lord Mahashivaratri</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2014-02-21</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Source: Tambrapatrika</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Maha Shivaratri is celebrated widely in temples all over Andhra Pradesh, Karnataka, Kerala and Tamil Nadu. Shiva is considered the Adi (first) Guru from whom the yogic tradition originates..</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Maha Shivaratri is celebrated widely in temples all over Andhra Pradesh, Karnataka, Kerala and Tamil Nadu. Shiva is considered the Adi (first) Guru from whom the yogic tradition originates. According to tradition, the planetary positions on this night are such that there is a powerful natural upsurge of energy in the human system. It is said to be beneficial for one's physical and spiritual well-being to stay awake and aware throughout the night. On this day, artists from various fields such as music and dance perform the whole night. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sahasrakalasabishekam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very special and rare puja conducted during 10 days of the Maha Sivarathri festival. It is well known that Lord Siva is abhishekapriya (lover of ablutions). Lord Parasurama and Kroshta Muni, during their worship of the Lord, are believed to have bathed the deity with Sahasrakalasam or a thousand pots of holy water according to Vedic rites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Mahasivarathri festival days the Head Priest (Thanthri) and his team perform this puja. It is a ten-day function, each day an offering of 101 Kalasam or pots of holy water (100 being made of silver, while one is made of gold), surcharged with mantras recited by learned Brahmins seated on the Mukhamantapam. These are emptied on the deity, the golden pot Brahmakalasam being the last one. A magnificent light is the indication or identity of Lord Shiva and the Shiva Lingam is considered to be the symbol of it. Hence, the formal worship on Maha Shivaratri consists of bathing the Shiva Lingam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lord Shiva is said to be burning with the fire of austerity and so only those items are offered to Him that have a cooling effect. A cool water bath is believed to propitiate Him best. There is a belief a m o n g d e v o t e e s t h a t p a rt i c i p a t i o n i n Sahasrakalasam and offering holy worship materials, will lead to blessings with prosperity and peaceful life. Hundreds of devotees thronging the shrine with chants of "Namah Shivaya", "Hara hara Mahadeva", and "Sambho Mahadeva"...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Sivarathri Nrutham&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sivarathri Nrutham at Thrikkuratti temple, according to religious scholars, resembles the cosmic dance of Shiva, called ‘Anandatandava,' meaning, the Dance of Bliss, symbolising the cosmic cycles of creation and destruction, as well as the daily rhythm of birth and death. The dance is a pictorial allegory of the five principle manifestations of eternal energy – creation, destruction, preservation, salvation, and illusion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Priest keeps the sheeveli vigraha (idol) fixed on a decorated frame on his head. He makes seven rounds on Pradakshina Vazhi (holy walkway made of granite around Sanctum Santorum). When the fifth round is reached at the west nada (Parvathi nada), the door opens for just 10 minutes. This is an annual ceremony. Thousands of Pilgrims rush to have a glance of this auspicious moment. At this time all the pradakshina vazhi is lit with camphor and brass temple lamps by thousands of devotes who stay awake through the night while chanting "Nama Sivaya", "Hara Hara Mahadeva" and "Sambho Mahadeva". and "Hara sankara siva sankara duritham kala sivane". In this enlightened serene mood, the Priest performs Nrutham and runs on the pradakshina vazhi towards the east nada. During the next two rounds he accepts "Valiya kanikka". The Sivarathri Nrutham is followed by the well known magnificent display of fireworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Mahasivarathri Procession &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sivarathri day evening a grand procession starts from Kadapra Kainikkara Temple. It includes, several decorated floats, Kaavadi Aaatam, Mayilattom, Amman Kudom, Thaiyyam, Vela Kali, Kuthiyotta Chuvadu, richly caparisoned elephants and folk art forms etc. attracts thousands of devotees and tourists. When the main procession reaches Market Junction, other mini processions from Kurattikkadu Mutharamman Temple, Kurattissery Kannamkavil Mutharamman Temple, Thrippavoor Mahavishnu Temple, Vishavarsherikkara Subrahmanya Swami temple, Sreekaryam Maliekal Rajan temple, and Alumoodu Sivaparvathy Temple join the main one and make the procession quite livening. The marvellous as well as magical effect of the Sinakari melam and Panchavadyam, a combination of five percussion and wind instruments is to be felt and enjoyed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the varieties of festivals celebrated in Kerala, Thrikkuratti Sivarathri Procession is one of the most spectacular. It is an expression of popular fascination for sound and colour, and because of the pageantry, it appeals to all people including foreigners. Once the procession reaches the temple, Deeparadhana is followed by colourful display of fireworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Panchaakshari&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shiva, as the god of destroying evil, is the third among the divine trinity of Hindu mythology. The holy mantra consisting of five-syllables: "Na" "Ma" "Shi" "Vaa" "Ya" (Om NamaH Shivaaya) in praise of Lord Shiva is chanted incessantly on special occasions like Shivaratri. Shiva means auspicious. As Shankara, He is the giver of happiness to all. Nataraja (the king of dancers) is a favourite form adored by dancers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Rudrabhisheka&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a special set of mantras in the Vedas, Rudra sukta, which is recited by priests while they offer a holy bath to the Shiva Lingam with the waters of sacred rivers like the Ganges, cow milk, curd (yoghurt), ghee,, honey and sugar powder. This ritual, known as "Rudrabhisheka", is an important part of Shiva-puja. Mysticism According to the Puraanaas. The Kailasa peak of the Himalayas is the abode of Shiva and He bears the Ganges on His head. As the Lord of creatures, He is metaphorically called as Pashupathi (with Nandi, the bull, His favourite animal) and His fearless nature is euphemised as Sarpabhushana. Shiva's posture, in meditation, is ascribed to Him as the head of Yogis (Yogiraja) who practises various spiritual feats to attain salvation. Lord Shiva's divine consort, Goddess Parvati (daughter of Himalaya), is the deity of strength.&lt;/p&gt;

]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>February</AMonth>
  <AYear>2014</AYear>
</Article>