<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20140820080446</ArticleID>
  <category>recipes</category>
  <PageTitle>Nendram Pazham Pradhaman Recipe</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>Nendram Pazham Pradhaman</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Recipe to make Nendram Pazham Pradhaman!</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Nendram Pazham Pradhaman</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2014-08-20</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Latha Aiyer</Author>
  <MiniDescription>Recipe for Nendram Pazham Pradhaman..</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Thiruvonam is round the corner and falls on 6th September 2014 this year. Onam is a harvest festival celebrated in Kerala. As Payasam is an important part of any South Indian Feast, starting this column with a traditional recipe for Nendram Pazham Pradhaman. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you’ll need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nendram Pazham (Cooking Plantain) – 3, ripe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thin Coconut Milk – 2 ½ cups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thick Coconut Milk – 1 cup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Powdered Jaggery – 2 cups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cocount – ¼ cup, cut into small pieces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghee – 1 tbsp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cut the nendram pazham into 2 inch pieces with the skin and steam them. Allow to cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove skin; also remove the black stem like thing from the inside of the banana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grind the banana and make it into a smooth pulp, do not add any water while grinding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat a thick bottom Kadai, add the jaggery with ½ cup of water. Dissolve the jaggery completely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strain for impurities and pour it back into the Kadai.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the nendram pazham pulp and mix well. Stir it well and mash with the back of the spatula if you find any lumps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook on medium heat for 4 to 5 minutes, stirring continuously, till the banana and jaggery mixture come together as a mass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now add the thin coconut milk and cook on medium flame for 8 to 10 minutes. Stir occasionally to avoid burning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn of flame and add the Thick coconut milk. Mix well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat a small frying pan with ghee, fry the coconut pieces in it till brown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add these fried coconut pieces to the prepared payasam and serve warm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delicious nendram pazham pradhaman is ready to be devored. &lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>August</AMonth>
  <AYear>2014</AYear>
</Article>