<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Article>
  <ArticleID>20140224060636</ArticleID>
  <category>art</category>
  <PageTitle>Mindful Mudra in Meditation - Yoga Practice Guide</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>meditation, yoga guide</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Mindful mudra in meditation, a yoga practice tips and guide from Sam Anand.</MetaDescription>
  <ArticleHeading>Mindful Mudra in Meditation</ArticleHeading>
  <ArticleDate>2014-02-24</ArticleDate>
  <Author>Sam Anand</Author>
  <MiniDescription>The word "Mudra" means energy seal.  Hand Mudras are physical actions that directly effect universal energy/pranic energy within the astral and physical body..</MiniDescription>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;strong&gt;"Mudra"&lt;/strong&gt; means energy seal.  Hand Mudras are physical actions that directly effect universal energy/pranic energy within the astral and physical body. These Mudras are used widely in the following fields&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dance (to express feelings and emotions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rituals (during worship and Yagnas to invoke God)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hatha Yoga (to help stabilise the mind)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do they denote?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the Science of Mudra, the 5 fingers of our hands represents the 5 natural elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The thumb indicates &lt;strong&gt;Fire/Agni&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The index finger indicates &lt;strong&gt;Air/Vaayu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The middle finger indicates &lt;strong&gt;Space/Akash&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ring finger indicates &lt;strong&gt;Earth/Adi Parashakthi&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Aditi&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The little finger indicates &lt;strong&gt;Water/Jala&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chin Mudra (Gesture of Consciousness)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stretch and relax the hands and place gently on top of the knees or thighs, place thumb nail to index nail and let other fingers softly extend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such mudras are difficult to hold simply because you have to stay physically still in both body and mind.  It will invent disturbance to try and somehow make you move out of it.
Try to resist this, unless the source of disturbance really warrants it (like a sobbing child who 
needs your attention immediately, for instance!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/articles/yoga-instructor-sam-anand.jpg" alt="Yoga instructor Sam Anand" title="Yoga instructor Sam Anand" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10px; text-align:center;"&gt;Yoga instructor Sam Anand in Chin Mudra&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to practice Chin Mudra?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit comfortably in any meditative posture (Vajrasana/ Padmasana) or even on a chair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let the hands relax in Chin Mudra.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit with back straight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shut eyes.  Continue to breathe relaxed breaths initially, lets say for 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can time yourself with a soft timer.  When this time is over, sit still for a few more seconds, rub your palms together and cup them gently on your eyelids before opening them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to breathe using Chin Mudra in meditative postures?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In Vajrasana, simply let the hands rest on the knees in Chin Mudra)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simply breathe letting go, relaxing your mind, body and breathing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inhale right up to the top of your lungs and fully exhale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, inhale (Purakam) gently (not forcefully) up to 4 counts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relax your chest and hold the breath (Kumbakam) up to 16 counts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Softly exhale (Rechakam) up to 8 counts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The usual ratio of retention (holding breath) is &lt;strong&gt;1:4:2 (inhale:retain:exhale)&lt;/strong&gt;, in other words retain your breath in a proportion of x4 to your inhalation and exhale in a proportion of x2 to your inhalataion, however &lt;strong&gt;beginners&lt;/strong&gt; can just practice at &lt;strong&gt;1:1:1 ratio&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;img src="/images/articles/chin-mudra.jpg" alt="Chin Mudra" title="Chin Mudra" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:10px; text-align:center;"&gt;Chin Mudra&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why practice Chin Mudra?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes Prana flow evenly throughout the body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduces fatigue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removes ego, anger &amp; negative thoughts and flushes the mind with positivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeps mind calm and balanced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
  <AMonth>February</AMonth>
  <AYear>2014</AYear>
</Article>