<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20101127065124</EventID>
  <PageTitle>SIS Annual Sports Event 2010 - United Kingdom</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>sis sports event, sis 20-20 cricket match</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>Come and join South Indian Society Annual Sports event 2010 at Harrow, London on 10th Jul 2010.</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>SIS Annual Sports Event 2010</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2010-07-10</EventDate>
  <EventTime>10 a.m. to 2 p.m.</EventTime>
  <Address>Recreation Ground, Pinner Road, Harrow, Middlesex, HA1 1PB.</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Please join us for the SIS Annual Sports event, that will be held on JULY 10, 2010 SATURDAY from 10 AM TO 2 PM. at the RECREATION GROUND, PINNER ROAD, HARROW, MIDDLESEX HA1 1PB (Adults: £5 / Children up to 12 years £ 2)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate or cheer a team in the 20/20 cricket match for Men / Boys followed by a game of 10/10 for beginners including ladies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge yourselves to various creative and entertaining games that will be organised parallel to the 20-20 cricket&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate in our Thinnaik katcheri ( gossip group)! - on from 10.00 to 14/00&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just relax and enjoy all activities around!! including the snack lunch that will be provided!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan to have 2 teams to play the 20-20 match. If you are interested in playing, please confirm and register your participation with Subbu - 0783746 6338 or PK - 01296 748336 on or before Sunday 5th July. In order for the teams to be balanced, when you register, we request you to furnish the following information : What is your speciality (batsman / bowler - fast or spin / wicket keeper and if you are still playing regular cricket etc.). Alternatively please fill your details in the attached form and have it mailed to 
southindiansociety.london2010@googlemail.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While every effort would be made to include as many of you as possible, inclusion in the team will be on a 1st come basis and therefore we request you to please register your participation immediately.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>