<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20110324060748</EventID>
  <PageTitle>SIS Cricket 2011</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>South Indian Society Cricket, cricket Galatta, harrow cricket</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society presents Annual Sports event "Cricket Galatta 2011".</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>SIS Cricket Galatta 2011</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2011-07-09</EventDate>
  <EventTime>9 am onwards</EventTime>
  <Address>Recreation Ground, Pinner Road, Harrow, Middlesex, HA1 1PB.</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;On the 9th of July, Essex Ekambaram XI, Harrow Sendamarai XI, Middlesex Mailvaganam XI, Bucks Balakrishna XI will meet each other at Harrow Recreation Ground to decide the strongest team. Do we have a Tendulkar, Dhoni, Kholi, Raina, Sehwag, Badrinath or Chris Gayle disguised in our society?  We don’t know yet.  That will be revealed on Saturday the 9th of July at Harrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Trustees of SIS proudly announces the most awaited SIS Cricket 2011. After a grand success of SIS Cricket event 2010 and due to popular demand, we have organised the event for this year on the 9th of July 2011. That day will be a cricket day and the games will be played at the same ground as last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Admission&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an incentive to encourage early confirmations and payments whilst simultaneously attempting to keep costs and food wastage down to the minimum, the entrance fee has been restructured as follows:&lt;br /&gt;

Reduced fee for Members Confirming &amp; Paying in advance (by 2nd July): £7 (Preferred option)&lt;br /&gt;
Members paying at the venue: £10&lt;br /&gt;
Non members : £12&lt;br /&gt;
Children (between 5 and 10) : £4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Agenda&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;
9:00 am to 10:00 am: Assembly&lt;br /&gt;
10:00 am to 12:30 pm: Cricket&lt;br /&gt;
12:30 pm to 1:30 pm: Lunch&lt;br /&gt;
1:30 pm to 4:30 pm: Cricket&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gear, beer and notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please be informed, every individual irrespective of participating or cheering are required to pay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you send your RSVP, please specify your areas of expertise, from one of the following. 
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Batting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wicket Keeping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase / medium fast bowling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spin bowling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheering&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The game will start sharp at 10 am. We request you to be on time.  You will be automatically be fall into the cheering group if you are late.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We request you to bring your own cricket gear if you already have. For those who don’t have, you can always borrow.  However, bring your own box (which obviously you may not want to borrow.)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Cold beer will be available for purchase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directions to the ground are available at &lt;a href="http://www.harrow.gov.uk/info/200073/parks_and_open_spaces/1352/green_flag_parks/4" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.harrow.gov.uk/info/200073/parks_and_open_spaces/1352/green_flag_parks/4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please send RSVP by &lt;strong&gt;2nd of July&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Mailing address&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
No 7 Erroll Road&lt;br /&gt;
Romford&lt;br /&gt;
Essex&lt;br /&gt;
RM1 3DJ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bank account details&lt;/u&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Bank Sort Code: 20-29-37&lt;br /&gt;
A/c Name:  South Indian Society&lt;br /&gt;
A/c No. 50284645&lt;br /&gt;
Ref: Cricket 2011
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you all at the next event on 9th July 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>