<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20110630064356</EventID>
  <PageTitle>Monthly Mini Event -- August</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>South Indian Society London Upanyasam Krishna Leela and Rukmini Kalyanam</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society London Upanyasam / Spiritual Discourse Krishna Leela and Rukmini Kalyanam</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>Monthly Mini Event -- August</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2011-08-07</EventDate>
  <EventTime>3 pm</EventTime>
  <Address>Church of Ascension Hall on Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Krishna Leela and Rukmini Kalyanam&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;வசுதேவ சுதம் தேவம், கம்ச சாணூரமர்தனம்&lt;/br&gt;
தேவகி பரமானந்தம் கிருஷ்ணம் வந்தே ஜகத் குரும்&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;This year, Sri Krishna Jayanthi falls on 21st of August (according to பாம்பு பஞ்சாங்கம்). In line with that, we at SIS are pleased to organise an upanyasam on "Krishna Leela and Rukmini Kalyanam" on the 7th of August.  Sri Krishna Jayanti, signifies not merely the birth of a great and divine teacher of mankind but also the lighting of the spark of the divine power in every one of us. Krishna represents the total power of attraction and is the source of joy.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Sri Vasudeva Battar, who has learnt to perform upanyasam from Sri Anantharama Dikshadar will give a discourse. Some of the members have listened to his Upanyasam a few times and his depth of knowledge and his command on the subject is outstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We request you to bring your children along as well and they will get exposed to the original Indian culture in a British environment.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;SIS PRESENTS &lt;b&gt;"Krishna Leela and Rukmini Kalyanam"&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Date :&lt;/b&gt;  7th August 2011&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Time    :&lt;/b&gt;  3.00 p.m to 6.00 p.m&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Venue   :&lt;/b&gt;  Church of Ascension Hall,&lt;/br&gt;
           Beaufort Road&lt;/br&gt;
           Ealing W5 3EB&lt;/br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Entry FREE !!!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;b&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Agenda&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/u&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;3:00 pm  to 3:30 pm : Assembly&lt;/br&gt;
3:30 pm to 5:30 pm : Krishna Leela and Rukmini Kalyanam Upanyasam by Sri. Vasudeva Battar&lt;/br&gt;
5:30 pm to 6 pm : Snacks and Socialising&lt;/br&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;Please send RSVP by 5th of August, by simply replying to this e-mail.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;PS: Please note the subject for upanyasam has changed from the earlier Prahladha Charitram&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>