<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20120609115444</EventID>
  <PageTitle>SIS Carnival 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>SIS South Indian Society Carnival 2012 a charity drive to support "Shooting Star Children’s Hospice" and "Great Ormond Street Hospital"</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>SIS South Indian Society Carnival 2012 a charity drive to support "Shooting Star Children’s Hospice" and "Great Ormond Street Hospital"</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>SIS Carnival 2012</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2012-08-18</EventDate>
  <EventTime>3 pm</EventTime>
  <Address>St Andrews Church, 89 Malvern Avenue, Harrow, Middlesex, HA2 9ER Roxbourne, Harrow  </Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idhu Namma Ooru Thiruvizha!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience the Street Foods of India, Yummy Mumbai Bhel or mouth watering Kolkotta Gol Guppa, Chatpatta Punjabi Samosa or sizzzzling Chennai Marina Beach Sundal, Cakes and Pastries, Fresh Juice, Dosa, Rice &amp; Curry and many more…….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that is not enough, you can buy funky jewellery, exotic Indian arts and crafts, exquisite paintings and participate in game show. Foot tapping Bollywood dance for the Katrina Kaifs and Bebos in London and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If that is still not enough, you can win fantastic Irresistible prizes…… Yessssssss ! ! ! ! !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;Apple TV / iPOD Shuffle/ Gear 4 Portable Speaker iPOD Dock / Gift hampers ! ! ! ! ! !&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You cannot have a more perfect weekend this summer with your family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come in with loads of energy and friends for a mind blowing experience of India in London&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;St Andrews Church, 89 Malvern Avenue, Harrow, Middlesex HA2 9ER.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date and Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday the 18th of August 2012&lt;br&gt;
3 PM – 7 PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Entry: &lt;span style="color:red;"&gt;FREE ! ! ! ! !&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The carnival is being held in aid of Shooting Stars Children Hospice and Great Ormond Street Hospital. Celebrate the Joy of Giving with SIS Summer Carnival.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember!!! August 18, 2012!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/events/SIS-Carnival-Poster.jpg" alt=""   /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>