<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20120609115926</EventID>
  <PageTitle>SIS Youth Career Development Event -- September 2012</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>SIS South Indian Society Career Event</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>SIS South Indian Society Career Event</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>SIS Youth Career Development Event 2012</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2012-09-22</EventDate>
  <EventTime>3 pm</EventTime>
  <Address>Church of Ascension Hall on Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;The event is aimed at providing specific, 'supplementary' guidance to students (and their parents) about to make their higher educational choice - specific, in the sense, it is aimed at children of the SIS family; supplementary to the guidance provided by their schools. The ambit is to provide guidance on both making the right choice, in terms of universities, subjects, etc., and how to go about navigating the selection process and put one's best foot forward. What to choose and how to make it click!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The target audience is children about to make their UCAS application this year or next year; but, children, at a slightly earlier academic stage, will also benefit. Parents are particularly invited as they can constructively help their children. Whilst it is meant for children of the SIS family, we will be delighted to have children of non-member Indian families. It is important that we have advance registration from all the children who want to participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aim to make the event interactive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have engaged the services of a professional career's guide &lt;strong&gt;David Scales Career Adviser (Dip CG, PGCE)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have organised eminent speakers - young graduates and professionals with multifarious  background (medicine, engineering, science, law, finance and accounting, dentistry, arts, etc.) - to share their thoughts about their career choices  and experiences &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mr N Sundar&lt;/strong&gt; of SIS will draw on his industry-academic experience to handle a brief session on what makes people succeed as students and as professionals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mrs Mythili Venkateswaran&lt;/strong&gt; has kindly agreed to compere the whole event in her inimitable style, along with providing guidance on oral and written communication. Students will have an opportunity to have a brief one on one chat with the professional advisor at the end of the event. We will also circulate some useful material and web links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are others whom we have approached and a final list of confirmed speakers will be sent out later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the event is aimed at students and their parents, all other SIS members are invited to attend and interact. On a one on one basis they will be able to share their own experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; Church of Ascension Hall on Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; Saturday, 22nd September, 2012.  2:30 pm to assemble; 3:00 pm sharp 			the actual event will start. Please be on time.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Entry:&lt;/strong&gt; Free!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, we will have snacks and drinks at the end of the event. We plan to finish by 5:30 pm latest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:red;"&gt;Due to nature of the event and to ensure that participants gain maximum benefit, we would like to know the number of participants, their profile and what they are looking to gain from this event in advance. Hence we kindly request you to RSVP before Sunday the 16th of September by sending an e-mail to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>