<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20120324052103</EventID>
  <PageTitle>South Indian Society - Tamil Music &amp; Dance - Cruise Evening in Thames</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>London cruise, thames cruise, SIS cruise, south indian society cruise</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>A cruise evening in Thames on June 2012. Come and Join South Indian Society for a fun ride.</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>SIS -- Sunset Cruise in Thames -- June 2012</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2012-06-16</EventDate>
  <EventTime>5:15 pm</EventTime>
  <Address>Tower Hill Millennium Pier, 53 Lower Thames Street, EC3R 6DT</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p style="color:red;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The boat is fully booked. We have absolutely no tickets to be sold. So our sincere request is not to bring any additional guests for whom you have not already paid. Anyone turning up without a confirmed ticket, regrettably, cannot get on board.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;வசந்த கால நதிகளிலே &lt;br /&gt;
வைரமணி நீரலைகள்&lt;br /&gt;
நீரலைகள் மீதினிலே&lt;br /&gt;
நெஞ்சிரெண்டின் நினைவலைகள்....&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;SIS is thrilled to announce a fun filled evening in June, Sunset Cruise on Thames. Let’s welcome the summer with our friends. Let’s gather together on a sun-kissed evening for fabulous music, dance and much more. Tongue tickling food guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;And all this at a very nominal cost&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Spoil yourself, chill out and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember to mark your diary for June 16, 2012&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Date: Saturday the 16th of June 2012&lt;br /&gt;
Venue: Tower Hill Millennium Pier, 53 Lower Thames Street, EC3R 6DT&lt;br /&gt;
Boarding Time: 5:15 pm&lt;br /&gt;
Departure Time: 6 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nearby Stations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
National Rail: Fenchurch Street&lt;br /&gt;
DLR: Tower Gateway&lt;br /&gt;
Tube: Tower Hill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have reached the full capacity.  Our sincere thanks for the overwhelming response. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who have not paid yet, we have to apologies that we can't take any more bookings.  Will see you all in the next event&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For those who have paid, looking forward to welcoming you all aboard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Please note that we will operate a first paid first served policy, as the seats in the boat are limited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to operational difficulties, we operate on no-refund policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please be advised not to bring alcoholic drink, however drinks can be purchased on your own from the bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>