<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20120320073906</EventID>
  <PageTitle>SIS Special Satsang</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>South Indian Society Special Satsang -- Anugraha Bhasan by the Udupi Swamiji Sri Sugunendra Theertha Swamiji on Friday the 23rd of March, 2012</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Satsang Special Satsang -- Anugraha Bhasan by the Udupi Swamiji Sri Sugunendra Theertha Swamiji on Friday the 23rd of March, 2012SIS Special Satsang -- Anugraha Bhasan by the Udupi Swamiji Sri Sugunendra Theertha Swamiji on Friday the 23rd of March, 2012</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>SIS Special Satsang</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2012-03-23</EventDate>
  <EventTime>7:00 pm</EventTime>
  <Address>8A, Malden Park, New Malden, KT3 6AS, Surrey </Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;Patrons,&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

We are delighted to invite you to a Special Satsang – &lt;strong&gt;Anugraha Bhasan by the Udupi Swamiji Sri Sugunendra Theertha Swamiji on Friday the 23rd of March, 2012.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Udipi Swamiji is the highly revered Pontiff of Jagadguru Shree Madwaachaarya Moola Mahaa Samsthaanam, Shree Puthige Matha, Udupi. In addition to performing the traditional religious activities and pujas of the Mutt, the Swamiji is the International President of World Conference of Religions for Peace, New York and delivers inspiring discourses. He is a torch bearer of the Dwaitha School of Hindu philosophy. In recent years, swamiji has set up branches of the mutt in Los Angeles, Houston, New Jersey, Phoenix, Toronto, etc. Full details of the matha are available at &lt;a href="http://www.shreeputhige.org" target="_blank"&gt;www.shreeputhige.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.catemple.org" target="_blank"&gt;www.catemple.org&lt;/a&gt; and other related websites.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Swamiji is in the UK on a brief visit. He arrived in the UK 17th late evening and will be leaving 24th afternoon. Given his hectic schedule and puja commitments, the only available slot is Friday 23rd evening and he has kindly consented to deliver an anugraha bhasan for SIS members on that auspicious day of Ugadi, new year’s day in Andhra Pradesh, Karnataka, Maharashtra etc. The venue will be the residence of Mrs Jayanthi Sundar and Mr N Sundar in New Malden. We will start with a recital of Vishnu Sahasranamam at 700 pm. When the swamiji arrives at 730 pm, there will be a pada puja, followed by anugraha bhasan.  Swamiji will be happy to answer questions.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;All SIS members and their families are invited to attend the event and receive the blessings of the swamiji.  Kindly however RSVP the host by Thursday 22nd.&lt;/p&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Programme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 
Ugadi day, 23rd March, 2012&lt;br /&gt;
 
700 pm Vishnu Sahasranamam recital&lt;br /&gt;
730 pm  Pada puja for the Swamiji&lt;br /&gt;
800 pm Anugraha Bhasan by the Swamiji&lt;br /&gt;
830 pm Prasadam&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 
Venue: 8A, Malden Park, New Malden, KT3 6AS, Surrey&lt;br /&gt;
 
RSVP: &lt;a href="mailto:nsundar@btinternet.com"&gt;nsundar@btinternet.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
02089495755&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>