<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20130203111602</EventID>
  <PageTitle>SIS "Let's talk money" -- Half a day seminar</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>SIS "Let's talk money" -- Half a day seminar</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>SIS "Let's talk money" -- Half a day seminar</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>SIS "Let's talk money" -- Half a day seminar</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2013-02-16</EventDate>
  <EventTime>2:00 PM</EventTime>
  <Address>Church of Ascension Hall, Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;u&gt;Sponsored by State Bank of India&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I fully understand the difference between NRE / NRO accounts and recent changes in Banking rules and practices?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the advantages, and risks, in putting money in high interest earning deposits in India?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I fully understand the repatriation rules?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How better can I use my status of being a "Person of Indian Origin?"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there a safe haven for my money, where I can get better returns than I currently get?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the Indian economic climate and what are the opportunities for investment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the tax implications?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us have these kind of questions in our mind and would like authentic clarifications. South Indian Society is happy to announce a half day seminar on "Let's talk money" sponsored by State Bank of India.  Mr. Subramanian Venkatraman CEO, SBI London Branch will be leading the seminar and there are other speakers being lined up both from and outside SBI.&lt;/p&gt;
            
            
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this email is to give you advance notice so that you can block the date in your diary. SIS members will obviously notice that this seminar will take place at the same venue and date as the postponed 2013 Annual General Meeting. After a brief break at the end of the seminar we will have the AGM, where of course only members whose membership subscription is up to date can attend. A separate notice has been sent to all the SIS members on the postponed AGM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we have the final programme, with confirmations from various speakers, we will send further details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="color:blue; font-weight: bold"&gt; "Let's Talk Money" Seminar&lt;/p&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt; &lt;strong&gt; Date   : &lt;/strong&gt;  16th Feb 2013&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Time   : &lt;/strong&gt; 2:00 PM - 4:30 PM (Request you to register 30 mins earlier)&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Venue   : &lt;/strong&gt; Church of Ascension Hall, Beaufort Road, Ealing W5 3EB&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;strong&gt;Entry   : &lt;/strong&gt; FREE, but, RSVP is a must: please let us have the RSVP latest by Thursday the 14th of February&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refreshments will be available at the end of the seminar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will obviously have plenty of opportunity to ask questions at the event.  However, you may like to send in your questions to &lt;a href="mailto:sisnambalava@gmail.com"&gt;sisnambalava@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;  in advance and we will request the speakers to cover those in the presentation. We also want to make it abundantly clear that neither SIS nor SBI seeks to, or will, provide personal financial advice during or after the seminar. Any decision you may like to take with regard to your investments or other financial matters will necessarily be based on your own judgement and advice that you may receive from professional financial advisers engaged by you for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seminar is open to both SIS members and non-members. So please feel free to forward this invitation to your friends who may be interested. In order to help us keep the number of participants under control and to organise refreshments, we would like to have the RSVPs &lt;strong&gt;latest by Thursday, the 14th of February 2013.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to seeing you all.&lt;/p&gt;          
        ]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>