<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20140525091500</EventID>
  <PageTitle>SIS Special Satsang - 26th May 2014</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>SIS Special Satsang - 26th May 2014</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>SIS Special Satsang - 26th May 2014..</MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>Webinar with Kanchi Kamakoti Peetam Sankaracharyas - Special Satsang </EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2014-05-26</EventDate>
  <EventTime>3:45 PM</EventTime>
  <Address>21, Garrick Road, Greenford, UB6 9HT</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Webinar with Kanchi Kamakoti Peetam Sankaracharyas, HH Sri Jayendra Saraswathi Swamigal and HH Sri Vijayendra Saraswathi Swamigal 26th May, 2014: 3.45 pm to 5.00 pm (UK time)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As already announced devotees in the UK will have the fortune of a webinar with their Holinesses, the first one by the Kanchi Acharyas, at 3.45 pm UK time on 26th May 2014. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For devotees in London, we are arranging to have the webcast on a big screen at the residence of Mr Murali Ramdos, 21, Garrick Road, Greenford, UB6 9HT. Kindly ring Mr Murali on ph 07833146070.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who can not come to Greenford in person, an alternative is to watch the webcast from their own email connection, through internet or through their smarphone . For this you need to immediately send your email details to me at &lt;a href="mailto:nsundar@btinternet.com"&gt;nsundar@btinternet.com&lt;/a&gt;. You will then be sent an 'invitation' email which will enable you join the webcast. It is a relatively simple process, but, you need to immediately send me the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although we are using modern technology, I am sure you will all treat viewing the telecast as if their Holinesses themselves are visiting your home. Those who come to Mr Murali's residence, in particular, are requested to dress traditionally, as if they are having a personal darshan of the Periavals. The Periavals will be able to see the assembly of devotees and interact with them and we will be able to offer our respects to them. You are welcome to bring flowers and fruits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any clarification or assistance, please call N Sundar at 07802782659 or Subbu 07837466338.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>