<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20140206034101</EventID>
  <PageTitle>London Yoga Workshop - South Indian Society </PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>yoga workshop, london yoga, london yoga workshop</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>South India Society presents a free Yoga workshop in Harrow, London on 15th March 2014. </MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>London Yoga Workshop</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2014-03-15</EventDate>
  <EventTime>3 pm to 5 pm </EventTime>
  <Address>Victoria Hall, Sheepcote Rd, Harrow, Middlesex HA1 2JE</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London Yoga Workshop - YOGA FOR ALL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FREE!!! ALL ARE WELCOME!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 15th March 2014&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 pm to 5 pm (Assembly @ 2:30 pm for a 3 pm start)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Venue:&lt;/strong&gt; Victoria Hall, Sheepcote Rd, Harrow, Middlesex HA1 2JE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;About the trainer:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shyamala alias Sam is a self-motivated and passionate yoga instructor, who has been inspired by her guru Sri Asana Andiappan who practices and lives the yogic philosophies until today in his 80's.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She qualified as a Yoga therapist at the renowned Andiappan college of Yoga and research, Chennai, India, successfully completing an intensive Yoga Therapy course and basic principles of Ayurveda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is certified to instruct Yoga in corporate circles, community centres, sport and leisure and schools. She has developed her own style of teaching that combines Vinyasa and Ashtanga delivered with a touch of Iyengar Yoga making it suitable for all ability levels and those with particular health issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam has actively participated and volunteered to travel in her groups for yogic and meditation courses and workshops conducted in India, Malaysia and Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>