<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Event>
  <EventID>20140213122549</EventID>
  <PageTitle>SIS Vaanavil - Kids Program - Essex</PageTitle>
  <MetaKeywords>south indian society, kids activity program</MetaKeywords>
  <MetaDescription>South Indian Society presents an exclusive events for kids called "Vaanavil" to show and express their talents. The program will be held on May 2014 in Billericay, Essex. </MetaDescription>
  <EventHeading>SIS Vaanavil - Kids Program</EventHeading>
  <EventDate>2014-05-18</EventDate>
  <EventTime>12:30 PM - 5 PM</EventTime>
  <Address>Barleylands Farm, Barleylands Road, Billericay CM11 2UD</Address>
  <Maindescription>&lt;![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event Schedule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;We are organising a Kid's Fun Fair: a day out to a unique farm just outside M25, a great opportunity for kids of ages 4 to 13 participate in various activities and learn from Art experts and generally have a great family day out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tentative Schedule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12:30 - 13:00 -- Registration&lt;br /&gt;
13:00 - 13:45 -- Sloka Recitation Contest (Thiruppavai 1 to 3, Vishnu/Lalitha Sahasranamam, Hanuman Chalisa, Ashtalakshmi sloka,Lingashtakam: Each kid will be asked to recite any one of the Thiruppavai, that will be decided at random by the judge, or, any verse from the others)- Please find details for Sloka contest below.&lt;br/&gt;
13:45 - 14:15 -- Drawing &amp; Painting Contest (Please bring your own brush and colours): The chief guest will be.......More details will be sent later&lt;br /&gt;
14:15 - 15:00 -- Demonstration and guidance from Art experts&lt;br /&gt;
15:00 - 17:00 -- Entry to Barleylands Farm and play time&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Entry : &lt;strong&gt;FREE for all ! RSVP is a must. Please RSVP by 10th May.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For those children who confirm in advance, we will also give tickets (worth £9/-) for their entry to the farm and for free train ride- accompanying parents will need to buy their own tickets!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The Farm : Barleylands is the perfect all weather, best large attraction in Essex! As well as the cutest and friendiest animals in the Farm Park, the venue has fun packed indoor and outdoor adventure play areas - race down slides, scale the playframe, whizz on the zip wire and bounce on the huge jumping pillow. Then all onboard the miniature train ride, journey out to the crop fields on the bumpy tractor &amp; trailer ride, join in animal activities and explore Farmer Peter's Discovery Centre. Visit  &lt;a href="http://www.barleylands.co.uk" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.barleylands.co.uk&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Let's have a perfect family day out at Barleylands ! ! ! !  All are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slokas for the Competetion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids can choose to recite any one of the slokas below. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thiruppavai  (1 -3 verses)  any one will be asked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vishnu Sahasranamam  (10 lines) (from viswan vishnur to pradhyaya sarvadararshnaha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lalitha Sahasranamam (10 lines) (Om Sri mata to Samakarshi digandhara)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laskshmi ashtakam (Namasthesthu mahamaye)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lingashtakam (Brahma murari  1- 5 )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hanuman Chalisa (10 lines) (Sri guru charana to rama lakshana seetha man bhasiya)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;]]&gt;</Maindescription>
</Event>